<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cybersecurity on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/cybersecurity/</link><description>Recent content in Cybersecurity on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mozilla Cybersecurity Delphi 1.0: Towards a User-centric Policy Framework</title><link>/entries/87/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/87/</guid><description>Authors: Camille François, Chris Riley, Dave Steer, Jochai BenAvie, Su Midghall
Published: July 2015
URL: https://blog.mozilla.org/netpolicy/files/2015/07/Mozilla-Cybersecurity-Delphi-1.0.pdf
Tags: 2010s Cybersecurity Policy Primer</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad IDea</title><link>/entries/84/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/84/</guid><description>Authors: New America: OTI
Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Tags: 2010s Amendment I Backdoors Cybersecurity Economic Impact Foreign Concerns Going Dark Human Rights OTI Primer SAFE Act Surveillance Abstract: In testimony before House Oversight and Government Reform Committee today, Bankston pushes back against legislative fixes to limit the avail</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Encryption</title><link>/entries/195/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/195/</guid><description>Authors: Baker, Jim
Published: October 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/rethinking-encryption
Tags: 2010 Amendment IV Attorney General William P. Barr CLOUD Act Cybersecurity Going Dark Law Enforcement Public Safety Abstract: I. Embrace Reality and Deal With It</description></item><item><title>S. 2889 - National Security and Personal Data Protection Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/39/</guid><description>Authors: Hawley, Josh and Cotton, Tom and Rubio, Marco
Published: November 2019
Tags: 2010s Bill Cybersecurity Foreign Investment National Security and Personal Data Protection Act of 2019 Security Requirements US Congress Abstract: To safeguard data of Americans from foreign governments that pose risks to national security by imposing data security requirements and strengthening review of foreign investments, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>Surveillance Costs: The NSA's Impact on the Economy, Internet Freedom \&amp; Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/15/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle and Bankston, Kevin and Greene, Robyn and Morgus, Robert
Published: July 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/policy-papers/surveillance-costs-the-nsas-impact-on-the-economy-internet-freedom-cybersecurity/
Tags: 2010s Cybersecurity Economic Impact Government Access National Security OTI Personal Privacy Abstract: It has been over a year since The Guardian reported the first story on the National Security Agency’s surveillance programs based on the leaks from former NSA contractor Edward Snowden, yet the national conversation remains largely mired in a simplistic debate over the tradeoffs between national security and individual privacy.</description></item></channel></rss>