<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stanford CIS on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/stanford-cis/</link><description>Recent content in Stanford CIS on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/stanford-cis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DOJ Plans to Strike Against Encryption While the Techlash Iron Is Hot</title><link>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2020
URL: /blog/2020/02/doj-plans-strike-against-encryption-while-techlash-iron-hot
Abstract: This blog post by Riana Pfefferkorn argues that since 2016, the Department of Justice sought to capitalize on public anti-technology sentiment to weaken encryption. First, the article describes the political climate, shaped by the Apple v FBI case, the role of big tech in various privacy scandals and foreign interference in the 2016 election, and foreign legislation, particularly in Australia and the U.</description></item><item><title>The EARN IT Act Is Unconstitutional: Fourth Amendment</title><link>/entries/the-earn-it-act-is-unconstitutional-fourth-amendme-a7207348/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-earn-it-act-is-unconstitutional-fourth-amendme-a7207348/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: March 2020
URL: http://cyberlaw.stanford.edu/blog/2020/03/earn-it-act-unconstitutional-fourth-amendment
Abstract: This blog post outlines the argument that proposed legislation entitled the EARN IT Act is unconstitutional on Fourth Amendment Grounds. The Post argues that the Act would require online service providers to actively scan for Child Sexual Abuse Materials, rather than merely reporting it when it is found. By requiring providers to conduct these searches, the providers would become state actors and the searches would require a warrant, and without a warrant, these searches would be unconstitutional under the fourth amendment, and the evidence would be excluded in court proceedings.</description></item><item><title>The Risks of “Responsible Encryption”</title><link>/entries/the-risks-of-responsible-encryption-149c012c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-risks-of-responsible-encryption-149c012c/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2018
Abstract: The Risks of “Responsible Encryption” critiques “responsible encryption,” a term developed used by US law enforcement officials describing a general policy of government access to encrypted materials. The article begins by detailing the origins of the terms and their use by government officials, then seeks to define the scope of the term and possible technical definitions. Next, the paper warns of the risks of exceptional access, including increased key usage and access, authentication of exceptional access requests at scale, the economic and competitive effects on US technology companies, and the limitations of exceptional access capabilities.</description></item></channel></rss>