<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Attorney General William P. Barr on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/attorney-general-william-p.-barr/</link><description>Recent content in Attorney General William P. Barr on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/attorney-general-william-p.-barr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Attorney General William P. Barr Delivers Keynote Address at the International Conference on Cyber Security</title><link>/entries/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-a-55f805a8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-a-55f805a8/</guid><description>Authors: Barr, William
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-address-international-conference-cyber
Abstract: Former Attorney General William Barr delivered the keynote address at the International Conference on Cyber Security in 2019. In the speech, Barr describes encryption as a technology that gives cover to criminals, particularly drug cartels, and prevents law enforcement from solving crimes. Barr insinuates that the Fourth Amendment, through balancing personal privacy and public safety, may not allow so-called “warrant-proof encryption” and requests backdoors be added to encryption to allow law enforcement access to encrypted messages through pursuant to warrants.</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Encryption</title><link>/entries/rethinking-encryption-b0065e9b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/rethinking-encryption-b0065e9b/</guid><description>Authors: Baker, Jim
Published: October 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/rethinking-encryption
Abstract: This article written by Jim Baker encourages law enforcement officials in the U.S. to embrace encryption due to cybersecurity threats, particularly from china. The article begins by describing the issues of going dark to law enforcement, and quotes officials such as Attorney General William Barr encouraging Congress to legislate around encryption. However, because Congress has failed to act in light of such pressures, it is possible action will never occur.</description></item></channel></rss>