<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R Street Institute on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/r-street-institute/</link><description>Recent content in R Street Institute on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/r-street-institute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Encryption, Biometrics, and the Status Quo Ante</title><link>/entries/55/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/55/</guid><description>Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/encryption-biometrics-and-status-quo-ante
Abstract: As the recent indirect debate between FBI Director James Comey and co-blogger Susan Landau makes clear, the underlying premises of the encryption issue are highly contested. The Senate will continue the debate this week with a hearing before the Judiciary Committee on July 8 at which our own Herb Lin (among others) will testify and another hearing before the Intelligence Committee.</description></item><item><title>New Perspectives on the Future of Encryption</title><link>/entries/160/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/160/</guid><description>Published: May 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/new-perspectives-future-encryption
Abstract: Encryption and its effects on law enforcement’s access to data seem to occupy a perennial place in the headlines (and on Lawfare as well). The two of us have been working on it for years. The subject is often highly contested, but the fierce discussion has ignored some critical factors. One of those is how changing usage patterns and technologies will affect how law enforcement can—or can’t—obtain access.</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Encryption</title><link>/entries/157/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/157/</guid><description>Published: October 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/rethinking-encryption
Abstract: I. Embrace Reality and Deal With It</description></item></channel></rss>