<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Department of Justice on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/department-of-justice/</link><description>Recent content in Department of Justice on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/department-of-justice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Attorney General William P. Barr Delivers Keynote Address at the International Conference on Cyber Security</title><link>/entries/102/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/102/</guid><description>Authors: Barr, William
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-address-international-conference-cyber
Tags: 2010s Amendment IV Attorney General William P. Barr Department of Justice Law Enforcement Probable Cause</description></item><item><title>Promoting Public Saftey, Privacy, and the Rule of Law Around the World: The Purpose and Impact of the CLOUD Act</title><link>/entries/107/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/107/</guid><description>Published: April 2019
Tags: 2010s CLOUD Act Department of Justice Foreign International Law Enforcement</description></item><item><title>Report of the Attorney General's Cyber Digital Task Force</title><link>/entries/92/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/92/</guid><description>Published: July 2018
Tags: 2010s Department of Justice Going Dark Law Enforcement Abstract: In February of 2018, the Attorney General established a Cyber-Digital Task force within the U.S. Department of Justice and tasked it with answer two foundational questions. First, “how is the Department responding to cyber threats?” Second, “how can federal law enforcement more effectively accomplish its mission in this important and rapidly evolving area?” This Report addresses the first question.</description></item></channel></rss>