<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IV Amendment on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/iv-amendment/</link><description>Recent content in IV Amendment on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/iv-amendment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Don't Panic: Making Progress on Going Dark Debate</title><link>/entries/68/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/68/</guid><description>Published: February 2016
Abstract: Just over a year ago, with support from the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, the Berkman Center for Internet &amp;amp; Society at Harvard University convened a diverse group of security and policy experts from academia, civil society, and the U.S. intelligence community to begin to work through some of the particularly vexing and enduring problems of surveillance and cybersecurity. The group came together understanding that there has been no shortage of debate.</description></item><item><title>Old Technopanic in New iBottles</title><link>/entries/78/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/78/</guid><description>Authors: Julian Sanchez
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.cato.org/blog/old-technopanic-new-ibottles
Abstract: If we aim to preserve an “equilibrium” between government power and citizen privacy, we should accept that it will occasionally close one as well.</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad IDea</title><link>/entries/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/24/</guid><description>Authors: New America: OTI
Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Abstract: In testimony before House Oversight and Government Reform Committee today, Bankston pushes back against legislative fixes to limit the avail</description></item><item><title>Protecting the Fourth Amendment in the Information Age: A Response to Robert Litt</title><link>/entries/163/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/163/</guid><description>Published: 2016</description></item></channel></rss>