<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Primer on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/primer/</link><description>Recent content in Primer on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/primer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beyond Secrets: The Consumer Stake in the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/beyond-secrets-the-consumer-stake-in-the-encryptio-5a9a086a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/beyond-secrets-the-consumer-stake-in-the-encryptio-5a9a086a/</guid><description>Published: December 2017
URL: https://advocacy.consumerreports.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Beyond-Secrets-12.21.17-FINAL.pdf
Abstract: On December 21, 2017, ConsumersUnion and Upturn released this paper on consumers’ stake in the encryption debate. The paper begins with information on cryptography: what it is and how it works. It then discusses the ways in which encryption benefits consumers, including: protecting their health information, safeguarding their financial well-being, facilitating sale software updates, ensuring physical safety, and allowing consumers to communicate with confidence. The purpose of this paper is to educate consumers about the many ways that encryption benefits consumers and the systems and infrastructure consumers rely upon, and the potential costs if encryption were to be compromised.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Summit 1.0</title><link>/entries/crypto-summit-1-0-efc034c8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/crypto-summit-1-0-efc034c8/</guid><description>Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/crypto_summit_part1/
Abstract: AccessNow published a summary of the Crypto Summit 1.0, the first of two summits, which occurred on July 15, 2015 in Washington, DC. The topics discussed in the conference focus on the United States and include crypto history, encryption technology, the current state of the law and how it should evolve, the biggest challenges and opportunities of encryption and the future of encryption based on potential policy outcomes.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Summit 2.0 Outcomes Report Track 1</title><link>/entries/crypto-summit-2-0-outcomes-report-track-1-f3204001/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/crypto-summit-2-0-outcomes-report-track-1-f3204001/</guid><description>Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2016/07/CS2.0_Outcomes_Track1.pdf
Abstract: AccessNow published a summary of the Crypto Summit 2.0, the second of two summits, which occurred on March 30, 2016 in Silicon Valley. The goal of this conference was to build off the key questions identified in Crypto Summit 1.0. The group identified four policy tracks to focus on in the second summit. The first policy track entails the “roles and responsibilities in an encrypted world”.</description></item><item><title>Cryptography and Liberty 2000: An International Survey of Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/cryptography-and-liberty-2000-an-international-sur-3c4921c1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/cryptography-and-liberty-2000-an-international-sur-3c4921c1/</guid><description>Authors: Banisar, David and Madsen, Wayne
Published: 2000
URL: https://epic.org/reports/crypto2000.html/
Abstract: Cryptography and Liberty is a survey by EPIC, a non-profit organization, on governmental encryption and cryptography laws around the world and the impacts of human rights. The survey focused on laws on domestic use of cryptography, disclosure requirements for encryption keys, import and export controls, and which government agencies or entities regulate cryptography and encryption.</description></item><item><title>Encryption 101: A Non-Technical Guide to Protecting Your Digital Communications</title><link>/entries/encryption-101-a-non-technical-guide-to-protecting-a4994675/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-101-a-non-technical-guide-to-protecting-a4994675/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle
Published: February 2015
URL: https://slate.com/technology/2015/02/what-is-encryption-a-nontechnical-guide-to-protecting-your-digital-communications.html
Abstract: This article from Danielle Kehl offers a beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide to encryption, including how the technology works, its development, its modern uses, and how one can implement encryption technology into their daily life to increase their personal privacy. This article includes discussion of Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTPS), Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol and its successor, Transport Layer Security (TLS).</description></item><item><title>Encryption in the U.S.: Crypto Colloquium Outcomes Report</title><link>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</guid><description>Published: January 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/02/Encryption-in-the-United-States-Crypto-Colloquium-Outcomes-Report.pdf
Abstract: In September of 2017, Access Now, a non-profit dedicated to human rights advocacy in the digital age, hosted the Crypto Colloquium—an invite-only dialogue of civil society, academic experts, technology companies and former U.S. government officials—to discuss challenges associated with U.S. government agencies’ inability to access information on encrypted mobile phones. The Report, produced by Access Now, provides a summary of the key takeaways from the Colloquium, including a section on the “Lessons Learned” in each of the Law and Policy, Security, and Economics sectors.</description></item><item><title>Encryption under fire: discussion on threats to private messaging w/ Head of WhatsApp Will Cathcart</title><link>/entries/encryption-under-fire-discussion-on-threats-to-pri-6bbe4ed7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-under-fire-discussion-on-threats-to-pri-6bbe4ed7/</guid><description>Published: July 2020
URL: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y1LSFQo_07w</description></item><item><title>Entropy and Random Numbers</title><link>/entries/entropy-and-random-numbers-d61c00fb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/entropy-and-random-numbers-d61c00fb/</guid><description>Authors: Callan, Tim and Soroko, Jason
URL: https://sectigo.com/resources/root-causes-1-25
Abstract: Sectigo SSL Certificates formerly Comodo CA SSL Certificates. Same high quality SSL certificates you trust! Money Back Guarantee. Secure all Subdomains. 30 Day Refund Policy, 24/7 Live Support</description></item><item><title>From Clipper Chip to Smartphones: Unlocking the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-enc-cbe23268/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-enc-cbe23268/</guid><description>Authors: Flatow, Ira
URL: https://www.sciencefriday.com/segments/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-encryption-debate/
Abstract: This Podcast features comments made by security experts and privacy advocates made in the 1990s about the Clipper Chip. It offers a look back into what the policy discussion looked like concurrently with the Clipper Chip proposals. Some of those who previously made comments offer follow-up, looking back at the development of their views and policy positions and how they have developed in the intervening years.</description></item><item><title>Mozilla Cybersecurity Delphi 1.0: Towards a User-centric Policy Framework</title><link>/entries/mozilla-cybersecurity-delphi-1-0-towards-a-user-ce-3db1081f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/mozilla-cybersecurity-delphi-1-0-towards-a-user-ce-3db1081f/</guid><description>Authors: Camille François, Chris Riley, Dave Steer, Jochai Ben-Avie, Su Midghall
Published: July 2015
URL: https://blog.mozilla.org/netpolicy/files/2015/07/Mozilla-Cybersecurity-Delphi-1.0.pdf
Abstract: This study by Mozilla brought together 30 cybersecurity experts from academia, civil liberties, government and military, security, and technology, to discuss priorities and goals in the development of encryption policy. The report found several areas of agreement, such as prioritizing automating encryption over consumer education and the prioritization of developing behavioral and cultural norms in cybersecurity.</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad Idea</title><link>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</guid><description>Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Abstract: In April 2015, OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston was schedule to testify before the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform’s Subcommittee on Information Technology regarding backdoor mandates and potential U.S. policy responses. New America published this blog post, on April 28, 2015, summarizing Bankston’s prepared statement and highlighting the ten key reasons Bankston identified against backdoor mandates. The reasons identified by Bankston were: 1) surveillance backdoors were already rejected as a policy approach two decades ago, including by Congress; 2) it would seriously undermine U.</description></item><item><title>Secrets or Shields to Share? New Dilemmas for Dual Use Technology Development and the Quest for military and Commercial Advantage in the Digital Age</title><link>/entries/secrets-or-shields-to-share-new-dilemmas-for-dual-34d6ebbe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/secrets-or-shields-to-share-new-dilemmas-for-dual-34d6ebbe/</guid><description>Authors: Stowsky, Jay
Published: February 2003</description></item><item><title>Timeline: The U.S. Government and Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/timeline-the-u-s-government-and-cybersecurity-5f7be48e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/timeline-the-u-s-government-and-cybersecurity-5f7be48e/</guid><description>Published: May 2003
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/articles/A50606-2002Jun26.html
Abstract: This article offers a short timeline of government actions to curb the hacking of government computer systems. This article was prescient given the panic the Y2K bug that was creating in the vulnerabilities of government systems.</description></item></channel></rss>