<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OTI on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/oti/</link><description>Recent content in OTI on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/oti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Breaking: FBI Admits its Claims of “Going Dark” Were Overblown, Based on Bad Math</title><link>/entries/breaking-fbi-admits-its-claims-of-going-dark-were-b620adf1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/breaking-fbi-admits-its-claims-of-going-dark-were-b620adf1/</guid><description>Published: May 2018
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/press-releases/breaking-fbi-admits-its-claims-going-dark-were-overblown-based-bad-math/
Abstract: The Open Technology Institute released a statement regarding a Washington Post report that the FBI overstated “the number of encrypted mobile devices it could not unlock in 2017.” While the FBI had previously claimed there were 7,775 such devices, the FBI later clarified that the real number was around 1,200. Kevin Bankston, the Director of New America’s Open Technology Institute, issued a statement which called for Congressional investigation into the false numbers and arguing that the FBI’s requests for backdoors should be met with skepticism.</description></item><item><title>Debate: Law Enforcement vs. Smartphone Encryption</title><link>/entries/debate-law-enforcement-vs-smartphone-encryption-d2d753c0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/debate-law-enforcement-vs-smartphone-encryption-d2d753c0/</guid><description>Authors: New America
Published: November 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/events/debate-on-law-enforcement-vs-smartphone-encryption/
Abstract: This debate features former government officials, technologists, and privacy advocates about encryption being offered as a default on smartphones. One side argues that this move will deprive law enforcement of the ability to seek evidence, even with a warrant, and discusses the possible near for congressional action to require companies to allow law enforcement access. The other side argues that such laws would undermine security and privacy, and disadvantage US technology makers.</description></item><item><title>Doomed to Repeat History? Lessons from the Crypto Wars of the 1990s</title><link>/entries/doomed-to-repeat-history-lessons-from-the-crypto-w-d9384864/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/doomed-to-repeat-history-lessons-from-the-crypto-w-d9384864/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle and Wilson, Andi and Bankston, Kevin
Published: June 2015
Abstract: On June 17, 2015, the Open Technology Institute at New America published a report on the history of the debate between private companies, privacy advocates, and the United States government regarding “the right to use and distribute products that contain strong encryption technology.” Topics discussed include the history of encryption before this policy debate emerged in the 1990s, the fight over Clipper Chips and key escrow, the fight over encryption export controls, the “post-war” proof that privacy experts and technology companies were right “that strong encryption is good for security, liberty, and economic growth”, and the attempts by the government to reopen the debate.</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad Idea</title><link>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</guid><description>Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Abstract: In April 2015, OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston was schedule to testify before the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform’s Subcommittee on Information Technology regarding backdoor mandates and potential U.S. policy responses. New America published this blog post, on April 28, 2015, summarizing Bankston’s prepared statement and highlighting the ten key reasons Bankston identified against backdoor mandates. The reasons identified by Bankston were: 1) surveillance backdoors were already rejected as a policy approach two decades ago, including by Congress; 2) it would seriously undermine U.</description></item><item><title>Surveillance Costs: The NSA's Impact on the Economy, Internet Freedom \&amp; Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/surveillance-costs-the-nsa-s-impact-on-the-economy-5c789458/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/surveillance-costs-the-nsa-s-impact-on-the-economy-5c789458/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle and Bankston, Kevin and Greene, Robyn and Morgus, Robert
Published: July 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/policy-papers/surveillance-costs-the-nsas-impact-on-the-economy-internet-freedom-cybersecurity/
Abstract: It has been over a year since The Guardian reported the first story on the National Security Agency’s surveillance programs based on the leaks from former NSA contractor Edward Snowden, yet the national conversation remains largely mired in a simplistic debate over the tradeoffs between national security and individual privacy. It is time to start weighing the overall costs and benefits more broadly.</description></item><item><title>The Human Rights Benefits of Encryption</title><link>/entries/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption-9be91f1d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption-9be91f1d/</guid><description>Authors: Andi Wilson Thompson
Published: March 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption/
Abstract: The Human Rights Benefits of Encryption is a blog post detailing public interest organizations&amp;rsquo; efforts to have encryption recognized as a right by the UN Human Rights Council. This article describes submissions by a multitude of public interest organizations—including the ACLU, Human Rights Watch, and technology-specific organizations—and their arguments for the importance of encryption to free expression, privacy, and human rights.</description></item></channel></rss>