<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>End-to-End Encryption on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/end-to-end-encryption/</link><description>Recent content in End-to-End Encryption on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/end-to-end-encryption/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Congress, Not the Attorney General, Should Decide the Future of Encryption</title><link>/entries/congress-not-the-attorney-general-should-decide-th-61477972/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/congress-not-the-attorney-general-should-decide-th-61477972/</guid><description>Authors: Rozenshtein, Alan Z.
Published: February 2020
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/congress-not-attorney-general-should-decide-future-encryption
Abstract: Alan Z. Rozenshtein, Associate Professor of Law at the University of Minnesota Law School, warns of the dangers of forgoing end-to-end encryption, an anticipated consequence of the powers granted to the attorney general, in the circulating draft of the EARN IT Act. Rozenshtein argues, “the question of whether to permit ubiquitous encryption is the sort of high-level policy decision that is best handled not by the executive branch but by Congress,” recommends against the legislature “shirk[ing] its responsibility to make this tough decision,” and, in the context of the Act, calls for the exclusion of anything encryption-related from the list of best practices.</description></item><item><title>Content-Oblivious Trust and Safety Techniques: Results from a Survey of Online Service Providers</title><link>/entries/content-oblivious-trust-and-safety-techniques-resu-bd3a0a7e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/content-oblivious-trust-and-safety-techniques-resu-bd3a0a7e/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Abstract: Riana Pfefferkorn, research scholar at the Stanford Internet Observatory, describes a survey of online service providers regarding their online trust and safety techniques. She concludes that content-dependent techniques are not a “silver bullet against abuse” and that any marginal inhibiting effect of using end-to-end encryption will vary by abuse type. Instead, she encourages greater consideration of what she calls “content-oblivious” techniques in the ongoing policy debate regarding providers’ anti-abuse obligations and their use of end-to-end encryption.</description></item><item><title>Former GCHQ Boss Backs End-to-End Encryption</title><link>/entries/former-gchq-boss-backs-end-to-end-encryption-8c807a3b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/former-gchq-boss-backs-end-to-end-encryption-8c807a3b/</guid><description>Authors: Leyden, John
Published: July 2017
URL: https://www.theregister.co.uk/2017/07/10/former_gchq_wades_into_encryption_debate/
Abstract: In July of 2017, John Leyden of The Register, wrote regarding a statement made by former GCHQ Director Robert Hannigan against proposals to build backdoors into end-to-end encryption programs. In an interview with BBC Radio 4’s program Today, Hannigan explained “encryption is overwhelmingly a good thing. It keep us all safe and secure.” Rather than building in backdoors or “un-invent[ing] encryption,” Hannigan expressed support for cooperation between private tech companies and government agencies to “find a way around it,” by “target[ing] the people who are abusing&amp;rdquo; encryption systems and going after their smartphones or laptops through alternative means.</description></item><item><title>Open Letter to Mark Zuckerberg: Facebook's End-to-End Security Plans</title><link>/entries/open-letter-to-mark-zuckerberg-facebook-s-end-to-e-81bc1514/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/open-letter-to-mark-zuckerberg-facebook-s-end-to-e-81bc1514/</guid><description>Published: October 2019
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/open-letter-facebooks-end-to-end-encryption-plans/
Abstract: Letter in support of end-to-end encryption from 112 signatory groups/associations.</description></item><item><title>Outside Looking In: Approaches to Content Moderation in End-to-End Encrypted Systems</title><link>/entries/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderatio-3fcad0c7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderatio-3fcad0c7/</guid><description>Authors: Kamara, Seny, Knodel, Mallory, Llansó, Emma, Nojeim, Greg, Qin, Lucy, Thakur, Dhanaraj, Vogus, Caitlin
Published: August 2021
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderation-in-end-to-end-encrypted-systems/
Abstract: A group of researchers at the Center for Technology and Democracy orient the ongoing content moderation/end-to-end-encryption debate within the history of the Crypto Wars and analyze the strength of central competing claims. Content detection, and the obstacle of end-to-end-encryption, is only the latest permutation in the ongoing dialogue between law enforcement investigative capabilities and competing values including privacy, freedom of expression, and secure ecommerce.</description></item></channel></rss>