<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interactive on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/interactive/</link><description>Recent content in Interactive on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/interactive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crypto Summit 2.0 Outcomes Report Track 2</title><link>/entries/crypto-summit-2-0-outcomes-report-track-2-d37df90e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/crypto-summit-2-0-outcomes-report-track-2-d37df90e/</guid><description>Authors: Augusto Liguori Filho, Carlos and Kenzo dos Santos, Guilherme and Favaretto Salvador, João Pedro and Guimarães, Tatiane B.
URL: http://www.fgv.br/direitosp/cryptomap/eng/#home
Abstract: The “CryptoMap” is an interactive digital map project, conducted by the Center for Education and Research in Innovation (CEPI) at Fundação Getulio Vargas São Paulo Law School (FGV Direito SP), in Brazil, that seeks to map the international debate on encryption regulation. Each of the 40 countries on the map features a clickable “CryptoPedia” entry (a short summary of the country’s encryption policies), alongside an access link to a “Descriptive Pill,” which describes the country’s domestic privacy policies, encryption regulations, and the government’s access to encrypted data in greater detail.</description></item><item><title>World Map of Encryption Laws and Policies</title><link>/entries/world-map-of-encryption-laws-and-policies-af6d8b94/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/world-map-of-encryption-laws-and-policies-af6d8b94/</guid><description>Authors: Global Partners Digital
URL: https://www.gp-digital.org/world-map-of-encryption/
Abstract: This interactive map provides an overview of encryption laws throughout the world. The law categorized nations by minimal, some, and widespread restrictions, as well as imposing filters based on specific law or policy measures.</description></item></channel></rss>