<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Key Recovery on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/key-recovery/</link><description>Recent content in Key Recovery on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/key-recovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A “Stumbling” US Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/97/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/97/</guid><description>Authors: Madsen, Wayne
Published: July 1997
URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1361372397895486
Tags: 1990s Clinton Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls Key Recovery Abstract: “Are those in opposition to the administration&amp;rsquo;s [encryption] policy prepared to sacrifice public safety in the interests of commercial gain?” Those words, uttered by Deputy Assistant Attorney General Robert Litt, would etch themselves in the minds of those who attended the 7 May 1977 House International Economic Policy and Trade hearing on “Encryption: Individual Rights vs National Security”.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Policy for the 21st Century: A Future Without Government-Prescribed Key Recovery</title><link>/entries/66/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/66/</guid><description>Authors: Singleton, Solveig
Published: November 1998
URL: https://www.cato.org/sites/cato.org/files/pubs/pdf/pa325.pdf
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Key Recovery</description></item><item><title>The Risks of Key Recovery, Key Escrow, and Trusted Third-Party Encryption</title><link>/entries/28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/28/</guid><description>Authors: H. Abelson, R. Anderson, S. M. Bellovin, J. Benaloh, M. Blaze, W. Diffie, J. Gilmore, P. G. Neumann, R. L. Rivest, J. I. Schiller, B. Schneier
Published: 1998
URL: https://www.schneier.com/academic/archives/1997/04/the_risks_of_key_rec.html
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Key Escrow Key Recovery Abstract: A variety of &amp;ldquo;key recovery,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;key escrow,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;trusted third-party&amp;rdquo; encryption requirements have been suggested in recent years by government agencies seeking to conduct covert surveillance within the changing environments brought about by new technologies.</description></item></channel></rss>