<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2020s on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/2020s/</link><description>Recent content in 2020s on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/2020s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Congress, Not the Attorney General, Should Decide the Future of Encryption</title><link>/entries/congress-not-the-attorney-general-should-decide-th-61477972/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/congress-not-the-attorney-general-should-decide-th-61477972/</guid><description>Authors: Rozenshtein, Alan Z.
Published: February 2020
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/congress-not-attorney-general-should-decide-future-encryption
Abstract: Alan Z. Rozenshtein, Associate Professor of Law at the University of Minnesota Law School, warns of the dangers of forgoing end-to-end encryption, an anticipated consequence of the powers granted to the attorney general, in the circulating draft of the EARN IT Act. Rozenshtein argues, “the question of whether to permit ubiquitous encryption is the sort of high-level policy decision that is best handled not by the executive branch but by Congress,” recommends against the legislature “shirk[ing] its responsibility to make this tough decision,” and, in the context of the Act, calls for the exclusion of anything encryption-related from the list of best practices.</description></item><item><title>Content-Oblivious Trust and Safety Techniques: Results from a Survey of Online Service Providers</title><link>/entries/content-oblivious-trust-and-safety-techniques-resu-bd3a0a7e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/content-oblivious-trust-and-safety-techniques-resu-bd3a0a7e/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Abstract: Modern-day online services are plagued by various kinds of harmful content, from hate speech to terrorist propaganda to depictions of the sexual abuse of children, to name just a few. Regulators’ focus on content analysis overlooks the prevalence and utility of what this article calls content-oblivious techniques. This article presents the results of a survey about the trust and safety techniques employed by a group of online service providers, most of them communications services or services driven primarily by user-generated content.</description></item><item><title>Decryption Originalism: The Lessons of Burr</title><link>/entries/decryption-originalism-the-lessons-of-burr-a1d594eb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/decryption-originalism-the-lessons-of-burr-a1d594eb/</guid><description>Authors: Kerr, Orin
Published: February 2020
URL: https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=3533069
Abstract: The Supreme Court is likely to rule soon on how the Fifth Amendment privilege against self-incrimination applies to compelled decryption of a digital device. When the Court rules, the original understanding of the Fifth Amendment may control the outcome. This Article details an extraordinary case that illuminates the original understanding of the privilege and its application to compelled decryption. During the 1807 treason trial of Aaron Burr, with Chief Justice John Marshall presiding, the government asked Burr’s private secretary if he knew the cipher to an encrypted letter Burr had sent to a co-conspirator.</description></item><item><title>DOJ Plans to Strike Against Encryption While the Techlash Iron Is Hot</title><link>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2020
URL: /blog/2020/02/doj-plans-strike-against-encryption-while-techlash-iron-hot</description></item><item><title>Outside Looking In: Approaches to Content Moderation in End-to-End Encrypted Systems</title><link>/entries/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderatio-3fcad0c7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderatio-3fcad0c7/</guid><description>Authors: Kamara, Seny, Knodel, Mallory, Llansó, Emma, Nojeim, Greg, Qin, Lucy, Thakur, Dhanaraj, Vogus, Caitlin
Published: August 2021
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderation-in-end-to-end-encrypted-systems/
Abstract: A new front has opened up in the Crypto Wars: content moderation. As billions of people around the world began to use encrypted services to protect their privacy and data when communicating with others, the concerns of law enforcement agencies regained prominence in the last decade. But encryption is not just a law enforcement issue.</description></item><item><title>SS7 Hack Explained: What Can You Do About It?</title><link>/entries/ss7-hack-explained-what-can-you-do-about-it-2ca330ad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ss7-hack-explained-what-can-you-do-about-it-2ca330ad/</guid><description>Authors: Gibbs, Samuel
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/apr/19/ss7-hack-explained-mobile-phone-vulnerability-snooping-texts-calls
Abstract: A vulnerability means hackers can read texts, listen to calls and track mobile phone users. What are the implications and how can you protect yourself from snooping?</description></item><item><title>The EARN IT Act Is Unconstitutional: Fourth Amendment</title><link>/entries/the-earn-it-act-is-unconstitutional-fourth-amendme-a7207348/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-earn-it-act-is-unconstitutional-fourth-amendme-a7207348/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: March 2020
URL: /blog/2020/03/earn-it-act-unconstitutional-fourth-amendment</description></item><item><title>The Law and Policy of Client-Side Scanning</title><link>/entries/the-law-and-policy-of-client-side-scanning-7598c301/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-law-and-policy-of-client-side-scanning-7598c301/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenzweig, Paul
Published: August 2020
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/law-and-policy-client-side-scanning
Abstract: The idea of Client-Side Scanning—which aims to develop systems to scan photographs and messages before they are sent or received by users—is attractive, but it has far too many technical, legal and policy uncertainties to be ripe for adoption at this time.</description></item></channel></rss>