<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2020s on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/2020s/</link><description>Recent content in 2020s on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/2020s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Congress, Not the Attorney General, Should Decide the Future of Encryption</title><link>/entries/congress-not-the-attorney-general-should-decide-th-61477972/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/congress-not-the-attorney-general-should-decide-th-61477972/</guid><description>Authors: Rozenshtein, Alan Z.
Published: February 2020
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/congress-not-attorney-general-should-decide-future-encryption
Abstract: Alan Z. Rozenshtein, Associate Professor of Law at the University of Minnesota Law School, warns of the dangers of forgoing end-to-end encryption, an anticipated consequence of the powers granted to the attorney general, in the circulating draft of the EARN IT Act. Rozenshtein argues, “the question of whether to permit ubiquitous encryption is the sort of high-level policy decision that is best handled not by the executive branch but by Congress,” recommends against the legislature “shirk[ing] its responsibility to make this tough decision,” and, in the context of the Act, calls for the exclusion of anything encryption-related from the list of best practices.</description></item><item><title>Content-Oblivious Trust and Safety Techniques: Results from a Survey of Online Service Providers</title><link>/entries/content-oblivious-trust-and-safety-techniques-resu-bd3a0a7e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/content-oblivious-trust-and-safety-techniques-resu-bd3a0a7e/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
URL: https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3920031
Abstract: Riana Pfefferkorn, research scholar at the Stanford Internet Observatory, describes a survey of online service providers regarding their online trust and safety techniques. She concludes that content-dependent techniques are not a “silver bullet against abuse” and that any marginal inhibiting effect of using end-to-end encryption will vary by abuse type. Instead, she encourages greater consideration of what she calls “content-oblivious” techniques in the ongoing policy debate regarding providers’ anti-abuse obligations and their use of end-to-end encryption.</description></item><item><title>Decryption Originalism: The Lessons of Burr</title><link>/entries/decryption-originalism-the-lessons-of-burr-a1d594eb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/decryption-originalism-the-lessons-of-burr-a1d594eb/</guid><description>Authors: Kerr, Orin
Published: February 2020
URL: https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=3533069
Abstract: This law review article by Orin Kerr describes Fifth Amendment arguments in the treason trial against Aaron Burr and their application potential application to a Supreme Court case regarding encryption. The 1807 trial of Aaron Burr was exhaustively documented and therefore is able to shed light on the founder’s original intent of the Fifth Amendment’s prohibition on self-incrimination. Kerr applies these underlying intents and principles of the Fifth Amendment and applies them to the modern debate on encryption.</description></item><item><title>DOJ Plans to Strike Against Encryption While the Techlash Iron Is Hot</title><link>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2020
URL: /blog/2020/02/doj-plans-strike-against-encryption-while-techlash-iron-hot
Abstract: This blog post by Riana Pfefferkorn argues that since 2016, the Department of Justice sought to capitalize on public anti-technology sentiment to weaken encryption. First, the article describes the political climate, shaped by the Apple v FBI case, the role of big tech in various privacy scandals and foreign interference in the 2016 election, and foreign legislation, particularly in Australia and the U.</description></item><item><title>Outside Looking In: Approaches to Content Moderation in End-to-End Encrypted Systems</title><link>/entries/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderatio-3fcad0c7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderatio-3fcad0c7/</guid><description>Authors: Kamara, Seny, Knodel, Mallory, Llansó, Emma, Nojeim, Greg, Qin, Lucy, Thakur, Dhanaraj, Vogus, Caitlin
Published: August 2021
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderation-in-end-to-end-encrypted-systems/
Abstract: A group of researchers at the Center for Technology and Democracy orient the ongoing content moderation/end-to-end-encryption debate within the history of the Crypto Wars and analyze the strength of central competing claims. Content detection, and the obstacle of end-to-end-encryption, is only the latest permutation in the ongoing dialogue between law enforcement investigative capabilities and competing values including privacy, freedom of expression, and secure ecommerce.</description></item><item><title>SS7 Hack Explained: What Can You Do About It?</title><link>/entries/ss7-hack-explained-what-can-you-do-about-it-2ca330ad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ss7-hack-explained-what-can-you-do-about-it-2ca330ad/</guid><description>Authors: Gibbs, Samuel
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/apr/19/ss7-hack-explained-mobile-phone-vulnerability-snooping-texts-calls
Abstract: This article explains the SS7 hack—which allowed hackers to listen to phone calls, read texts, and track mobile phones—recounts what lead to the hack, and gives solutions for people to protect their data. The article, geared towards a law audience, explains how systems can be hacked and what can be done about it, both by a consumer and by companies and the government.</description></item><item><title>The EARN IT Act Is Unconstitutional: Fourth Amendment</title><link>/entries/the-earn-it-act-is-unconstitutional-fourth-amendme-a7207348/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-earn-it-act-is-unconstitutional-fourth-amendme-a7207348/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: March 2020
URL: http://cyberlaw.stanford.edu/blog/2020/03/earn-it-act-unconstitutional-fourth-amendment
Abstract: This blog post outlines the argument that proposed legislation entitled the EARN IT Act is unconstitutional on Fourth Amendment Grounds. The Post argues that the Act would require online service providers to actively scan for Child Sexual Abuse Materials, rather than merely reporting it when it is found. By requiring providers to conduct these searches, the providers would become state actors and the searches would require a warrant, and without a warrant, these searches would be unconstitutional under the fourth amendment, and the evidence would be excluded in court proceedings.</description></item><item><title>The Last Refuge of the Criminal: Encrypted Smartphones</title><link>/entries/the-last-refuge-of-the-criminal-encrypted-smartpho-ba7ee311/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-last-refuge-of-the-criminal-encrypted-smartpho-ba7ee311/</guid><description>Authors: de Bolle, Catherine, Vance, Cyrus R., Jr.
Published: July 2021
URL: https://www.politico.eu/article/the-last-refuge-of-the-criminal-encrypted-smartphones-data-privacy/
Abstract: Catherine de Bolle and Cyrus R. Vance, Jr., write in Politico that encrypted devices—particularly encrypted smartphones—pose an intolerable impediment to law enforcement, the pursuit of justice, and vindication of victims and their families. They argue that criminals exploit unregulated encryption to perpetrate a variety of crimes, from ransomware to child sex trafficking, and that the ability to lawfully access devices is overwhelmingly frustrated by judges, policies, and budgets.</description></item><item><title>The Law and Policy of Client-Side Scanning</title><link>/entries/the-law-and-policy-of-client-side-scanning-7598c301/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-law-and-policy-of-client-side-scanning-7598c301/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenzweig, Paul
Published: August 2020
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/law-and-policy-client-side-scanning
Abstract: Paul Rosenzweig, former Deputy Assistant Secretary for Policy in the Department of Homeland Security, and founder of a homeland security consulting company, writes an analysis of client-side scanning published by the Lawfare Institute in cooperation with the Brookings Institute. He concludes that, while client-side scanning offers attractive protective capabilities to meet the rise of online-distributed child pornography via encrypted systems, its adoption at its current nascent stage would be nonetheless undesirable due to technological, legal, and policy uncertainties.</description></item><item><title>We Need More Protection from Government Surveillance — Not Less</title><link>/entries/we-need-more-protection-from-government-surveillan-33e5e137/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/we-need-more-protection-from-government-surveillan-33e5e137/</guid><description>Authors: McGowan, Iverna, Naranjo, Diego, Koomen, Maria, Beltrà, Guillermo, Preiss, Omri, Massé, Estelle, Cohn, Cindy, Stollmeyer, Alice, Bukovská, Barbora, Dusepulchre, Gaelle, Anderson, Andrew, Skoric, Vanja, Westby, Joe, Keller, Paul
Published: July 2021
URL: https://www.politico.eu/article/we-need-more-protection-government-surveillance-not-less/
Abstract: A group of user- and human-rights advocates jointly write an article published by Politico in response to Catherine de Bolle and Cyrus R. Vance, Jr.s, &amp;ldquo;The Last Refuge of the Criminal: Encypted Smartphones.&amp;rdquo; They describe the importance of encryption to democracy and human rights in the face of increasing pressure by government for tech-company-assisted surveillance, citing multiple groups that depend upon encryption for privacy and physical safety: from investigative journalists to subjects of authoritarian governments to members of the LGBTQ+ community.</description></item></channel></rss>