<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Foreign Concerns on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/foreign-concerns/</link><description>Recent content in Foreign Concerns on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/foreign-concerns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Old Technopanic in New iBottles</title><link>/entries/155/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/155/</guid><description>Authors: Julian Sanchez
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.cato.org/blog/old-technopanic-new-ibottles
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Foreign Concerns Mobile Abstract: If we aim to preserve an “equilibrium” between government power and citizen privacy, we should accept that it will occasionally close one as well.</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad IDea</title><link>/entries/48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/48/</guid><description>Authors: New America: OTI
Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Tags: 2010s Amendment I Backdoors Cybersecurity Economic Impact Foreign Concerns Going Dark Human Rights OTI Primer SAFE Act Surveillance Abstract: In testimony before House Oversight and Government Reform Committee today, Bankston pushes back against legislative fixes to limit the avail</description></item><item><title>RightsCon Silicon Valley 2016 Session Videos</title><link>/entries/42/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/42/</guid><description>Authors: RightsCon
Published: 2016
URL: https://www.rightscon.org/rightscon-silicon-valley-2016-videos/
Tags: 2010s Amendment I Crypto Summit Cyber Attacks Data Breaches Domestic Concerns Foreign Concerns Personal Privacy Primer Terrorism</description></item><item><title>The NSA’s Split-Key Encryption Proposal is Not Serious</title><link>/entries/145/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/145/</guid><description>Authors: Joseph Lorenzo Hall
Published: April 2015
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-serious/
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Backdoors-Feasibility Center for Democracy and Technology Foreign Concerns Going Dark Abstract: The US Government has been busy on the encryption front in both positive and negative ways. On the positive front, there is a major effort underway to move all government websites to HTTPS; I’ll discuss that in a future post. But on the problematic and negative side of the ledger, we once again turn to …</description></item></channel></rss>