<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Center for Democracy and Technology on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/center-for-democracy-and-technology/</link><description>Recent content in Center for Democracy and Technology on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/center-for-democracy-and-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Outside Looking In: Approaches to Content Moderation in End-to-End Encrypted Systems</title><link>/entries/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderatio-3fcad0c7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderatio-3fcad0c7/</guid><description>Authors: Kamara, Seny, Knodel, Mallory, Llansó, Emma, Nojeim, Greg, Qin, Lucy, Thakur, Dhanaraj, Vogus, Caitlin
Published: August 2021
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderation-in-end-to-end-encrypted-systems/
Abstract: A group of researchers at the Center for Technology and Democracy orient the ongoing content moderation/end-to-end-encryption debate within the history of the Crypto Wars and analyze the strength of central competing claims. Content detection, and the obstacle of end-to-end-encryption, is only the latest permutation in the ongoing dialogue between law enforcement investigative capabilities and competing values including privacy, freedom of expression, and secure ecommerce.</description></item><item><title>The Human Rights Benefits of Encryption</title><link>/entries/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption-9be91f1d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption-9be91f1d/</guid><description>Authors: Andi Wilson Thompson
Published: March 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption/
Abstract: The Human Rights Benefits of Encryption is a blog post detailing public interest organizations&amp;rsquo; efforts to have encryption recognized as a right by the UN Human Rights Council. This article describes submissions by a multitude of public interest organizations—including the ACLU, Human Rights Watch, and technology-specific organizations—and their arguments for the importance of encryption to free expression, privacy, and human rights.</description></item><item><title>The NSA’s Split-Key Encryption Proposal is Not Serious</title><link>/entries/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-seri-126e61d2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-seri-126e61d2/</guid><description>Authors: Joseph Lorenzo Hall
Published: April 2015
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-serious/
Abstract: The NSA&amp;rsquo;s Split-Key Encryption Proposal is Not Serious discusses the NSA&amp;rsquo;s 2020 proposal to require technology companies to create a &amp;ldquo;golden key,&amp;rdquo; a split-key that would allow the company or the NSA access to encrypted communications. Hall argues that split-key encryption is a technology infeasible, vulnerable, and costly, and would not be able to ensure any data was protected from the NSA.</description></item></channel></rss>