<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Crypto Wars II on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/crypto-wars-ii/</link><description>Recent content in Crypto Wars II on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/crypto-wars-ii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Congress Mulls Stiff Crypto Laws</title><link>/entries/78/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/78/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/09/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws/
Tags: 2000s 9/11 Crypto Wars Crypto Wars II National Security Terrorism Abstract: Some lawmakers say encryption laws can let terrorists plot attacks such as Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s assaults on the East Coast. Congress is considering a crypto-crackdown. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>Disputes on Electronic Message Encryption Take on New Urgency</title><link>/entries/138/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/138/</guid><description>Authors: Schwartz, John
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2001/09/25/business/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-new-urgency.html
Tags: 2000s 9/11 Crypto Wars Crypto Wars II Terrorism Abstract: Attacks of Sept 11 renew debate on how strongly public&amp;ndash;and by extension terrorists and other criminals&amp;ndash;should be able to encrypt their electronic messages; technology of scrambling data and messages has become crucial element of computer security for businesses and consumers; officials of law enforcement and intelligence agencies have long warned lawmakers that they were unable to break strongest encryption products, and that crimes eventually would be committed that might otherwise have been prevented; FBI has not said publicly whether hijackers who attacked World Trade Center and Pentagon even used encryption to cloak their communications; Philip R Zimmermann, creator of popular encryption programs, known as PGP, says he would be surprised if this were not case; Sen Judd Gregg says he will not make specific legislative proposal until he sees what Atty Gen John Ashcroft includes in final version of his broad anti-terrorism bill; says he wants to see legislation to order encryption companies that sell products in US to include back door that would allow government access when terrorist uses encyption (M)</description></item><item><title>Encryption and the Press Clause</title><link>/entries/70/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/70/</guid><description>Authors: Baranetsky, D Victoria
Published: 2017
Tags: 2010s Amendment I Apple Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Crypto Wars II Journalism San Bernardino Abstract: Almost twenty years ago, a hostile debate over whether government could regulate encryption—later named the Crypto Wars—seized the country. At the center of this debate stirred one simple question: is encryption protected speech? This issue touched all branches of government percolating from Congress, to the President, and eventually to the federal courts.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Encryption and Potential Mechanisms for Authorized Government Access to Plaintext: Proceedings of a Workshop</title><link>/entries/202/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/202/</guid><description>Authors: Anne Johnson, Jon Eisenberg, Emily Grumbling
Published: 2016
Tags: 2010s Crypto Wars I Crypto Wars II</description></item><item><title>Senator Backs Off Backdoors</title><link>/entries/37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/37/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: October 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/10/senator-backs-off-backdoors/
Tags: 2000s Backdoors Crypto Wars Crypto Wars II US Congress Abstract: A senator changes his mind after calling for a prohibition on data-scrambling products without backdoors for government surveillance. Now, he &amp;ldquo;has no intentions&amp;rdquo; of working on such an encryption bill. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>Techies Urge Senator To Drop Encryption Key Plan</title><link>/entries/148/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/148/</guid><description>Authors: Brian Krebs
Published: October 2001
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20011011022244/http://www.newsbytes.com/news/01/170592.html
Tags: 2000s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars II</description></item></channel></rss>