<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clinton on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/clinton/</link><description>Recent content in Clinton on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/clinton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Flawed Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/a-flawed-encryption-policy-218380c7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/a-flawed-encryption-policy-218380c7/</guid><description>Authors: Anonymous
Published: October 1996
URL: https://search.proquest.com/docview/430685501/fulltext/2EA1B6B49BC74036PQ/1?accountid=14503
Abstract: This editorial in the New York Times argues that the Clinton Administration’s proposal to prevent the dissemination of encryption software to terrorists or criminals was both unworkable and presented risks to US commerce. The article discusses how industry and public interest advocates rejected the Administration’s proposals based on concerns about censorship, and the unworkability of the plan on practical grounds, including foreign unwillingness to acquiesce to potential surveillance by the U.</description></item><item><title>A “Stumbling” US Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/a-stumbling-us-encryption-policy-872ec273/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/a-stumbling-us-encryption-policy-872ec273/</guid><description>Authors: Madsen, Wayne
Published: July 1997
URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1361372397895486
Abstract: This article describes a 1997 hearing in the House of Representatives to discuss the SAFE Act, which would relax US encryption export controls. Administration officials sought to defend current key recovery policies and differentiate them from the Clipper Chip, while Representatives criticized them as unworkable, due to the necessary international cooperation. In discussing the SAFE ACT, industry representatives largely supported the bill and urged for minimal government restrictions.</description></item><item><title>Another Faulty Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/another-faulty-encryption-policy-092ca4e3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/another-faulty-encryption-policy-092ca4e3/</guid><description>Published: December 1996
URL: https://search.proquest.com/docview/430702910/fulltext/CAF9E584F5344769PQ/1?accountid=14503
Abstract: On December 16, 1996, the New York Times published an editorial piece criticizing the unworkability and risks associated with the (then) newest Clinton Administration plan to control the export of encryption software. The editorial expressed concerns related to infringement of privacy rights and damage to United States software firms, which would lose business as a result of the availability of less intrusive encryption software from foreign firms.</description></item><item><title>Clinton Administration Announces New Cybersecurity Proposals</title><link>/entries/clinton-administration-announces-new-cybersecurity-6826eb57/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/clinton-administration-announces-new-cybersecurity-6826eb57/</guid><description>Authors: Libbie Schlatheri
Published: July 2000
Abstract: On July 17, 2000, Libbie Schlatheir, a producer for CNN, issued a report detailing announcements by Clinton Administration officials regarding updates to its policy for encryption exports to the European Union and key trading partners. The updates, attributed largely to a speech by Clinton White House Chief of Staff, John Podesta, at the National Press Club, “liberalize[d] export controls on encryption, allowing more companies to export the technology to more end users… while maintaining a framework necessary to protect [U.</description></item><item><title>Clinton Administration Encryption Policy Statement \&amp; Press Briefing</title><link>/entries/clinton-administration-encryption-policy-statement-cdde72d2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/clinton-administration-encryption-policy-statement-cdde72d2/</guid><description>Published: September 1998
URL: https://congressional.proquest.com/congressional</description></item><item><title>Clinton Removes Export Limits on Encryption Technology</title><link>/entries/clinton-removes-export-limits-on-encryption-techno-9f78e038/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/clinton-removes-export-limits-on-encryption-techno-9f78e038/</guid><description>Authors: Gerstenzang, James
Published: September 1999
URL: https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1999-sep-17-fi-11110-story.html
Abstract: In September of 1999, James Gerstenzang, a staff writer for the Los Angeles Times, reported on the Clinton Administration decision to liberalize export requirements on encryption technology. Gerstenzang’s report details the political dynamics at play leading up to and anticipated to follow the decision. This analysis includes statements from Clinton Administration cabinet officials, such as Attorney General, Janet Reno, and Deputy Assistant for National Security Affairs, James B.</description></item><item><title>Encryption and the First Amendment</title><link>/entries/encryption-and-the-first-amendment-333ee479/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-and-the-first-amendment-333ee479/</guid><description>Authors: Samoriski, Jan H. and Huffman, John L. and Trauth, Denise M.
Published: September 1997
URL: https://doi.org/10.1080/10811689709368633
Abstract: This law review article by Jan H. Samoriski, John L. Huffman, and Denise M. Trauth describes finds that Clinton Administration proposals on encryption policy, including the Clipper Chip initiatives, encryption key escrow, and domestic restrictions on encryption infringe on the privacy interests of individuals and likely violate the First Amendment. The article first described the development of encryption policy through the &amp;rsquo;90s.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Control 'Unconstitutional'</title><link>/entries/encryption-control-unconstitutional-b86acf50/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-control-unconstitutional-b86acf50/</guid><description>Authors: The Associated Press
Published: September 1997
Abstract: In August of 1997, the Associated Press wrote regarding the decision of U.S. District Judge Marilyn Hall Patel to hold the Clinton Administration’s regulations prohibiting the electronic export of computer encryption without a Commerce Department license as a violation of the First Amendment of the U.S. Constitution. Judge Patel’s order prohibited enforcement of the regulation against a mathematics professor from the University of Illinois at Chicago, Daniel Bernstein, and his encryption program, Snuffle.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Export Controls</title><link>/entries/encryption-export-controls-1714ec24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-export-controls-1714ec24/</guid><description>Authors: Grimmett, Jeanne J.
Published: January 2001
Abstract: This report from the Congressional Research Service discusses existing U.S. export controls on encryption software, First Amendment Challenges to licensing regimes, and proposed export control legislation. First, the report provides background on both the Arms Export Control Act and the Export Administration Act, and how those statutory structures applied to governmental and commercial encryption software. Second, the report summarizes Federal Court decisions regarding the First Amendment in encryption, generally deciding cases based on whether the encryption was functional or expressive.</description></item><item><title>Encryption: A 21st Century National Security Dilemma</title><link>/entries/encryption-a-21st-century-national-security-dilemm-bc971f67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-a-21st-century-national-security-dilemm-bc971f67/</guid><description>Authors: Ackerman, Wystan M.
Published: July 1998
URL: https://doi.org/10.1080/13600869855487
Abstract: In 1998, an article was published in the International Review of Law, Computers &amp;amp; Technology, which advocated for the implementation of a federal encryption scheme which utilizes export controls and a key recovery system. Export controls should be used to address issues with gathering foreign intelligence for national security matters, and a key recovery system should be used to meet the needs of law enforcement when they conduct investigations.</description></item><item><title>Executive Order 13026 - Administration of Export Controls on Encryption Products</title><link>/entries/executive-order-13026-administration-of-export-con-edfd5315/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/executive-order-13026-administration-of-export-con-edfd5315/</guid><description>Published: November 1996
Abstract: On November 15, 1996, President William J. Clinton issued Executive Order 13026— Administration of Export Controls on Encryption Products. This Executive Order revised the provisions of the export control system maintained by the Department of Commerce in the Export Administration Regulations, 15 CFR Part 730 et seq, and amended previously issued Executive Orders 12981 and 13020. The Order transferred certain encryption products from the United States Munitions List to the Commerce Control List; revised the procedures for inter-agency review and disposition of dual-use-export license applications, by adding the Department of Justice to the list of agencies included in the process; and rendered all EAA provisions dealing with the issuance of licenses or removal of controls (based on foreign availability considerations) inapplicable to export controls on select encryption products, however, permitted the Secretary of Commerce to made such considerations on a discretionary basis.</description></item><item><title>First and Fifth Amendment Challenges to Export Controls on Encryption: Bernstein and Karn</title><link>/entries/first-and-fifth-amendment-challenges-to-export-con-41c9888c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/first-and-fifth-amendment-challenges-to-export-con-41c9888c/</guid><description>Authors: Pilkington, Laura M.
Published: 1996
URL: https://heinonline.org/HOL/P?h=hein.journals/saclr37&amp;amp;i=177</description></item><item><title>Software Firms Call U.S. Plan on Encryption 'Unworkable'</title><link>/entries/software-firms-call-u-s-plan-on-encryption-unworka-5550f1d3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/software-firms-call-u-s-plan-on-encryption-unworka-5550f1d3/</guid><description>Authors: Chandrasekaran, Rajiv
Published: December 1996
Abstract: This article details the Business Software Alliance, a software industry group, and its rejection of Clinton Administration export controls as unworkable. This disagreement presented a large roadblock to discussions between industry and government</description></item><item><title>Statement by Commerce Secretary William Daley Re: Administration encryption policy</title><link>/entries/statement-by-commerce-secretary-william-daley-re-a-f1d56237/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/statement-by-commerce-secretary-william-daley-re-a-f1d56237/</guid><description>Authors: Daley, William M.
Published: September 1999
URL: http://www.techlawjournal.com/cong106/encrypt/19990916dal.htm</description></item><item><title>Statement by the Press Secretary</title><link>/entries/statement-by-the-press-secretary-617ea86a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/statement-by-the-press-secretary-617ea86a/</guid><description>Published: April 1993
URL: https://epic.org/crypto/clipper/white_house_statement_4_93.html
Abstract: Statement on the Clipper Chip</description></item><item><title>U.S. Relaxes Export Controls on Supercomputers</title><link>/entries/u-s-relaxes-export-controls-on-supercomputers-a6ca258e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/u-s-relaxes-export-controls-on-supercomputers-a6ca258e/</guid><description>Authors: Diamond, Howard
Published: July 1999
URL: https://www.armscontrol.org/act/1999-07/press-releases/us-relaxes-export-controls-supercomputers
Abstract: This news article details a loosening of export restrictions on supercomputers to various nations on national security and economic grounds that had been tightened several years prior. The article details the process and substance of the loosened restrictions, as well as the political hurdles that had delayed the changes.</description></item></channel></rss>