<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mobile on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/mobile/</link><description>Recent content in Mobile on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apple Will No Longer Unlock Most iPhones, iPads for Police, Even with Search Warrants</title><link>/entries/183/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/183/</guid><description>Authors: Craig Timberg
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/2014/09/17/2612af58-3ed2-11e4-b03f-de718edeb92f_story.html
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Mobile Abstract: New operating system makes it impossible for company to comply with requests for data on devices.</description></item><item><title>Beyond Secrets: The Consumer Stake in the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/37/</guid><description>Published: December 2017
URL: https://advocacy.consumerreports.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Beyond-Secrets-12.21.17-FINAL.pdf
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Economic Impact Emergency Communications Healthcare Mobile Primer</description></item><item><title>Debate: Law Enforcement vs. Smartphone Encryption</title><link>/entries/185/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/185/</guid><description>Authors: New America
Published: November 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/events/debate-on-law-enforcement-vs-smartphone-encryption/
Tags: 2010s Going Dark Mobile OTI Abstract: The recent decision by Apple and Google to enable encryption by default on new iPhones and Android smartphones, so that only the user can unlock his or her phone, has led to strong complaints from law enforcement agencies arguing that the move will deprive them of critical evidence. The Attorney General and the FBI Director have gone so far as to suggest that Congress may need to step in and tell companies to redesign their products, to ensure that government investigators can access encrypted data or wiretap online communications when they have appropriate legal authority like a search warrant.</description></item><item><title>Decryption Originalism: The Lessons of Burr</title><link>/entries/38/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/38/</guid><description>Authors: Kerr, Orin
Published: February 2020
URL: https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=3533069
Tags: 2020s Amendment V Amendment V / Self Incrimination Mobile Abstract: The Supreme Court is likely to rule soon on how the Fifth Amendment privilege against self-incrimination applies to compelled decryption of a digital device. When the Court rules, the original understanding of the Fifth Amendment may control the outcome. This Article details an extraordinary case that illuminates the original understanding of the privilege and its application to compelled decryption.</description></item><item><title>Ex-MI5 Chief Warns Against Crackdown on Encrypted Messaging Apps</title><link>/entries/43/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/43/</guid><description>Authors: Grierson, Jamie
Published: August 2017
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/aug/11/ex-mi5-chief-warns-against-crackdown-encrypted-messaging-apps
Tags: 2010s Law Enforcement Mobile UK News UK Security and Counter-Terrorism Abstract: Jonathan Evans says although encryption services have hampered terrorism fight he does not support curtailment of its use</description></item><item><title>FBI Blasts Apple, Google for Locking Police out of Phones</title><link>/entries/174/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/174/</guid><description>Authors: Craig Timberg, Greg Miller
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/2014/09/25/68c4e08e-4344-11e4-9a15-137aa0153527_story.html
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Government Access Mobile</description></item><item><title>Federal Bureau of Investigation: FY 2010 Budget Request</title><link>/entries/114/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/114/</guid><description>URL: https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/jmd/legacy/2014/04/12/fbi-bud-summary.pdf
Tags: 2010s Going Dark Mobile National Security Surveillance</description></item><item><title>From Clipper Chip to Smartphones: Unlocking the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/88/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/88/</guid><description>Authors: Flatow, Ira
URL: https://www.sciencefriday.com/segments/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-encryption-debate/
Tags: 1990s 2010s Backdoors Clipper Chip Mobile Primer Abstract: In the ‘90s, the Clipper Chip was the big government encryption case. Two Science Friday guests involved in that early debate rejoin us to weigh in on the Apple argument.</description></item><item><title>Holder Urges Tech Companies to Leave Device Backdoors Open for Police</title><link>/entries/143/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/143/</guid><description>Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2014/09/30/holder-urges-tech-companies-to-leave-device-backdoors-open-for-police/
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Government Access Mobile</description></item><item><title>James Comey, F.B.I. Director, Hints at Action as Cellphone Data Is Locked</title><link>/entries/166/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/166/</guid><description>Authors: David E. Sanger, Matt Apuzzo
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2014/10/17/us/politics/fbi-director-in-policy-speech-calls-dark-devices-hindrance-to-crime-solving.html
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Government Access Mobile Abstract: Mr. Comey said on Thursday that the “post-Snowden pendulum” that has driven Apple and Google to offer fully encrypted cellphones had “gone too far.”</description></item><item><title>Old Technopanic in New iBottles</title><link>/entries/162/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/162/</guid><description>Authors: Julian Sanchez
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.cato.org/blog/old-technopanic-new-ibottles
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Foreign Concerns Mobile Abstract: If we aim to preserve an “equilibrium” between government power and citizen privacy, we should accept that it will occasionally close one as well.</description></item><item><title>Russia Wants to Make an Example of Telegram</title><link>/entries/56/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/56/</guid><description>Authors: Bershidsky, Leonid
Published: September 2017
URL: https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2017-09-28/russia-wants-to-make-an-example-of-telegram
Tags: 2010s Intelligence Mobile RUS Abstract: The messaging app is under direct attack from Russian domestic intelligence. The real target may be Facebook and Twitter.</description></item><item><title>Security “Front Doors” vs. “Back Doors”: A Distinction Without a Difference</title><link>/entries/159/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/159/</guid><description>Authors: Jeffrey Vagle, Matt Blaze
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.justsecurity.org/16503/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-distinction-difference/
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Backdoors-Feasibility Clipper Chip Golden Key James Comey Law Enforcement Mobile Abstract: Thursday, FBI Director James Comey delivered a talk at the Brookings Institution, titled “Going Dark: Are Technology, Privacy, and Public Safety on a Collision Course?” His thesis did not stray too far from his (and others’) recent calls for limitations on software from companies like Google and Apple that employs strong cryptography that even the …</description></item><item><title>Sources: We Were Pressured to Weaken the Mobile Security in the 80's</title><link>/entries/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/7/</guid><description>Authors: Færaas, Arild
Published: January 2014
URL: https://www.aftenposten.no/article/ap-Olkl.html
Tags: 1980s GSM Global Mobile NSA Abstract: Four men who were part of a group that wrote mobile history tell for the first time how strong protection against eavesdropping of cell phones was weakened.</description></item><item><title>SS7 Hack Explained: What Can You Do About It?</title><link>/entries/59/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/59/</guid><description>Authors: Gibbs, Samuel
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/apr/19/ss7-hack-explained-mobile-phone-vulnerability-snooping-texts-calls
Tags: 2020s Data and Computer Security Hacking Mobile SS7 Surveillance Telecoms World News Abstract: A vulnerability means hackers can read texts, listen to calls and track mobile phone users. What are the implications and how can you protect yourself from snooping?</description></item><item><title>U.S. Tries to Make It Easier to Wiretap the Internet</title><link>/entries/152/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/152/</guid><description>Authors: Savage, Charlie
Published: September 2010
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2010/09/27/us/27wiretap.html
Tags: 2010s CALEA Going Dark Government Access Mobile Surveillance Abstract: Officials are preparing to seek sweeping new regulations, arguing they are losing their capability to track suspects.</description></item></channel></rss>