<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hacking on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/hacking/</link><description>Recent content in Hacking on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hacking/​Journalism</title><link>/entries/hacking-journalism-04dbfbc9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/hacking-journalism-04dbfbc9/</guid><description>Authors: Salvo, Philip Di
Published: April 2017
URL: https://limn.it/articles/hackingjournalism/
Abstract: On May 19, 2011, The Washington Post published an article about one of the ways in which the “boundaries of journalism have expanded” into hacking through the adoption of encryption tools in whistleblowing cases. The article discusses the use of encryption tools in leaks including WikiLeaks’ Afghan and Iraqi War Logs, the Cablegate leaks, the Panama Papers, and Snowden’s leaks. In each of these leaks, encryption “played an enabling role in that whistleblowing” in part because it “played a fundamental part in facilitating communication between the source and the journalists.</description></item><item><title>Newest Androids Will Join iPhones in Offering Default Encryption, Blocking Police</title><link>/entries/newest-androids-will-join-iphones-in-offering-defa-48399d14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/newest-androids-will-join-iphones-in-offering-defa-48399d14/</guid><description>Authors: Timberg, Craig
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2014/09/18/newest-androids-will-join-iphones-in-offering-default-encryption-blocking-police/
Abstract: On September 18, 2014, The Washington Post published an article about the decision by Google to, for the first time, encrypt all data by default in its Android operating system. Previously, the operating system required a user to enable encryption in the device settings, but “few users [knew] how to turn on the feature.” Google made this move in order to be more competitive with Apple’s smartphones, who already encrypt all data by default.</description></item><item><title>SS7 Hack Explained: What Can You Do About It?</title><link>/entries/ss7-hack-explained-what-can-you-do-about-it-2ca330ad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ss7-hack-explained-what-can-you-do-about-it-2ca330ad/</guid><description>Authors: Gibbs, Samuel
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/apr/19/ss7-hack-explained-mobile-phone-vulnerability-snooping-texts-calls
Abstract: This article explains the SS7 hack—which allowed hackers to listen to phone calls, read texts, and track mobile phones—recounts what lead to the hack, and gives solutions for people to protect their data. The article, geared towards a law audience, explains how systems can be hacked and what can be done about it, both by a consumer and by companies and the government.</description></item></channel></rss>