<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1970s on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/1970s/</link><description>Recent content in 1970s on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/1970s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Method for Obtaining Digital Signatures and Public-Key Cryptosystems</title><link>/entries/a-method-for-obtaining-digital-signatures-and-publ-eb215250/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/a-method-for-obtaining-digital-signatures-and-publ-eb215250/</guid><description>Authors: Rivest, R.L. and Shamir, A. and Adleman, L.
Published: April 1977
URL: https://people.csail.mit.edu/rivest/Rsapaper.pdf
Abstract: This technical article discusses an encryption method where revealing an encryption key does not reveal the corresponding decryption key. This article proposes and explains a public-key cryptosystem that would not require a courier to carry the key. Further, the article explains its uses in the context of email, and how it would allow communications to be secure and private.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Secrets</title><link>/entries/keeping-secrets-73be089b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/keeping-secrets-73be089b/</guid><description>Authors: Corrigan-Gibbs, Henry
Published: December 2014
URL: https://stanfordmag.org/contents/keeping-secrets
Abstract: On November 6, 2014, Stanford Magazine published an article about a group of researchers at Stanford who, at the International Symposium on Information Theory on October 10, 1997, ended “the U.S. government’s longstanding domestic monopoly on cryptography”. Prior to the symposium, the group received a letter from an NSA employee who told the group that “merely publishing a scientific paper on cryptography would be the legal equivalent of exporting nuclear weapons to a foreign country.</description></item><item><title>New Directions in Cryptography</title><link>/entries/new-directions-in-cryptography-0e85af23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/new-directions-in-cryptography-0e85af23/</guid><description>Authors: Diffie, Whitfield and Hellman, Martin E.
Published: November 1976
URL: http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/1055638/
Abstract: In November 1976, Whitfield Diffie and Martin E. Hellman, of the Stanford University Department of Electrical Engineering, wrote regarding potential solutions to the need for new cryptographic systems which minimize the necessity of secure key distribution channels and supply the equivalent of a written signature. The paper noted that then-contemporary cryptography imposed such severe inconveniences on the system users (namely, the need to transfer keys prior to initially communicating) that it entirely nullified the benefits of teleprocessing and acted as a disincentive for industry adoption.</description></item><item><title>Timeline: The U.S. Government and Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/timeline-the-u-s-government-and-cybersecurity-5f7be48e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/timeline-the-u-s-government-and-cybersecurity-5f7be48e/</guid><description>Published: May 2003
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/articles/A50606-2002Jun26.html
Abstract: This article offers a short timeline of government actions to curb the hacking of government computer systems. This article was prescient given the panic the Y2K bug that was creating in the vulnerabilities of government systems.</description></item></channel></rss>