<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2010s on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/2010s/</link><description>Recent content in 2010s on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/2010s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Judicial Framework for Evaluating Network Investigative Techniques</title><link>/entries/a-judicial-framework-for-evaluating-network-invest-f6ee8147/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/a-judicial-framework-for-evaluating-network-invest-f6ee8147/</guid><description>Authors: Hennessey, Susan and Weaver, Nicholas
Published: July 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/judicial-framework-evaluating-network-investigative-techniques
Abstract: This article in Lawfare by Susan Hennessey and Nicholas Weaver discusses the use of the NIT in the Playpen investigation, whether the government must disclose an NIT so that defendants may receive a fair trial, and proposes questions that courts should ask when evaluating disclosure of an NIT going forward. First, this article gives a background on the Playpen investigation, and the use of an NIT in the investigation, and background on NITs generally.</description></item><item><title>A Roadmap for Exceptional Access Research</title><link>/entries/a-roadmap-for-exceptional-access-research-9b867071/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/a-roadmap-for-exceptional-access-research-9b867071/</guid><description>Authors: Varia, Mayank
Published: December 2018
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/roadmap-exceptional-access-research
Abstract: Mayank Varia, Research Associate Professor of Computer Science at Boston University and Co-Director of BU’s Center for Reliable Information Systems and Cyber Security, warns of the “dour consequences” of continued politicization in the “crypto wars” debate over End-to-End (E2E) and Exceptional Access (EA) encryption systems. In an effort to quell continued politicization, Varia proposes a four-step roadmap to inform the process of developing EA technology and aid future policy debates.</description></item><item><title>Anonymity and Encryption: Comments Submitted to the United Nations Special Rapporteur on the Promotion and Protection of the Right to Freedom of Opinion and Expression</title><link>/entries/anonymity-and-encryption-comments-submitted-to-the-679d1ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/anonymity-and-encryption-comments-submitted-to-the-679d1ec2/</guid><description>Authors: Rodriguez, Katitza
Published: February 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/files/2015/02/10/unanonymity-encryption-eff.pdf
Abstract: The Electron Frontier Foundation’s comments regarding Anonymity and Encryption describe and argue for the benefit of anonymity and encryption. The comments describe what anonymity and digital anonymity are, their relevance to human rights, and policies around the world which either undermine or support the right to anonymity from both private and government actors. Finally, the comments describe encryption and its defend individuals right to encryption.</description></item><item><title>Apple Will No Longer Unlock Most iPhones, iPads for Police, Even with Search Warrants</title><link>/entries/apple-will-no-longer-unlock-most-iphones-ipads-for-d5b21880/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/apple-will-no-longer-unlock-most-iphones-ipads-for-d5b21880/</guid><description>Authors: Craig Timberg
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/2014/09/17/2612af58-3ed2-11e4-b03f-de718edeb92f_story.html
Abstract: In late 2014, in response to allegations of over-participation in government efforts to collect user information, Apple announced a plan to cease turning over user data to police, even when they have a search a warrant. The move, which was classified as an “engineering solution to a legal quandary,” came in the form of an update to the Apple’s mobile operating system privacy policy and relied primarily upon the encryption automatically placed on Apple mobile devices, via the selection of an access passcode.</description></item><item><title>As Encryption Spreads, U.S. Grapples with Clash Between Privacy, Security</title><link>/entries/as-encryption-spreads-u-s-grapples-with-clash-betw-6b2738da/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/as-encryption-spreads-u-s-grapples-with-clash-betw-6b2738da/</guid><description>Authors: Ellen Nakashima, Barton Gellman
Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/as-encryption-spreads-us-worries-about-access-to-data-for-investigations/2015/04/10/7c1c7518-d401-11e4-a62f-ee745911a4ff_story.html
Abstract: Ellen Nakashima and Barton Gellman explore the Obama Administration’s handling of and resistance to calls within the Intelligence and Law Enforcement communities to pressure technology companies, such as Apple, to build “back door” access to encrypted user data. The article explores numerous alternative options which were being considered by the White House, such as setting up mirror accounts or compelling companies to back up data to a company server (which would be subject to decryption with a warrant), yet identifies considerable challenges associated with each of the proposed methods.</description></item><item><title>Attorney General William P. Barr Delivers Keynote Address at the International Conference on Cyber Security</title><link>/entries/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-a-55f805a8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-a-55f805a8/</guid><description>Authors: Barr, William
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-address-international-conference-cyber
Abstract: Former Attorney General William Barr delivered the keynote address at the International Conference on Cyber Security in 2019. In the speech, Barr describes encryption as a technology that gives cover to criminals, particularly drug cartels, and prevents law enforcement from solving crimes. Barr insinuates that the Fourth Amendment, through balancing personal privacy and public safety, may not allow so-called “warrant-proof encryption” and requests backdoors be added to encryption to allow law enforcement access to encrypted messages through pursuant to warrants.</description></item><item><title>Best Practices for Encryption in P25 Public Safety Land Mobile Radio Systems</title><link>/entries/best-practices-for-encryption-in-p25-public-safety-c4ce136f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/best-practices-for-encryption-in-p25-public-safety-c4ce136f/</guid><description>Published: September 2016
Abstract: In September 2016, The Federal Partnership for Interoperable Communications (FPIC), in coordination with Aviation Safety Communique (SAFECOM) and the National Council of Statewide Interoperability Coordinators (NCSWIC), published a report to guide all levels of government in their efforts to improve encrypted interoperability for public safety land mobile radio systems. The “Best Practices” they advocate for the government pertain to: key management organization, key generation and distribution, adopting a National SLN assignment plan, standards-based encryption, crypto period considerations, communications planning, education and training, communications exercises and testing, and experts outreach.</description></item><item><title>Beyond Secrets: The Consumer Stake in the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/beyond-secrets-the-consumer-stake-in-the-encryptio-5a9a086a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/beyond-secrets-the-consumer-stake-in-the-encryptio-5a9a086a/</guid><description>Published: December 2017
URL: https://advocacy.consumerreports.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Beyond-Secrets-12.21.17-FINAL.pdf
Abstract: On December 21, 2017, ConsumersUnion and Upturn released this paper on consumers’ stake in the encryption debate. The paper begins with information on cryptography: what it is and how it works. It then discusses the ways in which encryption benefits consumers, including: protecting their health information, safeguarding their financial well-being, facilitating sale software updates, ensuring physical safety, and allowing consumers to communicate with confidence. The purpose of this paper is to educate consumers about the many ways that encryption benefits consumers and the systems and infrastructure consumers rely upon, and the potential costs if encryption were to be compromised.</description></item><item><title>Big reputation: What the Australian Parliament Can Learn from Taylor Swift</title><link>/entries/big-reputation-what-the-australian-parliament-can-642ff3e3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/big-reputation-what-the-australian-parliament-can-642ff3e3/</guid><description>Authors: Stepanovich, Amie
Published: February 2019
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/big-reputation-what-the-australian-parliament-can-learn-from-taylor-swift/
Abstract: On January 26, 2019, Access Now published an article about Australia’s passage of the draconian Telecommunications and Other Legislation Amendment (Assistance and Access Bill) Act 2018, which requires technology companies to grant law enforcement hack devices and access to encrypted messages, without judicial oversight. At the time the article was written, the bill called for further review, which opened up the potential to add “amendments, safeguards, and transparency requirements” to the bill.</description></item><item><title>Breaking: FBI Admits its Claims of “Going Dark” Were Overblown, Based on Bad Math</title><link>/entries/breaking-fbi-admits-its-claims-of-going-dark-were-b620adf1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/breaking-fbi-admits-its-claims-of-going-dark-were-b620adf1/</guid><description>Published: May 2018
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/press-releases/breaking-fbi-admits-its-claims-going-dark-were-overblown-based-bad-math/
Abstract: The Open Technology Institute released a statement regarding a Washington Post report that the FBI overstated “the number of encrypted mobile devices it could not unlock in 2017.” While the FBI had previously claimed there were 7,775 such devices, the FBI later clarified that the real number was around 1,200. Kevin Bankston, the Director of New America’s Open Technology Institute, issued a statement which called for Congressional investigation into the false numbers and arguing that the FBI’s requests for backdoors should be met with skepticism.</description></item><item><title>Brief of Amici Curiae Access Now and Wickr Foundation in Support of Apple Inc.'s Motion to Vacate</title><link>/entries/brief-of-amici-curiae-access-now-and-wickr-foundat-c51e7fcb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/brief-of-amici-curiae-access-now-and-wickr-foundat-c51e7fcb/</guid><description>Authors: Wickr Foundation
Abstract: This amicus brief was filed by Access Now and the Wickr Foundation in support of Apple in the Central District of California, asserting that allowing the government to install software to weaken encryption would have far-reaching effects beyond the singular iPhone at hand. The FBI petitioned the court to require Apple to create and install &amp;ldquo;GovtOS&amp;rdquo; which would allow the FBI to work around security features and potentially access encrypted information.</description></item><item><title>CALEA II: Risks of Wiretap Modifications to Endpoints</title><link>/entries/calea-ii-risks-of-wiretap-modifications-to-endpoin-33317ce9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/calea-ii-risks-of-wiretap-modifications-to-endpoin-33317ce9/</guid><description>Authors: Adida, Ben and Anderson, Collin and Anton, Annie I. and Blaze, Matt and Dingledine, Roger and Felten, Edward W. and Green, Matthew D. and Halderman, J. Alex and Jefferson, David R. and Jennings, Cullen and Landau, Susan and Mitter, Navroop and Neumann, Peter G. and Rescorla, Eric and Schneider, Fred B. and Schneier, Bruce and Shacham, Hovav and Sherr, Micah and Wagner, David and Zimmermann, Philip
Published: May 2013</description></item><item><title>Canada's Quiet Weakening of Communications Encryption</title><link>/entries/canada-s-quiet-weakening-of-communications-encrypt-c6650006/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/canada-s-quiet-weakening-of-communications-encrypt-c6650006/</guid><description>Authors: Parsons, Christopher and Israel, Tamir
Published: August 2015
URL: https://citizenlab.ca/2015/08/canadas-quiet-history-of-weakening-communications-encryption/
Abstract: This article outlines some of the federal government of Canada’s successful and unsuccessful attempts to weaken encryption standards.</description></item><item><title>Canada’s New and Irresponsible Encryption Policy: How the Government of Canada’s New Policy Threatens Charter Rights, Cybersecurity, Economic Growth, and Foreign Policy</title><link>/entries/canadas-new-and-irresponsible-encryption-policy-ho-c1d6da72/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/canadas-new-and-irresponsible-encryption-policy-ho-c1d6da72/</guid><description>Authors: Parsons, Christopher
Published: August 2019
URL: https://citizenlab.ca/2019/08/canadas-new-and-irresponsible-encryption-policy-how-the-government-of-canadas-new-policy-threatens-charter-rights-cybersecurity-economic-growth-and-foreign-policy/
Abstract: This article by Christopher Parsons argues that a 2019 Canadian ministerial communique weakens encryption. First, the article provides background on the history of Canadian encryption policy and the 2019 ministerial communique, and how its proposed policy would weaken encryption and require that private companies add backdoors for the Canadian government. Next, the article details the government&amp;rsquo;s justifications for the policy, and how they fail to justify the weakening of encryption.</description></item><item><title>CEOs and Encryption: The Questions You Need to Ask Your Experts</title><link>/entries/ceos-and-encryption-the-questions-you-need-to-ask-f054d98f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ceos-and-encryption-the-questions-you-need-to-ask-f054d98f/</guid><description>Authors: Wilton, Robin
Published: March 2018
URL: https://www.internetsociety.org/blog/2018/03/ceos-encryption-questions-need-asking-experts-2/
Abstract: On March 16, 2018, Robin Wilton, Director of Internet Trust, published a paper – originally created as an internal memorandum for Internet Society CEO, Kathy Brown – detailing the key questions CEOs should ask technical experts to ensure encryption policy competency. The paper explores three key topics: (1) getting a snapshot of your organization’s crypto strategy and current states, (2) practical challenges of deployment and management, and (3) non-technical factors around risk mitigation and law enforcement access.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to Members of Australia's Parliament</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-members-of-australia-s-parliam-65b62b0b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-members-of-australia-s-parliam-65b62b0b/</guid><description>Published: July 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/07/Australia-Encryption-Coalition-Letter.pdf
Abstract: On July 17, 2018 a coalition of domestic and international organizations and experts sent a letter to Australia’s parliament, urging it to not pass the Telecommunications and Other Legislation Amendment (Assistance and Access) Act 2018 (TOLA Act), which would require technology companies to grant law enforcement access to encrypted messages. The letter stresses the direct and indirect consequences of Australia’s proposed TOLA Act, should it pass.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to Ministers Responsible for the Five Eyes Security Community</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-ministers-responsible-for-the-c239cb16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-ministers-responsible-for-the-c239cb16/</guid><description>Published: June 2017
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2017/07/Five-eyes-open-letter.pdf
Abstract: In June of 2017, a coalition of 83 civil society organizations and eminent individuals wrote to the Ministers Responsible for the Five Eyes Security Community to “emphasize the importance of national policies that encourage and facilitate the development and use of strong encryption.” The coalition expressed concern with a joint communiqué – published following a Five Eyes meeting – expressing a commitment to exploring solutions to the “perceived impediment posed by encryption to investigative objectives” and plans “to press technology firms to share encrypted data with security agencies.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to NIST</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-nist-7f0953e7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-nist-7f0953e7/</guid><description>Authors: Stepanovich, Amie
Published: November 2014
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/archive/Coalition-NIST-Nov2014.pdf
Abstract: In November of 2014, a coalition of companies and civil society organizations wrote to the National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST), President Barack Obama, and Secretary of Commerce, Penny Pritzker to “re-emphasize the importance of creating a process for establishing secure and resilient encryption standards, free from back doors.” The letter was intended to influence the final version of the NIST’s Cryptographic Standards and Guidelines Development Process, through a series of policy recommendations.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 04/11/2016</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-04-11-2016-4b5abd91/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-04-11-2016-4b5abd91/</guid><description>Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2016/04/Encryption-Letter.pdf
Abstract: On April 11, 2016, a coalition of domestic and international organizations and experts sent a letter to President Barack Obama in which they urged the White House to “specifically oppose legislation to undermine security and reiterate the need for a broad statement of support for encryption from the administration”. The letter was sent in response to a draft bill titled “Compliance with Court Order Act of 2016”, which would compel all internet companies and “any person who provides a product or method to facilitate a communication or the processing or storage of data,” to “either undermine the security features they offer users or offer lesser security so as to facilitate government access.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 10/27/2016</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</guid><description>Published: October 2016
Abstract: On October 27, 2016, a coalition of domestic organizations and experts sent a letter to President Barack Obama in which they urged the White House to respond to a petition using the Administration&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;We the People&amp;rdquo; platform. The petition asked that the Administration &amp;ldquo;[p]ublicly affirm your support for strong encryption,” to “[r]eject any law, policy, or mandate that would undermine our security” online, and to &amp;ldquo;encourage other governments worldwide to do the same.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 5/19/2015</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-5-19-2015-ad5d54f2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-5-19-2015-ad5d54f2/</guid><description>Published: May 2015
URL: https://static.newamerica.org/attachments/3138&amp;ndash;113/Encryption_Letter_to_Obama_final_051915.pdf
Abstract: We urge you to reject any proposal that U.S. companies deliberately weaken the security of their products. We request that the White House instead focus on developing policies that will promote rather than undermine the wide adoption of strong encryption technology. Such policies will in turn help to promote and protect cybersecurity, economic growth, and human rights, both here and abroad.</description></item><item><title>Compliance with Court Orders Act of 2016 - Draft</title><link>/entries/compliance-with-court-orders-act-of-2016-draft-517e2d28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/compliance-with-court-orders-act-of-2016-draft-517e2d28/</guid><description>Authors: Burr, Richard, Feinstein, Dianne
URL: https://www.feinstein.senate.gov/public/index.cfm/2016/4/intelligence-committee-leaders-release-discussion-draft-of-encryption-legislation</description></item><item><title>Considerations for Encryption in Public Safety Radio Systems</title><link>/entries/considerations-for-encryption-in-public-safety-rad-7298abf0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/considerations-for-encryption-in-public-safety-rad-7298abf0/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: September 2016
URL: https://www.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/publications/20160830_fact_sheet_considerations_final_draft508_0.pdf
Abstract: In September of 2016, at the request of the public safety community, the Federal Partnership for Interoperable Communications (FPIC), produced a report on the key reasons, implications, and considerations associated with the encryption of critical portions of public safety communication systems. Among the key considerations for policy and stakeholders were what to encrypt; how to encrypt; the impact on Interoperability; public information access; and general cost considerations.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Summit 1.0</title><link>/entries/crypto-summit-1-0-efc034c8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/crypto-summit-1-0-efc034c8/</guid><description>Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/crypto_summit_part1/
Abstract: AccessNow published a summary of the Crypto Summit 1.0, the first of two summits, which occurred on July 15, 2015 in Washington, DC. The topics discussed in the conference focus on the United States and include crypto history, encryption technology, the current state of the law and how it should evolve, the biggest challenges and opportunities of encryption and the future of encryption based on potential policy outcomes.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Summit 2.0 Outcomes Report Track 1</title><link>/entries/crypto-summit-2-0-outcomes-report-track-1-f3204001/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/crypto-summit-2-0-outcomes-report-track-1-f3204001/</guid><description>Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2016/07/CS2.0_Outcomes_Track1.pdf
Abstract: AccessNow published a summary of the Crypto Summit 2.0, the second of two summits, which occurred on March 30, 2016 in Silicon Valley. The goal of this conference was to build off the key questions identified in Crypto Summit 1.0. The group identified four policy tracks to focus on in the second summit. The first policy track entails the “roles and responsibilities in an encrypted world”.</description></item><item><title>Debate: Law Enforcement vs. Smartphone Encryption</title><link>/entries/debate-law-enforcement-vs-smartphone-encryption-d2d753c0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/debate-law-enforcement-vs-smartphone-encryption-d2d753c0/</guid><description>Authors: New America
Published: November 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/events/debate-on-law-enforcement-vs-smartphone-encryption/
Abstract: This debate features former government officials, technologists, and privacy advocates about encryption being offered as a default on smartphones. One side argues that this move will deprive law enforcement of the ability to seek evidence, even with a warrant, and discusses the possible near for congressional action to require companies to allow law enforcement access. The other side argues that such laws would undermine security and privacy, and disadvantage US technology makers.</description></item><item><title>Deep Dive into Crypto “Exceptional Access” Mandates: Effective or Constitutional—Pick One</title><link>/entries/deep-dive-into-crypto-exceptional-access-mandates-4ed0e169/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/deep-dive-into-crypto-exceptional-access-mandates-4ed0e169/</guid><description>Authors: Cardozo, Nate and Crocker, Andrew
Published: August 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/08/deep-dive-crypto-exceptional-access-mandates-effective-or-constitutional-pick-one
Abstract: Deep Dive into Crypto “Exceptional Access” Mandates: Effective or Constitutional—Pick One by Andrew Crocker and Nate Cardozo argues that any exceptional access mandate would violate the First Amendment. The article is responding to a plethora of news coverage, citing law enforcement officials and detailing law enforcement’s need for “exceptional access” to allow government access to all encrypted materials. The article next argues that any exceptional access would require government control over the development of encryption software, which is speech, and would therefore violate the First Amendment’s ban on prior restraint.</description></item><item><title>Deputy Attorney General Rod J. Rosenstein Delivers Remarks at the Global Cyber Security Summit</title><link>/entries/deputy-attorney-general-rod-j-rosenstein-delivers-a3df0cc4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/deputy-attorney-general-rod-j-rosenstein-delivers-a3df0cc4/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenstein, Rod
Published: October 2017
URL: https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/deputy-attorney-general-rod-j-rosenstein-delivers-remarks-global-cyber-security-summit
Abstract: This speech by Deputy Attorney General Rod J. Rosenstein at the Global Cyber Security Summit in 2017 argues that competitive forces lead technology companies and the makers of encrypted technologies to resist cooperation with law enforcement. The speech details global cybersecurity threats, and how government programs, such as the Department of Defense and Department of justice have developed programs to help counter cyber attacks.</description></item><item><title>Don’t Panic: Making Progress on the “Going Dark” Debate</title><link>/entries/dont-panic-making-progress-on-the-going-dark-debat-092ae356/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/dont-panic-making-progress-on-the-going-dark-debat-092ae356/</guid><description>Published: February 2016
Abstract: In September of 2016, the Federal Partnership for Interoperable Communications (FPIC), produced a report on the key reasons, implications, and considerations associated with the encryption of critical portions of public safety communication systems, Considerations for Encryption in Public Safety Radio Systems. As a supplement to that report, the FPIC published this two-page fact sheet, which provides a summary of the report and the policy justifications for its recommendations.</description></item><item><title>Dutch Government Backs Uncrackable Encryption</title><link>/entries/dutch-government-backs-uncrackable-encryption-8169af3a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/dutch-government-backs-uncrackable-encryption-8169af3a/</guid><description>Authors: Robert Hackett
Published: January 2016
URL: https://fortune.com/2016/01/05/dutch-government-encryption-no-backdoors/
Abstract: On January 5, 2016, Fortune published an article about the Dutch government’s decision to not request a backdoor to encryption data and communications. The article noted that the government acknowledged both sides of the backdoor debate, and determined that “it is not desirable at this time to take restrictive regulatory measures with respect to the development, availability, and use of encryption within the Netherlands.</description></item><item><title>Encryption 101: A Non-Technical Guide to Protecting Your Digital Communications</title><link>/entries/encryption-101-a-non-technical-guide-to-protecting-a4994675/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-101-a-non-technical-guide-to-protecting-a4994675/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle
Published: February 2015
URL: https://slate.com/technology/2015/02/what-is-encryption-a-nontechnical-guide-to-protecting-your-digital-communications.html
Abstract: This article from Danielle Kehl offers a beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide to encryption, including how the technology works, its development, its modern uses, and how one can implement encryption technology into their daily life to increase their personal privacy. This article includes discussion of Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTPS), Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol and its successor, Transport Layer Security (TLS).</description></item><item><title>Encryption and Globalization</title><link>/entries/encryption-and-globalization-9e3100e9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-and-globalization-9e3100e9/</guid><description>Authors: Swire, Peter P. and Ahmad, Kenesa
Published: 2012
URL: http://www.ssrn.com/abstract=1960602
Abstract: This law review article by Peter Swire and Kenesa Ahmad discusses changes to Indian and Chinese encryption laws. The article begins by describing the development of U.S. encryption laws, mainly focusing on the crypto wars and the United States&amp;rsquo; eventual embrace of encryption. However, the article then discusses globalization that has taken place since the 1990s, and how policy positions developed during the crypto wars are no longer sufficient when considering the increased interconnectedness of the world.</description></item><item><title>Encryption and the Press Clause</title><link>/entries/encryption-and-the-press-clause-46f389c7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-and-the-press-clause-46f389c7/</guid><description>Authors: Baranetsky, D Victoria
Published: 2017
Abstract: This law review article by D. Victoria Baranetsky argues that, through a historical understanding of the purpose of the Press Clause, the First Amendment protects encryption technology. The article begins by describing the Framers’ intent and purpose in the Press Clause, as well as the traditional interpretations and debates that have arisen surrounding its meaning, then goes on to describe how those interpretations may interact with and protect encryption.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Backdoors Decrease Trust In The Internet</title><link>/entries/encryption-backdoors-decrease-trust-in-the-interne-0da4e63b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-backdoors-decrease-trust-in-the-interne-0da4e63b/</guid><description>Authors: Kolkman, Olaf
Published: May 2015
URL: https://www.internetsociety.org/blog/2015/05/encryption-backdoors-decrease-trust-in-the-internet/
Abstract: In May of 2015, Olaf Kolkman, the Principal of Internet Technology, Policy, and Advocacy at the Internet Society, wrote to express his support for a letter sent to President Barack Obama, by a collection of civil society organizations, corporations, trade associations, and security and policy experts. The letter expressed concern regarding a suggestion by Administration officials that companies should refrain from providing products with strong encryption unless they simultaneously weakened their security “in order to maintain the capability to decrypt their customer’s data at the government’s request.</description></item><item><title>Encryption in the U.S.: Crypto Colloquium Outcomes Report</title><link>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</guid><description>Published: January 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/02/Encryption-in-the-United-States-Crypto-Colloquium-Outcomes-Report.pdf
Abstract: In September of 2017, Access Now, a non-profit dedicated to human rights advocacy in the digital age, hosted the Crypto Colloquium—an invite-only dialogue of civil society, academic experts, technology companies and former U.S. government officials—to discuss challenges associated with U.S. government agencies’ inability to access information on encrypted mobile phones. The Report, produced by Access Now, provides a summary of the key takeaways from the Colloquium, including a section on the “Lessons Learned” in each of the Law and Policy, Security, and Economics sectors.</description></item><item><title>Encryption is a Human Rights issue: Your Privacy and Pree Speech Depend on It</title><link>/entries/encryption-is-a-human-rights-issue-your-privacy-an-62451d82/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-is-a-human-rights-issue-your-privacy-an-62451d82/</guid><description>Authors: Amul Kalia
Published: December 2016
URL: https://www.learnliberty.org/blog/encryption-is-a-human-rights-issue-your-privacy-and-free-speech-depend-on-it/
Abstract: In December of 2016, Amul Kalia, a staff member of the Electronic Frontier Foundation, wrote, emphasizing the importance of encryption, through the lens of American history. Kalia highlighted the less technologically advanced uses of encrypted communications implored by the Founding Fathers of the United States (Thomas Jefferson, George Washington, and James Madison), such as coded messaging and ciphers, to argue that encryption is “crucial to a free society.</description></item><item><title>Encryption under fire: discussion on threats to private messaging w/ Head of WhatsApp Will Cathcart</title><link>/entries/encryption-under-fire-discussion-on-threats-to-pri-6bbe4ed7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-under-fire-discussion-on-threats-to-pri-6bbe4ed7/</guid><description>Published: July 2020
URL: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y1LSFQo_07w</description></item><item><title>Encryption, Biometrics, and the Status Quo Ante</title><link>/entries/encryption-biometrics-and-the-status-quo-ante-6819368c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-biometrics-and-the-status-quo-ante-6819368c/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenzweig, Paul
Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/encryption-biometrics-and-status-quo-ante
Abstract: On July 6, 2015, Paul Rosenzweig, founder of Red Branch Consulting PLLC, wrote about a paradigm shift in the encryption debate, and offered a solution to deal with the paradigm shift. In 1995, data “could not be maintained in an undecryptable format”, access to data was “achieved through lawful process (either a search warrant or a subpoena)”, and the subject of an investigation received notice.</description></item><item><title>Encryption, Trust, and the Online Economy: An Assessment of the Economic Benefits Associated with Encryption</title><link>/entries/encryption-trust-and-the-online-economy-an-assessm-b5968feb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-trust-and-the-online-economy-an-assessm-b5968feb/</guid><description>Authors: Hagemann, Ryan and Hampson, Josh
Published: November 2015
URL: https://www.niskanencenter.org/encryption-trust-and-the-online-economy-an-assessment-of-the-economic-benefits-associated-with-encryption/
Abstract: On November 9, 2015, the Niskanen Center published a report that assessed the economic benefits associated with the use of software-based encryption. The report’s aim is to “provide a ballpark estimate of the economic value of encryption” and “suggest how a more accurate estimate might be achieved”, with the end goal of showing “the way toward a better understanding of the role and benefit of encryption in the Internet-age economy”.</description></item><item><title>Entropy and Random Numbers</title><link>/entries/entropy-and-random-numbers-d61c00fb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/entropy-and-random-numbers-d61c00fb/</guid><description>Authors: Callan, Tim and Soroko, Jason
URL: https://sectigo.com/resources/root-causes-1-25
Abstract: Sectigo SSL Certificates formerly Comodo CA SSL Certificates. Same high quality SSL certificates you trust! Money Back Guarantee. Secure all Subdomains. 30 Day Refund Policy, 24/7 Live Support</description></item><item><title>Ex-MI5 Chief Warns Against Crackdown on Encrypted Messaging Apps</title><link>/entries/ex-mi5-chief-warns-against-crackdown-on-encrypted-9cfea775/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ex-mi5-chief-warns-against-crackdown-on-encrypted-9cfea775/</guid><description>Authors: Grierson, Jamie
Published: August 2017
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/aug/11/ex-mi5-chief-warns-against-crackdown-encrypted-messaging-apps
Abstract: On August 11, 2017, The Guardian published an article regarding comments made by a former head of MI5, Lord Evans, who does “not support a clampdown on use of encryption”. Instead, Lord Evans pointed to other, greater threats than encryption, including the state of cybersecurity as a whole, cybersecurity for the internet of things, and attacks on British democracy from foreign actors like Russia.</description></item><item><title>Ex-NSA Chief Thinks the Government is Dead Wrong in Asking Apple for a Backdoor</title><link>/entries/ex-nsa-chief-thinks-the-government-is-dead-wrong-i-8b5c5590/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ex-nsa-chief-thinks-the-government-is-dead-wrong-i-8b5c5590/</guid><description>Authors: Business Insider
Published: February 2016
URL: https://www.businessinsider.com/michael-hayden-encryption-apple-2016-2
Abstract: On February 25, 2016, Business Insider published an article regarding comments made by a former NSA Chief, General Michael Hayden, in which he expressed his rejection of the notion that tech companies should implement a backdoor to encryption on behalf of law enforcement. While he noted that a lack of a backdoor for encryption imposes “an unfair cost”, he said “we are not required to organize our entire national life around the needs of American law enforcement.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Encryption and Potential Mechanisms for Authorized Government Access to Plaintext: Proceedings of a Workshop</title><link>/entries/exploring-encryption-and-potential-mechanisms-for-26c5994f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/exploring-encryption-and-potential-mechanisms-for-26c5994f/</guid><description>Authors: Johnson, Anne and Eisenberg, Jon and Gumbling, Emily
Published: 2016
URL: https://www.nap.edu/catalog/23593/exploring-encryption-and-potential-mechanisms-for-authorized-government-access-to-plaintext
Abstract: On June 23-24, 2016, the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine held a “Workshop on Encryption and Mechanisms for Authorized Government Access to Plaintext”. In September 2016, The National Academies Press published a book which summarizes the “presentations and discussions” from the workshop. Participants discussed encryption mechanisms that “would enable access to plaintext information by law enforcement or national security agencies with appropriate authority.</description></item><item><title>FAQ on the FCC CALEA Expansion</title><link>/entries/faq-on-the-fcc-calea-expansion-cb61ed55/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/faq-on-the-fcc-calea-expansion-cb61ed55/</guid><description>Published: 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/issues/calea
Abstract: In 2014 the Electronic Frontier Foundation published an article on the evolving history of the The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994. Initially, CALEA “forced telephone companies to redesign their network architectures to make it easier for law enforcement to wiretap digital telephone calls.” In 2004, several law enforcement agencies petitioned the FCC to expand the scope of CALEA to all Internet communications services, and the FCC issued a final rule which expanded CALEA “to broadband Internet access providers and managed VoIP systems.</description></item><item><title>FBI Blasts Apple, Google for Locking Police out of Phones</title><link>/entries/fbi-blasts-apple-google-for-locking-police-out-of-79e02027/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/fbi-blasts-apple-google-for-locking-police-out-of-79e02027/</guid><description>Authors: Craig Timberg, Greg Miller
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/2014/09/25/68c4e08e-4344-11e4-9a15-137aa0153527_story.html
Abstract: On September 26, 2014, The Washington Post published an article which discussed the FBI’s criticism of Apple and Google for “for developing forms of smartphone encryption so secure that law enforcement officials cannot easily gain access to information stored on the devices &amp;ndash; even when they have valid search warrants.” The article notes that “while the legal and technical changes are fueled by anger over reports of mass surveillance by the National Security Agency, the consequences are being felt most heavily by police detectives, often armed with warrants certifying that a judge has found probable cause that a search of a smartphone will reveal evidence of a crime.</description></item><item><title>FBI Pressuring Google, Facebook to Allow ‘Back Doors’ for Wiretapping</title><link>/entries/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-to-allow-back-doors-71473338/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-to-allow-back-doors-71473338/</guid><description>Authors: Daniel Tencer
Published: November 2010
URL: https://www.rawstory.com/2010/11/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-wiretapping/
Abstract: On November 17, 2010, Raw Story published an article discussing the debate surrounding a proposed expansion of The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994. At the time, FBI Director Robert Mueller placed pressure on technology companies to build “back doors” which would “allow law enforcement to wiretap data on their networks”, in an effort “to expand the FBI’s wiretapping powers to include the latest communications technologies, including social networking sites, voice-over-Internet (VoIP) telephone services and BlackBerries.</description></item><item><title>Federal Bureau of Investigation: FY 2010 Budget Request</title><link>/entries/federal-bureau-of-investigation-fy-2010-budget-req-f44e795f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/federal-bureau-of-investigation-fy-2010-budget-req-f44e795f/</guid><description>Authors: FBI
URL: https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/jmd/legacy/2014/04/12/fbi-bud-summary.pdf
Abstract: The FBI’s FY 2010 budget request proposed a roughly $560.3 million (or 7.7%) increase in funding from the preceding year. Included within this requested increase in funding were plans to increase total positions by 1,389—adding 407 new agents—and program enhancements to a number of FBI projects. Most notable among the program enhancements, in the context of encryption, was a requested $9 million increase (to the $233.</description></item><item><title>Feds Put Heat on Web Firms for Master Encryption Keys</title><link>/entries/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-k-c6363e83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-k-c6363e83/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: July 2013
URL: https://www.cnet.com/news/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-keys/
Abstract: In July of 2013, Declan McCullagh, a senior writer for CNET, wrote regarding the continued effort of major U.S. intelligence agencies (the FBI and NSA) to obtain master encryption (SSL) keys used by internet service providers to shield private communications. McCullagh referred to the efforts of the U.S. government as a “technological escalation in the clandestine methods that the FBI and National Security Agency employ when conducting electronic surveillance against Internet users,” and warned of the sheer scope of the information which could be intercepted if such a key were turned over.</description></item><item><title>Former GCHQ Boss Backs End-to-End Encryption</title><link>/entries/former-gchq-boss-backs-end-to-end-encryption-8c807a3b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/former-gchq-boss-backs-end-to-end-encryption-8c807a3b/</guid><description>Authors: Leyden, John
Published: July 2017
URL: https://www.theregister.co.uk/2017/07/10/former_gchq_wades_into_encryption_debate/
Abstract: In July of 2017, John Leyden of The Register, wrote regarding a statement made by former GCHQ Director Robert Hannigan against proposals to build backdoors into end-to-end encryption programs. In an interview with BBC Radio 4’s program Today, Hannigan explained “encryption is overwhelmingly a good thing. It keep us all safe and secure.” Rather than building in backdoors or “un-invent[ing] encryption,” Hannigan expressed support for cooperation between private tech companies and government agencies to “find a way around it,” by “target[ing] the people who are abusing&amp;rdquo; encryption systems and going after their smartphones or laptops through alternative means.</description></item><item><title>Former National-Security Officials Suddenly See the Peril of Weakening Encryption</title><link>/entries/former-national-security-officials-suddenly-see-th-d46b3725/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/former-national-security-officials-suddenly-see-th-d46b3725/</guid><description>Authors: Friedersdorf, Conor
Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2015/07/former-national-security-officials-see-the-peril-of-weakening-encryption/399848/
Abstract: This new article examines how former national security officials, after leaving their government jobs for private industry, tended to support strong encryption and argued against mandatory backdoor access. The article reported comments made by several former national security officials who had then transitioned to private industry, and the comments they made against government infringement on encryption at the Aspen Security Forum in 2015.</description></item><item><title>From Clipper Chip to Smartphones: Unlocking the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-enc-cbe23268/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-enc-cbe23268/</guid><description>Authors: Flatow, Ira
URL: https://www.sciencefriday.com/segments/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-encryption-debate/
Abstract: This Podcast features comments made by security experts and privacy advocates made in the 1990s about the Clipper Chip. It offers a look back into what the policy discussion looked like concurrently with the Clipper Chip proposals. Some of those who previously made comments offer follow-up, looking back at the development of their views and policy positions and how they have developed in the intervening years.</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Are Technology, Privacy, and Public Safety on a Collision Course?</title><link>/entries/going-dark-are-technology-privacy-and-public-safet-b115d093/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/going-dark-are-technology-privacy-and-public-safet-b115d093/</guid><description>Authors: Comey, James
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/speeches/going-dark-are-technology-privacy-and-public-safety-on-a-collision-course
Abstract: This speech by FBI Director James Comey, offered at the Brooking Institute in 2014, discusses the challenges that encryption and going dark present to law enforcement. Director Comey discusses how a proliferation in digital data and communication are increasingly encrypted, and how law enforcement is technologically incapable of keeping up. Further, CALEA is not equipped to offer fair access to newer forms of technology.</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Lawful Electronic Surveillance in the Face of New Technologies</title><link>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-5165cb74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-5165cb74/</guid><description>Authors: Valerie Caproni
Published: February 2011
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/testimony/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-face-of-new-technologies
Abstract: On February 17, 2001, Valeria Caproni, General Counsel, Federal Bureau of Investigation, testified before the House Judiciary Committee, Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security. In her testimony, Caproni discussed the “Going Dark” problem facing law enforcement. The “legal authorities [the FBI has] for intercepting electronic communications are adequate”, but the government often does not have the “practical ability to actually intercept those communications”.</description></item><item><title>Guidelines for Encryption in Land Mobile Radio Systems</title><link>/entries/guidelines-for-encryption-in-land-mobile-radio-sys-b0ed6104/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/guidelines-for-encryption-in-land-mobile-radio-sys-b0ed6104/</guid><description>Published: February 2016
URL: https://www.dhs.gov/publication/encryption
Abstract: On February 8, 2016, the Federal Partnership for Interoperable Communications (FPIC) published guidelines for encryption in land mobile radio (LRM) systems for state, local, and tribal public safety entities. The report discusses the background of public safety entities and encryption, high-level technical information about encryption, types of encryption algorithms for public safety, cryptographic algorithms, and issues with interoperability. The goal of the guidelines was to get rid of confusion and competing information “regarding voice and data encryption” in LMR systems for the state, local, and tribal public safety entities.</description></item><item><title>H.R. 2545 - Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/h-r-2545-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-a-2d6fd580/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/h-r-2545-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-a-2d6fd580/</guid><description>Authors: Cummings, Elijah E. and Krishnamoorthi, Raja
Published: May 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/2545/text
Abstract: On May 7, 2019, Representatives Cummings and Krishnamoorthi introduced H.R. 2545, the Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019. H.R. 2545 sought to create an Office of Cybersecurity at the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) for “supervision of data security at consumer reporting agencies, to require the promulgation of regulations establishing standards for effective cybersecurity for effective cybersecurity at consumer reporting agencies, to impose penalties on credit reporting agencies for cybersecurity breaches that put sensitive consumer data at risk, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>H.R. 4943 - Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act</title><link>/entries/h-r-4943-clarifying-lawful-overseas-use-of-data-ac-f1395da4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/h-r-4943-clarifying-lawful-overseas-use-of-data-ac-f1395da4/</guid><description>Authors: Collins, Doug
Published: February 2018
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/4943
Abstract: On February 6, 2018, Representatives Collins, Jeffries, Issa, DelBene, Marino, Rutherford and Demings introduced H.R. 4943, the “Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act” or the “CLOUD Act.” H.R. 4943 amends title 18 of the United States federal criminal code to “improve law enforcement access to data stored across borders, and for other purposes.” The bill requires electronic communication service (ECS) and remote computer service (RCS) providers to comply with existing preservation, backup and disclosure requirements pertaining to contents of electronic communications and any record or other information pertaining to a customer or subscriber within their possession, regardless of whether the information is located within the United States.</description></item><item><title>Hacking/​Journalism</title><link>/entries/hacking-journalism-04dbfbc9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/hacking-journalism-04dbfbc9/</guid><description>Authors: Salvo, Philip Di
Published: April 2017
URL: https://limn.it/articles/hackingjournalism/
Abstract: On May 19, 2011, The Washington Post published an article about one of the ways in which the “boundaries of journalism have expanded” into hacking through the adoption of encryption tools in whistleblowing cases. The article discusses the use of encryption tools in leaks including WikiLeaks’ Afghan and Iraqi War Logs, the Cablegate leaks, the Panama Papers, and Snowden’s leaks. In each of these leaks, encryption “played an enabling role in that whistleblowing” in part because it “played a fundamental part in facilitating communication between the source and the journalists.</description></item><item><title>Half the Web Is Now Encrypted. That Makes Everyone Safer</title><link>/entries/half-the-web-is-now-encrypted-that-makes-everyone-2100a1e7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/half-the-web-is-now-encrypted-that-makes-everyone-2100a1e7/</guid><description>Authors: Finley, Klint
Published: January 2017
URL: https://www.wired.com/2017/01/half-web-now-encrypted-makes-everyone-safer/
Abstract: In January of 2017, Klint Finley of Wired Magazine, a significant milestone in computer security news—the average volume of encrypted internet traffic “finally” surpassing the average volume of unencrypted traffic. The achievement, Finley noted, “means when you visit a website, you’re now more likely than not to see a little green lock right next to its address…indicat[ing] that the page you’ve visited came to you via HTTPS, the web’s secure protocol.</description></item><item><title>Holder Urges Tech Companies to Leave Device Backdoors Open for Police</title><link>/entries/holder-urges-tech-companies-to-leave-device-backdo-1737189d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/holder-urges-tech-companies-to-leave-device-backdo-1737189d/</guid><description>Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2014/09/30/holder-urges-tech-companies-to-leave-device-backdoors-open-for-police/
Abstract: This news article from 2014 features comments from Attorney General Eric Holder urging technology companies to insert back doors into their products because encryption could potentially imperial investigations into kidnapping and sexual predation of children. Holder stated that companies could design technology in such a way that would not burden privacy. This article outlines statements from a top law enforcement official, linking encryption to crimes against children.</description></item><item><title>How secure is AES Against Brute Force Attacks?</title><link>/entries/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks-a76070ac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks-a76070ac/</guid><description>Authors: Arora, Mohit
Published: May 2012
URL: https://www.eetimes.com/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks/
Abstract: In May of 2012, Mohit Arora, Sr. Systems Engineer &amp;amp; Security Architect for Freescale Semiconductor, wrote for the EE Times regarding the security of Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) against brute force attacks. Arora analyzed the system’s strength against brute force attacks with different key sizes and projected advancements in processing speeds. Ultimately, Arora concluded that “even with a supercomputer, it would take 1 billion years to crack the 128-bit AES keying using [a] brute force attack,” and thus deemed AES “safe against any brute force attack.</description></item><item><title>How Unvalidated Encryption Threatens Patient Data Security</title><link>/entries/how-unvalidated-encryption-threatens-patient-data-f2fafa62/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/how-unvalidated-encryption-threatens-patient-data-f2fafa62/</guid><description>Authors: HealthITSecurity
Published: July 2016
URL: https://healthitsecurity.com/news/how-unvalidated-encryption-threatens-patient-data-security
Abstract: This article argues that failures by regulators to enforce precise encryption rules in data breaches by healthcare providers endanger allow substandard encryption to continue operating, endangering patient data. The article discusses the HIPAA, and subsequently elucidating NIST standards for encryption for healthcare patient data. However, because of leniency enforcement, vendors continue providing inadequate encryption without fear of consequences. The article argues that consistent enforcement of the NIST standards will ensure more secure data protection for healthcare patients.</description></item><item><title>HTTPS-Everywhere for Government</title><link>/entries/https-everywhere-for-government-5c0a30ab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/https-everywhere-for-government-5c0a30ab/</guid><description>Published: June 2015
URL: https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/blog/2015/06/08/https-everywhere-government
Abstract: This 2015 announcement from the White House Office of Management and Budget announces the HTTPS-Only Standard Directive, where federal websites and web services will use a secure HTTPS connection. The program seeks to solve vulnerabilities in unsecured HTTP connections and create uniformity in privacy and security standards across federal websites.</description></item><item><title>Human Rights and Encryption</title><link>/entries/human-rights-and-encryption-380229a2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/human-rights-and-encryption-380229a2/</guid><description>Authors: U.N. Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization
Published: 2016
URL: https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000246527
Abstract: This study from the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization outlines the benefits of encryption to human rights, the legality of interference with free and strong encryption, and gives best practices for nations and other stakeholders. This study offers case studies in various member states, including Germany, the United States, India, and Brazil, and looks at both legal restrictions on encryption as well as legal measures which promote its adoption.</description></item><item><title>IC on the Record, Video: ODNI General Counsel Robert Litt</title><link>/entries/ic-on-the-record-video-odni-general-counsel-robert-f1f2db82/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ic-on-the-record-video-odni-general-counsel-robert-f1f2db82/</guid><description>Authors: Robert Litt
Published: February 2015
URL: https://icontherecord.tumblr.com/post/110099240063/video-odni-general-counsel-robert-litt-speaks-on
Abstract: On February 4, 2015, Robert Litt, General Counsel, Office of the Director of National Intelligence, gave a talk titled “U.S. Intelligence Community Surveillance One Year After President Obama’s [January 2014] Address” at the Brookings Institute. Litt discussed issues related to transparency in intelligent activities, limitations on surveillance, bulk collection of data, incidental collection of data, protection for non-American citizens, and the future.</description></item><item><title>In Re: Application for an Order Pursuant to 18 U.S.C. 2705(b) Relating to a Subpoena to Open Whisper Systems for the Accounts Listed</title><link>/entries/in-re-application-for-an-order-pursuant-to-18-u-s-f42df79e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/in-re-application-for-an-order-pursuant-to-18-u-s-f42df79e/</guid><description>Published: September 2016
URL: https://signal.org/bigbrother/eastern-virginia-grand-jury/</description></item><item><title>Issue Brief: A “Backdoor” to Encryption for Government Surveillance</title><link>/entries/issue-brief-a-backdoor-to-encryption-for-governmen-feec9f35/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/issue-brief-a-backdoor-to-encryption-for-governmen-feec9f35/</guid><description>Authors: Hall, Joseph Lorenzo
Published: March 2016
URL: https://cdt.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Issue-brief-A-backdoor-to-encryption-for-government-surveillance-CDT-03032012.pdf
Abstract: On March 3, 2016, the Center for Democracy and Technology published an article about whether or not there should be an encryption “backdoor” for government surveillance. The article discussed the decision by Apple and Google to make their smartphones “encrypted by default”, the desire of the FBI that all encrypted communications services have a “backdoor”, the major problems created by backdoors, including the undermining of user security and harm to United States businesses, rejects the claim that “companies’ increasing adoption of strong encryption by default will suddenly lead to government ‘going dark’ and unable to access critical information”, and factors relevant to whether or not compelled decryption is legal.</description></item><item><title>James Comey, F.B.I. Director, Hints at Action as Cellphone Data Is Locked</title><link>/entries/james-comey-f-b-i-director-hints-at-action-as-cell-f7538b3a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/james-comey-f-b-i-director-hints-at-action-as-cell-f7538b3a/</guid><description>Authors: David E. Sanger, Matt Apuzzo
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2014/10/17/us/politics/fbi-director-in-policy-speech-calls-dark-devices-hindrance-to-crime-solving.html
Abstract: On October 16, 2014, David E. Sanger and Matt Apuzzo wrote for the New York Times regarding F.B.I. Director James Comey’s comments on the potential the Obama administration would seek regulations and laws forcing companies to create an encryption backdoor to unlock photos, emails and contacts stored on cellular devices. The comments came shortly following the decisions of Apple and Google to automatically encrypt the contents of their cellphones—a first among widely used consumer devices—which Comey claimed would hinder intelligence gathering.</description></item><item><title>Key Escrow from a Safe Distance: Looking Back at the Clipper Chip</title><link>/entries/key-escrow-from-a-safe-distance-looking-back-at-th-acc94260/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/key-escrow-from-a-safe-distance-looking-back-at-th-acc94260/</guid><description>Authors: Blaze, Matt
Published: 2011
URL: http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?doid=2076732.2076777
Abstract: In 2011, Matt Blaze, of the University of Pennsylvania, published a retrospective paper on the key escrow cryptosystem and the Clipper Chip. The paper begins with a carrot and stick analogy on early 1990s encryption regulations. The stick, classification of encryption as a munition and its deterrent effect on incorporation of strong encryption in consumer products. The carrot, an exception for systems incorporating a backdoor (the key escrow system).</description></item><item><title>Keys Under Doormats: Mandating Insecurity by Requiring Government Access to All Data and Communications</title><link>/entries/keys-under-doormats-mandating-insecurity-by-requir-5df4f072/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/keys-under-doormats-mandating-insecurity-by-requir-5df4f072/</guid><description>Authors: Abelson, Harold and Anderson, Ross and Bellovin, Steven M and Benaloh, Josh and Blaze, Matt and Diffie, Whitﬁeld and Gilmore, John and Green, Matthew and Landau, Susan and Neumann, Peter G and Rivest, Ronald L and Schiller, Jeﬀrey I and Schneier, Bruce and Specter, Michael and Weitzner, Daniel J
Published: July 2015
Abstract: On July 7, 2015, a group of computer scientists and security experts published a study to ascertain the likely effects of renewed attempts to mandate back doors of all data for law enforcement.</description></item><item><title>McCaul’s Crypto Commission: First, Do No Harm</title><link>/entries/mccauls-crypto-commission-first-do-no-harm-478ce042/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/mccauls-crypto-commission-first-do-no-harm-478ce042/</guid><description>Authors: White, Nathan
Published: February 2016
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/mccauls-crypto-commission-first-no-harm/
Abstract: On March 2, 2016, AccessNow published an article about the proposed McCaul-Warner Encryption Commission, which would “create a bipartisan commission of experts to study the debate over encryption and provide recommendations for overcoming the current impasse.” The article notes that despite their good intentions, “the commission, as proposed, might not produce what” they expect. The proposal relies on “the assumption that people from both ‘sides’ of the debate have not already engaged with one another in good faith” when in fact they did in the 1990s and more recently.</description></item><item><title>Memorandum for the Heads of Executive Departments and Agencies: Policy to Require Secure Connections Across Federal Websites and Web Services</title><link>/entries/memorandum-for-the-heads-of-executive-departments-beed0dbf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/memorandum-for-the-heads-of-executive-departments-beed0dbf/</guid><description>Authors: Scott, Tony
Published: June 2015</description></item><item><title>Mozilla Cybersecurity Delphi 1.0: Towards a User-centric Policy Framework</title><link>/entries/mozilla-cybersecurity-delphi-1-0-towards-a-user-ce-3db1081f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/mozilla-cybersecurity-delphi-1-0-towards-a-user-ce-3db1081f/</guid><description>Authors: Camille François, Chris Riley, Dave Steer, Jochai Ben-Avie, Su Midghall
Published: July 2015
URL: https://blog.mozilla.org/netpolicy/files/2015/07/Mozilla-Cybersecurity-Delphi-1.0.pdf
Abstract: This study by Mozilla brought together 30 cybersecurity experts from academia, civil liberties, government and military, security, and technology, to discuss priorities and goals in the development of encryption policy. The report found several areas of agreement, such as prioritizing automating encryption over consumer education and the prioritization of developing behavioral and cultural norms in cybersecurity.</description></item><item><title>New Perspectives on the Future of Encryption</title><link>/entries/new-perspectives-on-the-future-of-encryption-29240979/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/new-perspectives-on-the-future-of-encryption-29240979/</guid><description>Authors: Baker, Jim and Landau, Susan
Published: May 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/new-perspectives-future-encryption
Abstract: Encryption and its effects on law enforcement’s access to data seem to occupy a perennial place in the headlines (and on Lawfare as well). The two of us have been working on it for years. The subject is often highly contested, but the fierce discussion has ignored some critical factors. One of those is how changing usage patterns and technologies will affect how law enforcement can—or can’t—obtain access.</description></item><item><title>Newest Androids Will Join iPhones in Offering Default Encryption, Blocking Police</title><link>/entries/newest-androids-will-join-iphones-in-offering-defa-48399d14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/newest-androids-will-join-iphones-in-offering-defa-48399d14/</guid><description>Authors: Timberg, Craig
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2014/09/18/newest-androids-will-join-iphones-in-offering-default-encryption-blocking-police/
Abstract: On September 18, 2014, The Washington Post published an article about the decision by Google to, for the first time, encrypt all data by default in its Android operating system. Previously, the operating system required a user to enable encryption in the device settings, but “few users [knew] how to turn on the feature.” Google made this move in order to be more competitive with Apple’s smartphones, who already encrypt all data by default.</description></item><item><title>NSA Isn’t the Going Dark Solution, Part I: Richard Clarke Gets It Wrong</title><link>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-cl-976df318/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-cl-976df318/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/nsa-isnt-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-clarke-gets-it-wrong
Abstract: Let’s start with a point that will be significant emotional satisfaction to many readers: Richard Clarke was dead wrong. In a remarkable statement last week, the former Clinton and early Bush administration counterterrorism official told NPR’s Morning Edition:</description></item><item><title>NSA Isn’t the Going Dark Solution, Part II: There’s No Such Thing As Magic</title><link>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-9863433f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-9863433f/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/nsa-isnt-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-such-thing-magic
Abstract: In Part I of this series, I noted the tendency of commentators—without any actual knowledge—to assert that NSA could simply break into a given locked iPhone.</description></item><item><title>Old Technopanic in New iBottles</title><link>/entries/old-technopanic-in-new-ibottles-50857d54/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/old-technopanic-in-new-ibottles-50857d54/</guid><description>Authors: Julian Sanchez
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.cato.org/blog/old-technopanic-new-ibottles
Abstract: If we aim to preserve an “equilibrium” between government power and citizen privacy, we should accept that it will occasionally close one as well.</description></item><item><title>Open Letter to Mark Zuckerberg: Facebook's "Privacy First" Proposals</title><link>/entries/open-letter-to-mark-zuckerberg-facebook-s-privacy-ac79aa39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/open-letter-to-mark-zuckerberg-facebook-s-privacy-ac79aa39/</guid><description>Authors: Patel, Priti and Barr, William and McAleenan, Kevin K. and Dutton, Peter
Published: November 2019
Abstract: From US, UK, Australia objecting to implementation of end-to-end encryption without ensuring &amp;ldquo;there is no reduction in user safety and without including a means for lawful access to the content of communications to protect our citizens.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Open Letter to Mark Zuckerberg: Facebook's End-to-End Security Plans</title><link>/entries/open-letter-to-mark-zuckerberg-facebook-s-end-to-e-81bc1514/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/open-letter-to-mark-zuckerberg-facebook-s-end-to-e-81bc1514/</guid><description>Published: October 2019
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/open-letter-facebooks-end-to-end-encryption-plans/
Abstract: Letter in support of end-to-end encryption from 112 signatory groups/associations.</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad Idea</title><link>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</guid><description>Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Abstract: In April 2015, OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston was schedule to testify before the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform’s Subcommittee on Information Technology regarding backdoor mandates and potential U.S. policy responses. New America published this blog post, on April 28, 2015, summarizing Bankston’s prepared statement and highlighting the ten key reasons Bankston identified against backdoor mandates. The reasons identified by Bankston were: 1) surveillance backdoors were already rejected as a policy approach two decades ago, including by Congress; 2) it would seriously undermine U.</description></item><item><title>Prepared Statement by Senator Chuck Grassley, Hearing On “Going Dark: Encryption, Technology, and the Balance Between Public Safety and Privacy</title><link>/entries/prepared-statement-by-senator-chuck-grassley-heari-63a8fa1c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/prepared-statement-by-senator-chuck-grassley-heari-63a8fa1c/</guid><description>Authors: Grassley, Chuck
Published: July 2015
Abstract: On July 8, 2015, Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, Senator Chuck Grassley, addressed a Senate hearing, inquiring “whether recent technological changes have upset the balance between public safety and privacy.” Of particular focus for Senator Grassley was responding to law enforcement questions of “whether the laws Congress has enacted over the years to adapt [the framework of the Fourth Amendment] to changing technology, such as the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act, or CALEA, are adequate to the task [of preserving the rule of law, ensuring the maintenance of public safety, and protecting individual privacy and civil liberties].</description></item><item><title>Press Release: The Search for Quantum-Resistant Cryptography: Understanding the Future Landscape</title><link>/entries/press-release-the-search-for-quantum-resistant-cry-90e3d809/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/press-release-the-search-for-quantum-resistant-cry-90e3d809/</guid><description>Published: September 2019
URL: https://sectigo.com/newsroom/the-search-for-quantum-resistant-cryptography-understanding-the-future-landscape
Abstract: This press release by Sectigo, a commercial Certificate Authority, describes Sectigo&amp;rsquo;s release of educational materials that describe how developments in quantum computing could render modern encryption ineffective. The materials describe the necessity for quantum-resistant cryptography, the capabilities such technology must possess, and the efforts to develop quantum-resistant algorithms.</description></item><item><title>Promoting Public Saftey, Privacy, and the Rule of Law Around the World: The Purpose and Impact of the CLOUD Act</title><link>/entries/promoting-public-saftey-privacy-and-the-rule-of-la-062fe8ee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/promoting-public-saftey-privacy-and-the-rule-of-la-062fe8ee/</guid><description>Published: April 2019
Abstract: In April 2019, the Department of Justice published this White Paper on the purpose and impact of the CLOUD Act. The Paper explains the CLOUD Act was enacted to speed access to electronic information held by U.S.-based global providers (communications service providers, “CSPs”) that is critical to foreign partners’ investigations of serious crimes. Specifically, the CLOUD Act is designed to permit those “foreign partners that have robust protections for privacy and civil liberties to enter into executive agreements with the United States to obtain access” this electronic information and evidence.</description></item><item><title>Protecting the Fourth Amendment in the Information Age: A Response to Robert Litt</title><link>/entries/protecting-the-fourth-amendment-in-the-information-5c78fc7e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/protecting-the-fourth-amendment-in-the-information-5c78fc7e/</guid><description>Authors: Cohn, Cindy
Published: 2016
Abstract: On July 27, 2016, the Yale Law Journal Forum published a short essay that agrees in part and disagrees in part with Robert Litt’s, General Counsel of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, “new analysis for the Fourth Amendment in the Information Age”. The author rejected Litt’s proposal that the “reasonable expectation of privacy” test “should simply be eliminated”, and analyzed why Litt’s proposed balancing test is not a suitable replacement.</description></item><item><title>Questions for Apple</title><link>/entries/questions-for-apple-b3e6b97c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/questions-for-apple-b3e6b97c/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey, Benjamin Wittes
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/questions-apple
Abstract: On March 1, 2016, Susan Hennessey and Benjamin Wittes, Executive Editor and Editor in Chief of Lawfare, wrote in Lawfare regarding a House Judiciary Committee hearing at which both FBI Director James Comey and Apple General Counsel Bruce Sewell were scheduled to testify on going dark matters. Hennessey and Wittes published a series of questions for Apple. The questions covered a range of topics, including anticipated impacts on Apple stemming from China’s 2015 Counterterrorism Law and Apple’s rationale for declining to comply with requests from law enforcement to decrypt their devices.</description></item><item><title>Report of the Attorney General's Cyber Digital Task Force</title><link>/entries/report-of-the-attorney-general-s-cyber-digital-tas-7bcf0590/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/report-of-the-attorney-general-s-cyber-digital-tas-7bcf0590/</guid><description>Published: July 2018
Abstract: In February of 2018, the Attorney General established a Cyber-Digital Task force within the U.S. Department of Justice and tasked it with answer two foundational questions. First, “how is the Department responding to cyber threats?” Second, “how can federal law enforcement more effectively accomplish its mission in this important and rapidly evolving area?” This Report addresses the first question. The Report begins with a focus on malign foreign influence operations, before expanding into a discussion of other cyber-enabled threats.</description></item><item><title>Report of the Special Rapporteur on the promotion and protection of the right to freedom of opinion and expression, David Kaye</title><link>/entries/report-of-the-special-rapporteur-on-the-promotion-8c9333a5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/report-of-the-special-rapporteur-on-the-promotion-8c9333a5/</guid><description>Authors: Kaye, David
Published: May 2015
URL: https://www.undocs.org/A/HRC/29/32
Abstract: On June 19, 2018, the United Nations’ Special Rapporteur on the promotion and protection of the right to freedom of opinion and expression issued a report regarding Liberia’s protections of the right to freedom of opinion and expression. The aim of the visit and subsequent report was “to assess the situation as regards the right to freedom of expression in [Liberia], in particular the issues of press freedom, media independence and diversity, and access to information.</description></item><item><title>Report on Post-Quantum Cryptography</title><link>/entries/report-on-post-quantum-cryptography-ee42092b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/report-on-post-quantum-cryptography-ee42092b/</guid><description>Authors: Lily Chen, Stephen Jordan, Yi-Kai Liu, Dustin Moody, Rene Peralta, Ray Perlner, Daniel Smith-Tone
Published: April 2016
URL: https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2016/NIST.IR.8105.pdf
Abstract: In recent years, there has been a substantial amount of research on quantum computers –machines that exploit quantum mechanical phenomena to solve mathematical problems that are difficult or intractable for conventional computers. If large-scale quantum computers are ever built, they will be able to break many of the public-key cryptosystems currently in use.</description></item><item><title>Revealed: How US and UK Spy Agencies Defeat Internet Privacy and Security</title><link>/entries/revealed-how-us-and-uk-spy-agencies-defeat-interne-6703184c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/revealed-how-us-and-uk-spy-agencies-defeat-interne-6703184c/</guid><description>Authors: Ball, James and Borger, Julian and Greenwald, Glenn
Published: September 2013
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/sep/05/nsa-gchq-encryption-codes-security
Abstract: • NSA and GCHQ unlock encryption used to protect emails, banking and medical records• $250m-a-year US program works covertly with tech companies to insert weaknesses into products• Security experts say programs &amp;lsquo;undermine the fabric of the internet&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>Russia Wants to Make an Example of Telegram</title><link>/entries/russia-wants-to-make-an-example-of-telegram-7aa97786/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/russia-wants-to-make-an-example-of-telegram-7aa97786/</guid><description>Authors: Bershidsky, Leonid
Published: September 2017
URL: https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2017-09-28/russia-wants-to-make-an-example-of-telegram
Abstract: The messaging app is under direct attack from Russian domestic intelligence. The real target may be Facebook and Twitter.</description></item><item><title>S. 1336 - Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/s-1336-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-act-e1fa535f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-1336-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-act-e1fa535f/</guid><description>Authors: Warren, Elizabeth and Warner
Published: May 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/1336/text
Abstract: To create an Office of Cybersecurity at the Federal Trade Commission for supervision of data security at consumer reporting agencies, to require the promulgation of regulations establishing standards for effective cybersecurity at consumer reporting agencies, to impose penalties on credit reporting agencies for cybersecurity breaches that put sensitive consumer data at risk, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>S. 2889 - National Security and Personal Data Protection Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/s-2889-national-security-and-personal-data-protect-a7b6e85d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-2889-national-security-and-personal-data-protect-a7b6e85d/</guid><description>Authors: Hawley, Josh and Cotton, Tom and Rubio, Marco
Published: November 2019
Abstract: To safeguard data of Americans from foreign governments that pose risks to national security by imposing data security requirements and strengthening review of foreign investments, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>S.1842 - Protecting Personal Health Data Act</title><link>/entries/s-1842-protecting-personal-health-data-act-8bffdbe7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-1842-protecting-personal-health-data-act-8bffdbe7/</guid><description>Authors: Klobuchar, Amy and Murkowski, Lisa
Published: June 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/1842/text
Abstract: To protect the personal health data of all Americans.</description></item><item><title>Secret US Cybersecurity Report: Encryption Vital to Protect Private Data</title><link>/entries/secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-vital-to-9703fda8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-vital-to-9703fda8/</guid><description>Authors: Ball, James
Published: January 2015
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/jan/15/-sp-secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-protect-data-cameron-paris-attacks
Abstract: Newly uncovered Snowden document contrasts with British PM’s vow to crack down on encrypted messaging after Paris attacks</description></item><item><title>Security vs. Security - Rapid7 Supports Strong Encryption</title><link>/entries/security-vs-security-rapid7-supports-strong-encryp-4634f37f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-vs-security-rapid7-supports-strong-encryp-4634f37f/</guid><description>Authors: Geiger, Harley
Published: April 2016
URL: https://blog.rapid7.com/2016/04/01/security-vs-security-rapid7-supports-strong-encryption/
Abstract: A major area of focus in the current cybersecurity policy discussion is how growing adoption of encryption impacts law enforcement and national security, and whether new policies should be developed in response. This post briefly evaluates several potential outcomes of the debate, and provides Rapid7&amp;rsquo;s current position on each. Background</description></item><item><title>Security Win: Burr-Feinstein Proposal Declared “Dead” for This Year</title><link>/entries/security-win-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-728401be/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-win-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-728401be/</guid><description>Authors: Reitman, rainey
Published: May 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/05/win-one-security-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-year
Abstract: This post from the Electronic Frontier Foundation details how proposed legislation from Senators Burr and Feinstein was not going to be introduced, which was seen as a win by many privacy advocates. The article explains the proposal, which would mandate backdoors, and then describes that although it would not advance, many others like it were still being proposed or debated.</description></item><item><title>Security “Front Doors” vs. “Back Doors”: A Distinction Without a Difference</title><link>/entries/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-a-distinction-w-27fb709b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-a-distinction-w-27fb709b/</guid><description>Authors: Jeffrey Vagle, Matt Blaze
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.justsecurity.org/16503/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-distinction-difference/
Abstract: This article by Jeffrey Vagle and Matt Blaze discusses FBI Director James Comey’s speeches calling for back doors in encryption for law enforcement and argues that it is technologically infeasible and politically wise. The article details how back doors will eventually be uncovered and lead to vulnerabilities in systems. Finally, the article argues that the language being used to advocate for back doors builds a false sense of security in populations unfamiliar with the technological realities and leads people away from more workable solutions.</description></item><item><title>Security, Surveillance And The Truth About Going Dark</title><link>/entries/security-surveillance-and-the-truth-about-going-da-639358d3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-surveillance-and-the-truth-about-going-da-639358d3/</guid><description>Authors: Blech, Richard
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2019/07/25/security-surveillance-and-the-truth-about-going-dark/
Abstract: This article details a meeting among government officials on whether to ban the public availability and explores similar proposals from the past. The article details how encryption policy frequently debates back doors and the balance between security and surveillance. The article argues that as surveillance technology becomes increasingly prevalent, security must be prioritized.</description></item><item><title>Shining a Light on the Encryption Debate: A Canadian Field Guide</title><link>/entries/shining-a-light-on-the-encryption-debate-a-canadia-9d78aca2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/shining-a-light-on-the-encryption-debate-a-canadia-9d78aca2/</guid><description>Authors: Gill, Lex and Parsons, Christopher and Israel, Tamir
Published: May 2018</description></item><item><title>Statement of General Keith B. Alexander, Commander, United States Cyber Command, Before the Senate Committee on Armed Services</title><link>/entries/statement-of-general-keith-b-alexander-commander-u-d467327a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/statement-of-general-keith-b-alexander-commander-u-d467327a/</guid><description>Authors: Alexander, Keith B.
Published: March 2013</description></item><item><title>Status Report on the First Round of the NIST Post-Quantum Cryptography Standardization Process</title><link>/entries/status-report-on-the-first-round-of-the-nist-post-579fe6e3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/status-report-on-the-first-round-of-the-nist-post-579fe6e3/</guid><description>Authors: Alagic, Gorjan and Alperin-Sheriff, Jacob and Apon, Daniel and Cooper, David and Dang, Quynh and Liu, Yi-Kai and Miller, Carl and Moody, Dustin and Peralta, Rene and Perlner, Ray and Robinson, Angela and Smith-Tone, Daniel
Published: January 2019
URL: https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2019/NIST.IR.8240.pdf
Abstract: The National Institute of Standards and Technology is in the process of selecting one or more public-key cryptographic algorithms through a public competition-like process. The new publickey cryptography standards will specify one or more additional digital signature, public-key encryption, and key-establishment algorithms to augment FIPS 186-4, Digital Signature Standard (DSS), as well as special publications SP 800-56A Revision 2, Recommendation for Pair-Wise Key Establishment Schemes Using Discrete Logarithm Cryptography, and SP 800-56B, Recommendation for Pair-Wise Key-Establishment Schemes Using Integer Factorization.</description></item><item><title>Submission of the Citizen Lab (Munk School of Global Affairs, University of Toronto) to the United Nations Special Rapporteur on Violence Against Women, Its Causes and Consequences, Ms. Dubravka Šimonović</title><link>/entries/submission-of-the-citizen-lab-munk-school-of-globa-8208d51f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/submission-of-the-citizen-lab-munk-school-of-globa-8208d51f/</guid><description>Published: November 2017
URL: https://citizenlab.ca/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Final-UNSRVAG-CitizenLab.pdf
Abstract: This report, submitted to the o the United Nations Special Rapporteur on violence against women, details how gender-based violence can be perpetrated through technology and how encryption should be part of the solution to prevent such violence. The report offers case studies of gendered violence in Canada and proposes solutions. Among those solutions, encryption can offer privacy and anonymity to victims, as well as advocates.</description></item><item><title>Surveillance Costs: The NSA's Impact on the Economy, Internet Freedom \&amp; Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/surveillance-costs-the-nsa-s-impact-on-the-economy-5c789458/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/surveillance-costs-the-nsa-s-impact-on-the-economy-5c789458/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle and Bankston, Kevin and Greene, Robyn and Morgus, Robert
Published: July 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/policy-papers/surveillance-costs-the-nsas-impact-on-the-economy-internet-freedom-cybersecurity/
Abstract: It has been over a year since The Guardian reported the first story on the National Security Agency’s surveillance programs based on the leaks from former NSA contractor Edward Snowden, yet the national conversation remains largely mired in a simplistic debate over the tradeoffs between national security and individual privacy. It is time to start weighing the overall costs and benefits more broadly.</description></item><item><title>the People of the State of Colorado v. Shaun R. Davis</title><link>/entries/the-people-of-the-state-of-colorado-v-shaun-r-davi-ca69bf48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-people-of-the-state-of-colorado-v-shaun-r-davi-ca69bf48/</guid><description>Published: April 2019
Abstract: In Colorado v. Davis, the Colorado Supreme Court held that using a passcode given to police officers to execute a search warrant on a smartphone did not violate the Fourth Amendment. In this case, a criminal defendant had given his cellphone passcode to police officers during his arrest so they could call his girlfriend. Later, after law enforcement received a warrant to search the phone, the passcode was used to search the phone.</description></item><item><title>The Burr-Feinstein Proposal Is Simply Anti-Security</title><link>/entries/the-burr-feinstein-proposal-is-simply-anti-securit-e9e5d5f1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-burr-feinstein-proposal-is-simply-anti-securit-e9e5d5f1/</guid><description>Authors: Cohn, Cindy
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/04/burr-feinstein-proposal-simply-anti-security
Abstract: This article described proposed legislation that would require technology companies—including device manufacturers, software developers, ISPs, and others—to decrypt data if ordered to do so by any court at any time. Further, because the proposed actions are not feasible, and if the law were enacted it would harm Americans’ privacy, all while foreign alternatives would still be available. The article argues that because the proposal is so far removed from any technologically feasible solution, it demonstrates how out of touch key regulators are with the reality of encryption.</description></item><item><title>The Encryption Debate in the European Union</title><link>/entries/the-encryption-debate-in-the-european-union-6437b4a5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-encryption-debate-in-the-european-union-6437b4a5/</guid><description>Authors: Koomen, Maria and Koomen, Maria
Published: May 2019
URL: https://carnegieendowment.org/2019/05/30/encryption-debate-in-european-union-pub-79220
Abstract: The Encryption Debate in the European Union is a policy brief that describes the intensifying encryption debate in the European Union, the interests and actors involved, and a possible timeline and substance of potential legislation. While encryption had largely thrived in Europe since the 1990s, the occurrence of multiple terror attacks in the late 10’s sparked a debate about encryption and national security within the EU.</description></item><item><title>The Encryption Tightrope: Balancing Americans' Security and Privacy</title><link>/entries/the-encryption-tightrope-balancing-americans-secur-8372b960/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-encryption-tightrope-balancing-americans-secur-8372b960/</guid><description>Published: March 2016
Abstract: On March 1, 2016, the House Judiciary Committee of the 114th Congress held a hearing entitled, The Encryption Tightrope: Balancing Americans’ Security and Privacy. The key focus of the hearing was answering the question: How do we deploy ever stronger, more effective encryption without unduly preventing lawful access to communications of criminals and terrorists intent on doing us harm? The Committee began the hearing by nothing its chief concern, that “[a]doption of new communications technologies by those intending harm to the American people is outpacing law enforcement’s technological capability to access those communications in legitimate criminal and national security investigations.</description></item><item><title>The Five Eyes Statement on Encryption: Things Are Seldom What They Seem</title><link>/entries/the-five-eyes-statement-on-encryption-things-are-s-be5639a2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-five-eyes-statement-on-encryption-things-are-s-be5639a2/</guid><description>Authors: Landau, Susan
Published: September 2018
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/five-eyes-statement-encryption-things-are-seldom-what-they-seem
Abstract: This report from Lawfare details a summit of law enforcement officials from the Five Eyes intelligence alliance—made up of Australia, Canada, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, and the United States—and argues that the rhetoric espoused was far less troubling than it seemed. At the summit, Australian officials detailed an aggressive stance against encryption. However, by ignoring technical realities, the policy proposals are rendered toothless.</description></item><item><title>The Human Rights Benefits of Encryption</title><link>/entries/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption-9be91f1d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption-9be91f1d/</guid><description>Authors: Andi Wilson Thompson
Published: March 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption/
Abstract: The Human Rights Benefits of Encryption is a blog post detailing public interest organizations&amp;rsquo; efforts to have encryption recognized as a right by the UN Human Rights Council. This article describes submissions by a multitude of public interest organizations—including the ACLU, Human Rights Watch, and technology-specific organizations—and their arguments for the importance of encryption to free expression, privacy, and human rights.</description></item><item><title>The NSA’s Split-Key Encryption Proposal is Not Serious</title><link>/entries/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-seri-126e61d2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-seri-126e61d2/</guid><description>Authors: Joseph Lorenzo Hall
Published: April 2015
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-serious/
Abstract: The NSA&amp;rsquo;s Split-Key Encryption Proposal is Not Serious discusses the NSA&amp;rsquo;s 2020 proposal to require technology companies to create a &amp;ldquo;golden key,&amp;rdquo; a split-key that would allow the company or the NSA access to encrypted communications. Hall argues that split-key encryption is a technology infeasible, vulnerable, and costly, and would not be able to ensure any data was protected from the NSA.</description></item><item><title>The Risks of “Responsible Encryption”</title><link>/entries/the-risks-of-responsible-encryption-149c012c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-risks-of-responsible-encryption-149c012c/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2018
Abstract: The Risks of “Responsible Encryption” critiques “responsible encryption,” a term developed used by US law enforcement officials describing a general policy of government access to encrypted materials. The article begins by detailing the origins of the terms and their use by government officials, then seeks to define the scope of the term and possible technical definitions. Next, the paper warns of the risks of exceptional access, including increased key usage and access, authentication of exceptional access requests at scale, the economic and competitive effects on US technology companies, and the limitations of exceptional access capabilities.</description></item><item><title>The Role of Encryption in Australia</title><link>/entries/the-role-of-encryption-in-australia-4e0f543e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-role-of-encryption-in-australia-4e0f543e/</guid><description>Authors: O&amp;rsquo;Shea, Lizzie and Thomas, Elise
Published: January 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/01/Crypto-Australia-Memo.pdf
Abstract: Encryption is essential to Australia’s modern digital society, economy, and cyber security, and it is only effective if it is strong and robust.
Strong encryption serves Australia’s national interests by protecting governments, communities, and the economy from criminal, terrorist, and state-sponsored attacks.
Encryption will only become more important for protecting Australian interests as technology advances in the coming decades.</description></item><item><title>The Shifting Landscape of Global Internet Censorship</title><link>/entries/the-shifting-landscape-of-global-internet-censorsh-92d9e491/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-shifting-landscape-of-global-internet-censorsh-92d9e491/</guid><description>Authors: Zittrain, Jonathan L. and Faris, Robert and Noman, Helmi and Clark, Justin and Tilton, Casey and Morrison-Westphal, Ryan
Published: 2017
URL: https://www.ssrn.com/abstract=2993485
Abstract: The 2017 Shifting Landscape of Global Internet Censorship by the Berkman Klein Center for Internet &amp;amp; Society is the 2017 update to their report which studies Internet censorship in 75 countries. The study looks at the filtering of documents and information, both in terms of specific topics or individuals as well as entire platforms.</description></item><item><title>The Way Forward: Working Together to Tackle Cybercrime</title><link>/entries/the-way-forward-working-together-to-tackle-cybercr-9b44953b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-way-forward-working-together-to-tackle-cybercr-9b44953b/</guid><description>Authors: Wray, Christopher
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/speeches/the-way-forward-working-together-to-tackle-cybercrime
Abstract: These remarks, given by Cristopher Wray, former director of the FBI at the 2019 FBI International Conference on Cyber Security, offer an insight into the goals and capabilities of the FBI. Director Wray describes the capabilities of the FBI to combat cybersecurity, the dangers of foreign influence, and the foreign development of cyber technology. Then, Director Wray argues how encryption impedes law enforcement, describes specific crimes where encrypted information hindered an FBI investigation, and argues that lawful access to encrypted materials is increasingly necessary to law enforcement investigations.</description></item><item><title>Travel Guide to the Digital World: Encryption Policy for Human Rights Defenders</title><link>/entries/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-encryption-polic-d0a50ee7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-encryption-polic-d0a50ee7/</guid><description>Authors: Global Partners Digital, Stepanovich, Amie, Wingfield, Richard
Published: 2017
URL: https://www.gp-digital.org/publication/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-4-encryption-policy-for-human-rights-defenders/
Abstract: This is a guide, aimed at a non-technical audience, seeking to explain the connection between human rights and encryption. The article gives a background on the basics of encryption, and how it affects the day-to-day life of people around the globe, and its impacts on privacy and freedom of expression. Finally, the article outlines the legal and policy background of encryption regulation across the globe and at the international, national, and local levels.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Says It Has Unlocked iPhone Without Apple</title><link>/entries/u-s-says-it-has-unlocked-iphone-without-apple-c5d963b4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/u-s-says-it-has-unlocked-iphone-without-apple-c5d963b4/</guid><description>Authors: Benner, Katie and Lichtblau, Eric
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2016/03/29/technology/apple-iphone-fbi-justice-department-case.html
Abstract: This New York Times article by Katie Benner and Eric Lichtblau reports on the government&amp;rsquo;s successful unlocking of the iPhone of the suspect in the San Bernardino mass shooting, the investigation which gave rise to the Apple vs. FBI court case. The article reports on how the successful unlocking may lead Apple to request information about the exploited vulnerability in order to fix it.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Tries to Make It Easier to Wiretap the Internet</title><link>/entries/u-s-tries-to-make-it-easier-to-wiretap-the-interne-7c6b8243/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/u-s-tries-to-make-it-easier-to-wiretap-the-interne-7c6b8243/</guid><description>Authors: Savage, Charlie
Published: September 2010
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2010/09/27/us/27wiretap.html
Abstract: This New York Times article by Charlie Savage reports on planned legislation by the Obama administration which would allow for the US government to decrypt select communications and prevent going dark. The article discusses how encryption has worked in recent law enforcement investigations, and why the government finds such a technology necessary. The article discusses the feasibility of different possible elements of the proposed law, including attempting to regulate encryption technology coming from abroad.</description></item><item><title>US Government Fines Intel's Wind River Over Crypto Exports</title><link>/entries/us-government-fines-intel-s-wind-river-over-crypto-09cbe60a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/us-government-fines-intel-s-wind-river-over-crypto-09cbe60a/</guid><description>Authors: Leyden, John
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.theregister.co.uk/2014/10/17/intel_subsidiary_crypto_export_fine/
Abstract: This article by John Leyden discussed a $750,000 fine by the Department of Commerce on Wind River for exporting products utilizing encryption to foreign nations, including China, Russia, and Israel. The article explores increasing action by regulators, viewing large fines for violations as the norm going forward, in the conflict over foreign control over encryption. The article explores the consequences of escalating enforcement action over the trade of encrypted technology with foreign nations.</description></item><item><title>Why An Encryption Backdoor for Just the "Good Guys" Won't Work</title><link>/entries/why-an-encryption-backdoor-for-just-the-good-guys-918a9e9d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/why-an-encryption-backdoor-for-just-the-good-guys-918a9e9d/</guid><description>Authors: Stepanovich, Amie and Karanicolas, Michael
Published: March 2018
URL: https://www.justsecurity.org/53316/criminalize-security-criminals-secure/
Abstract: Recently, U.S. law enforcement officials have re-energized their push for a technical means to bypass encryption. But seeking to undermine encryption only looks backward instead of focusing on where technology is going. We should be having conversations about new investigative techniques, not trying to preserve the access enjoyed in the days before encryption was so widespread, particularly when so much is at stake in doing so.</description></item><item><title>Wiretapping and Cryptography Today</title><link>/entries/wiretapping-and-cryptography-today-02c48835/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/wiretapping-and-cryptography-today-02c48835/</guid><description>Authors: Matt Blaze
Published: July 2011
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20110715210433/http://www.crypto.com/blog/wiretap2010
Abstract: This blog post from Matt Blaze examines the 2011 Wiretap report and argues that encryption has done little to hinder law enforcement. The blog post points out that despite the increased prevalence of encryption, few wiretap searches by law enforcement even encountered encryption, and never did it interfere with the investigation. The proposes that with the increased prevalence of encryption, law enforcement methods have adapted.</description></item><item><title>Worried about Apple? California Has a Bill That Would Disable Encryption on All Phones</title><link>/entries/worried-about-apple-california-has-a-bill-that-wou-8a2f438c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/worried-about-apple-california-has-a-bill-that-wou-8a2f438c/</guid><description>Authors: Andrew Crocker
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/03/worried-about-apple-california-has-bill-would-disable-encryption-all-phones
Abstract: This article from the Electronic Frontier Foundation discusses a bill proposed in the California state legislature that would require smartphones sold in the state to be capable of being decrypted by the manufacturer. The article discusses the concurrent Apple court case seeking decryption, and other similar legislation being proposed at the state and federal levels. The article argues that such measures are likely unconstitutional, but that they are also ineffective and impractical.</description></item><item><title>“Five Eyes” Governments Respond to Coalition Demands to Stop Undermining Encryption</title><link>/entries/five-eyes-governments-respond-to-coalition-demands-c670f1bb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/five-eyes-governments-respond-to-coalition-demands-c670f1bb/</guid><description>Authors: Cyphers, Bennett and Stepanovich, Amie
Published: October 2017
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/five-eyes-governments-respond-coalition-demands-stop-undermining-encryption/
Abstract: Status update on the Five Eyes governments&amp;rsquo; position on encryptionIn October of 2017, Amie Stepanovich and Bennett Cyphers of Access Now, wrote regarding the organization’s decision to join the more than 80 members of civil society from the “Five Eyes” countries in a letter calling on government leaders to protect strong encryption, and the responses received to date. The letter called for “an unequivocal rejection of laws, policies or other mandates or practices—including secret agreements with companies—that limit access to or undermine encryption and other secure communications tools and technologies.</description></item></channel></rss>