<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Crypto Wars on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/crypto-wars/</link><description>Recent content in Crypto Wars on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/crypto-wars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Academic: The Risks of Key Recovery, Key Escrow, and Trusted Third-Party Encryption - Schneier on Security</title><link>/entries/71/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/71/</guid><description>Authors: H. Abelson, R. Anderson, S. M. Bellovin, J. Benaloh, M. Blaze, W. Diffie, J. Gilmore, P. G. Neumann, R. L. Rivest, J. I. Schiller, B. Schneier
Published: 1998
URL: https://www.schneier.com/academic/archives/1997/04/the_risks_of_key_rec.html
Abstract: A variety of &amp;ldquo;key recovery,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;key escrow,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;trusted third-party&amp;rdquo; encryption requirements have been suggested in recent years by government agencies seeking to conduct covert surveillance within the changing environments brought about by new technologies. This report examines the fundamental properties of these requirements and attempts to outline the technical risks, costs, and implications of deploying systems that provide government access to encryption keys.</description></item><item><title>CDT \textbar Law Professors Letter regarding SAFE Amendments</title><link>/entries/39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/39/</guid><description>Published: February 1999
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/19990224070155/http://www.cdt.org/crypto/legis_105/SAFE/97093_profs.html</description></item><item><title>Congress Mulls Stiff Crypto Laws</title><link>/entries/36/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/36/</guid><description>Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/09/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws/
Abstract: Some lawmakers say encryption laws can let terrorists plot attacks such as Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s assaults on the East Coast. Congress is considering a crypto-crackdown. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>Disputes on Electronic Message Encryption Take On New Urgency</title><link>/entries/153/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/153/</guid><description>Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2001/09/25/business/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-new-urgency.html
Abstract: Attacks of Sept 11 renew debate on how strongly public&amp;ndash;and by extension terrorists and other criminals&amp;ndash;should be able to encrypt their electronic messages; technology of scrambling data and messages has become crucial element of computer security for businesses and consumers; officials of law enforcement and intelligence agencies have long warned lawmakers that they were unable to break strongest encryption products, and that crimes eventually would be committed that might otherwise have been prevented; FBI has not said publicly whether hijackers who attacked World Trade Center and Pentagon even used encryption to cloak their communications; Philip R Zimmermann, creator of popular encryption programs, known as PGP, says he would be surprised if this were not case; Sen Judd Gregg says he will not make specific legislative proposal until he sees what Atty Gen John Ashcroft includes in final version of his broad anti-terrorism bill; says he wants to see legislation to order encryption companies that sell products in US to include back door that would allow government access when terrorist uses encyption (M)</description></item><item><title>Doomed to Repeat History?</title><link>/entries/8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/8/</guid><description>Published: June 2015</description></item><item><title>Encryption and Globalization</title><link>/entries/156/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/156/</guid><description>Published: 2012
URL: http://www.ssrn.com/abstract=1960602</description></item><item><title>EPIC - Efforts to Ban Encryption in the 1990s</title><link>/entries/148/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/148/</guid><description>Published: 1995
URL: https://www.epic.org/crypto/ban/
Abstract: The Electronic Privacy Information Center (EPIC) focuses public attention on emerging civil liberties, privacy, First Amendment issues and works to promote the Public Voice in decisions concerning the future of the Internet.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Encryption and Potential Mechanisms for Authorized Government Access to Plaintext: Proceedings of a Workshop</title><link>/entries/157/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/157/</guid><description>Authors: National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine
Published: June 2016
URL: https://www.nap.edu/read/23593/chapter/1
Abstract: Read chapter Front Matter: In June 2016 the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine convened the Workshop on Encryption and Mechanisms</description></item><item><title>GAO Report on Communications Privacy</title><link>/entries/127/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/127/</guid><description>Authors: U.S. General Accounting Office
Published: November 1993
URL: https://epic.org/crypto/reports/gao_comm_privacy.html</description></item><item><title>Information Security and Privacy in Network Environments</title><link>/entries/154/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/154/</guid><description>Authors: Computing Technologies Program (Joan Winston) Telecommunications
Published: September 1994
URL: https://www.epic.org/crypto/reports/ota_1994.html</description></item><item><title>Key escrow from a safe distance: looking back at the Clipper Chip</title><link>/entries/73/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/73/</guid><description>Published: 2011
URL: http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?doid=2076732.2076777
Abstract: In 1993, the US Government proposed a novel (and highly controversial) approach to cryptography, called key escrow. Key escrow cryptosystems used standard symmetric- and public- key ciphers, key management techniques and protocols, but with one added feature: a copy of the current session key, itself encrypted with a key known to the government, was sent at the beginning of every encrypted communication stream. In this way, if a government wiretapper encountered ciphertext produced under a key escrowed cryptosystem, recovering the plaintext would be a simple matter of decrypting the session key with the government’s key, regardless of the strength of the underlying cipher algorithms.</description></item><item><title>McCaul’s Crypto Commission: First, do no harm</title><link>/entries/195/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/195/</guid><description>Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/mccauls-crypto-commission-first-no-harm/
Abstract: However well-intended, a new Congressional commission on encryption may do more harm than good.</description></item><item><title>Senator Backs Off Backdoors</title><link>/entries/151/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/151/</guid><description>Published: October 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/10/senator-backs-off-backdoors/
Abstract: A senator changes his mind after calling for a prohibition on data-scrambling products without backdoors for government surveillance. Now, he &amp;ldquo;has no intentions&amp;rdquo; of working on such an encryption bill. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>Techies Urge Senator To Drop Encryption Key Plan</title><link>/entries/152/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/152/</guid><description>Authors: Brian Krebs
Published: October 2001
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20011011022244/http://www.newsbytes.com/news/01/170592.html</description></item><item><title>White House Clipper Statement (4/16/93)</title><link>/entries/117/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/117/</guid><description>Authors: Office of the Press Secretary
Published: April 1993
URL: https://epic.org/crypto/clipper/white_house_statement_4_93.html</description></item><item><title>Wiretapping and Cryptography Today</title><link>/entries/96/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/96/</guid><description>Authors: Matt Blaze
Published: July 2011
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20110715210433/http://www.crypto.com/blog/wiretap2010</description></item></channel></rss>