<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Crypto Wars on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/crypto-wars/</link><description>Recent content in Crypto Wars on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/crypto-wars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Flawed Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/119/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/119/</guid><description>Authors: Anonymous
Published: April 1996
URL: https://search.proquest.com/docview/430685501/fulltext/2EA1B6B49BC74036PQ/1?accountid=14503
Tags: 1990s Clinton Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls Terrorism Abstract: An editorial contends that the new White House proposal to keep high-powered encryption software out of the hands of foreign terrorists and criminals is needlessly restrictive and probably unworkable. The editorial says that the technology, which is legal in the US, is a good way for honest citizens to prevent crime and should be disseminated domestically and abroad.</description></item><item><title>A Roadmap for Exceptional Access Research</title><link>/entries/131/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/131/</guid><description>Authors: Mayank Varia
Published: December 2018
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/roadmap-exceptional-access-research
Tags: 2010s Crypto Wars Exceptional Access Abstract: This is part of a series of essays from the Crypto 2018 Workshop on Encryption and Surveillance.</description></item><item><title>A “Stumbling” US Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/120/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/120/</guid><description>Authors: Madsen, Wayne
Published: July 1997
URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1361372397895486
Tags: 1990s Clinton Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls Key Recovery Abstract: “Are those in opposition to the administration&amp;rsquo;s [encryption] policy prepared to sacrifice public safety in the interests of commercial gain?” Those words, uttered by Deputy Assistant Attorney General Robert Litt, would etch themselves in the minds of those who attended the 7 May 1977 House International Economic Policy and Trade hearing on “Encryption: Individual Rights vs National Security”.</description></item><item><title>Another Faulty Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/118/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/118/</guid><description>Published: December 1996
URL: https://search.proquest.com/docview/430702910/fulltext/CAF9E584F5344769PQ/1?accountid=14503
Tags: 1990s Clinton Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls</description></item><item><title>Bureau of Export Administration Annual Report 1998</title><link>/entries/124/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/124/</guid><description>Authors: Bureau of Export Administration
Published: 1998
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls National Security</description></item><item><title>Clinton Administration Encryption Policy Statement \&amp; Press Briefing</title><link>/entries/117/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/117/</guid><description>Authors: President Clinton
Published: September 1998
URL: https://congressional.proquest.com/congressional
Tags: 1990s Clinton Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls Law Enforcement Security White House</description></item><item><title>Clinton Removes Export Limits on Encryption Technology</title><link>/entries/116/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/116/</guid><description>Authors: James Gerstenzang
Published: September 1999
URL: https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1999-sep-17-fi-11110-story.html
Tags: 1990s Clinton Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls Abstract: Computers: Despite objections from Pentagon and FBI, U.S. will allow sale of most powerful data-scrambling tools.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter of Law Professors to Hon. Thomas J. Biley Regarding SAFE Amendments</title><link>/entries/182/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/182/</guid><description>Authors: None Identified
Published: February 1999
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/19990224070155/http://www.cdt.org/crypto/legis_105/SAFE/97093_profs.html
Tags: 1990s Academic Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I US Congress</description></item><item><title>Complete ACM Columns Collection</title><link>/entries/110/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/110/</guid><description>Authors: John Perry Barlow
Published: 1991
URL: https://www.eff.org/pages/complete-acm-columns-collection
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Abstract: Coming Into The Country Private Life in Cyberspace The Great Work Decrypting the Puzzle Palace Will Japan Jack In? Bill O&amp;rsquo; Rights Lite A Plaintext On Crypto Dad&amp;rsquo;s Invisible Shield Death from Above</description></item><item><title>Congress Mulls Stiff Crypto Laws</title><link>/entries/105/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/105/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/09/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws/
Tags: 2000s 9/11 Crypto Wars Crypto Wars II National Security Terrorism Abstract: Some lawmakers say encryption laws can let terrorists plot attacks such as Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s assaults on the East Coast. Congress is considering a crypto-crackdown. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>Cracking DES: Secrets of Encryption Research, Wiretap Politics \&amp; Chip Design. How Federal Agencies Subvert Privacy</title><link>/entries/25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/25/</guid><description>Authors: Electronic Frontier Foundation
Published: 1998
URL: http://archive.org/details/crackingdessecre00elec
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I EFF Abstract: Includes bibliographical references</description></item><item><title>Daniel J. Bernstein v. U.S. Department of State</title><link>/entries/20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/20/</guid><description>Published: December 1996
URL: https://law.justia.com/cases/federal/district-courts/FSupp/945/1279/1457799/
Tags: 1990s Case Law Crypto Wars Abstract: Bernstein v. US Dept. of State, 945 F. Supp. 1279 (N.D. Cal. 1996) case opinion from the US District Court for the Northern District of California</description></item><item><title>Disputes on Electronic Message Encryption Take on New Urgency</title><link>/entries/148/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/148/</guid><description>Authors: Schwartz, John
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2001/09/25/business/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-new-urgency.html
Tags: 2000s 9/11 Crypto Wars Crypto Wars II Terrorism Abstract: Attacks of Sept 11 renew debate on how strongly public&amp;ndash;and by extension terrorists and other criminals&amp;ndash;should be able to encrypt their electronic messages; technology of scrambling data and messages has become crucial element of computer security for businesses and consumers; officials of law enforcement and intelligence agencies have long warned lawmakers that they were unable to break strongest encryption products, and that crimes eventually would be committed that might otherwise have been prevented; FBI has not said publicly whether hijackers who attacked World Trade Center and Pentagon even used encryption to cloak their communications; Philip R Zimmermann, creator of popular encryption programs, known as PGP, says he would be surprised if this were not case; Sen Judd Gregg says he will not make specific legislative proposal until he sees what Atty Gen John Ashcroft includes in final version of his broad anti-terrorism bill; says he wants to see legislation to order encryption companies that sell products in US to include back door that would allow government access when terrorist uses encyption (M)</description></item><item><title>Doomed to Repeat History? Lessons from the Crypto Wars of the 1990s</title><link>/entries/150/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/150/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle and Wilson, Andi and Bankston, Kevin
Published: June 2015
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars OTI</description></item><item><title>Efforts to Ban Encryption in the 1990s</title><link>/entries/145/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/145/</guid><description>Authors: Center, Electronic Privacy Information
Published: 1995
URL: https://www.epic.org/crypto/ban/
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Abstract: The Electronic Privacy Information Center (EPIC) focuses public attention on emerging civil liberties, privacy, First Amendment issues and works to promote the Public Voice in decisions concerning the future of the Internet.</description></item><item><title>Encryption and Globalization</title><link>/entries/199/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/199/</guid><description>Authors: Swire, Peter P. and Ahmad, Kenesa
Published: 2012
URL: http://www.ssrn.com/abstract=1960602
Tags: 2010s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Global</description></item><item><title>Encryption and the Press Clause</title><link>/entries/98/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/98/</guid><description>Authors: Baranetsky, D Victoria
Published: 2017
Tags: 2010s Amendment I Apple Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Crypto Wars II Journalism San Bernardino Abstract: Almost twenty years ago, a hostile debate over whether government could regulate encryption—later named the Crypto Wars—seized the country. At the center of this debate stirred one simple question: is encryption protected speech? This issue touched all branches of government percolating from Congress, to the President, and eventually to the federal courts.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Export Controls</title><link>/entries/12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/12/</guid><description>Authors: Grimmett, Jeanne J.
Published: January 2001
Tags: 1990s Amendment I Clinton Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls</description></item><item><title>Encryption Policy for the 21st Century: A Future Without Government-Prescribed Key Recovery</title><link>/entries/95/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/95/</guid><description>Authors: Singleton, Solveig
Published: November 1998
URL: https://www.cato.org/sites/cato.org/files/pubs/pdf/pa325.pdf
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Key Recovery</description></item><item><title>EPIC Key Escrow Page</title><link>/entries/66/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/66/</guid><description>Authors: Electronic Privacy Information Center
Published: April 1998
URL: https://epic.org/crypto/key_escrow/
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I EPIC</description></item><item><title>GAO Report on Communications Privacy</title><link>/entries/194/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/194/</guid><description>Authors: U.S. General Accounting Office
Published: November 1993
URL: https://epic.org/crypto/reports/gao_comm_privacy.html
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I National Security</description></item><item><title>Information Security and Privacy in Network Environments</title><link>/entries/198/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/198/</guid><description>Authors: Computing Technologies Program (Joan Winston) Telecommunications
Published: September 1994
URL: https://www.epic.org/crypto/reports/ota_1994.html
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I US Congress</description></item><item><title>Key Escrow from a Safe Distance: Looking Back at the Clipper Chip</title><link>/entries/19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/19/</guid><description>Authors: Blaze, Matt
Published: 2011
URL: http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?doid=2076732.2076777
Tags: 1990s 2010s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Abstract: In 1993, the US Government proposed a novel (and highly controversial) approach to cryptography, called key escrow. Key escrow cryptosystems used standard symmetric- and public- key ciphers, key management techniques and protocols, but with one added feature: a copy of the current session key, itself encrypted with a key known to the government, was sent at the beginning of every encrypted communication stream.</description></item><item><title>Revision to Encryption Items - Bureau of Export Administration</title><link>/entries/81/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/81/</guid><description>Authors: Bureau of Export Administration
Published: January 2000
Tags: 2000s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls</description></item><item><title>Senator Backs Off Backdoors</title><link>/entries/73/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/73/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: October 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/10/senator-backs-off-backdoors/
Tags: 2000s Backdoors Crypto Wars Crypto Wars II US Congress Abstract: A senator changes his mind after calling for a prohibition on data-scrambling products without backdoors for government surveillance. Now, he &amp;ldquo;has no intentions&amp;rdquo; of working on such an encryption bill. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>Standards Setting and Federal Information Policy: The Escrowed Encryption Standard (EES)</title><link>/entries/70/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/70/</guid><description>Authors: Gegner, Karen E. and Veeder, Stacy B.
Published: January 1994
URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0740624X94900183
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Encryption Standards Abstract: The controversial Escrowed Encryption Standard, recently adopted as a Federal Information Processing Standard (FIPS), has polarized some stakeholders both within and outside government and has also raised disturbing questions about the role of Federal agencies in the standards-setting process. This article explores the relationship between standards and Federal information policy and examines the balance between national security and law enforcement concerns, on the one hand, and privacy rights and U.</description></item><item><title>Symposium: Recent Development: Key Escrow Encryption Policies and Technoligies</title><link>/entries/69/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/69/</guid><description>Authors: Dorothy E. Denning, Jr., William E. Baugh
Published: 1996
URL: https://advance-lexis-com.colorado.idm.oclc.org/document/teaserdocument/?pdmfid=1516831&amp;amp;crid=8b6ba342-19bb-468d-ba50-25b58114a8ae&amp;amp;pddocfullpath=%2Fshared%2Fdocument%2Fanalytical-materials%2Furn%3AcontentItem%3A3S3V-6N10-00CT-V0F6-00000-00&amp;amp;pddocid=urn%3AcontentItem%3A3S3V-6N10-00CT-V0F6-00000-00&amp;amp;pdcontentcomponentid=139228&amp;amp;pdteaserkey=h1&amp;amp;pditab=allpods&amp;amp;ecomp=sp79k&amp;amp;earg=sr0&amp;amp;prid=045f1ac9-dc07-4c8a-abad-d37187cd5523
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Government Policy Key Escrow</description></item><item><title>Techies Urge Senator To Drop Encryption Key Plan</title><link>/entries/157/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/157/</guid><description>Authors: Brian Krebs
Published: October 2001
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20011011022244/http://www.newsbytes.com/news/01/170592.html
Tags: 2000s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars II</description></item><item><title>Testimony on Encryption as Constitutionally Protected Speech</title><link>/entries/68/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/68/</guid><description>Authors: Cindy A. Cohn
Published: September 1999
URL: http://www.techlawjournal.com/cong106/encrypt/19990916dal.htm
Tags: 1990s Clinton Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Government Policy White House</description></item><item><title>The Metaphor is the Key: Cryptography, The Clipper Chip, and the Constitution</title><link>/entries/65/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/65/</guid><description>Authors: A. Michael Froomkin
Published: 1996
URL: http://osaka.law.miami.edu/~froomkin/articles/clipper.htm
Tags: 1990s Clipper Chip Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Key Escrow</description></item><item><title>The Risks of Key Recovery, Key Escrow, and Trusted Third-Party Encryption</title><link>/entries/63/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/63/</guid><description>Authors: H. Abelson, R. Anderson, S. M. Bellovin, J. Benaloh, M. Blaze, W. Diffie, J. Gilmore, P. G. Neumann, R. L. Rivest, J. I. Schiller, B. Schneier
Published: 1998
URL: https://www.schneier.com/academic/archives/1997/04/the_risks_of_key_rec.html
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Key Escrow Key Recovery Abstract: A variety of &amp;ldquo;key recovery,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;key escrow,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;trusted third-party&amp;rdquo; encryption requirements have been suggested in recent years by government agencies seeking to conduct covert surveillance within the changing environments brought about by new technologies.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Supercomputer Export Control Policy</title><link>/entries/50/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/50/</guid><description>Authors: House of Representatives, Committee on National Security, Chairman, Hon. Floyd D. Spence
Published: November 1997
URL: http://commdocs.house.gov/committees/security/has317000.000/has317000_1.HTM
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls Hearing National Security</description></item><item><title>White House Clipper Statement (4/16/93)</title><link>/entries/53/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/53/</guid><description>Authors: Office of the Press Secretary
Published: April 1993
URL: https://epic.org/crypto/clipper/white_house_statement_4_93.html
Tags: 1990s Clinton Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I White House</description></item><item><title>Wiretapping and Cryptography Today</title><link>/entries/179/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/179/</guid><description>Authors: Matt Blaze
Published: July 2011
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20110715210433/http://www.crypto.com/blog/wiretap2010
Tags: 2010s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Wiretap</description></item></channel></rss>