<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Content Detection on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/content-detection/</link><description>Recent content in Content Detection on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/content-detection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Content-Oblivious Trust and Safety Techniques: Results from a Survey of Online Service Providers</title><link>/entries/content-oblivious-trust-and-safety-techniques-resu-bd3a0a7e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/content-oblivious-trust-and-safety-techniques-resu-bd3a0a7e/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
URL: https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3920031
Abstract: Riana Pfefferkorn, research scholar at the Stanford Internet Observatory, describes a survey of online service providers regarding their online trust and safety techniques. She concludes that content-dependent techniques are not a “silver bullet against abuse” and that any marginal inhibiting effect of using end-to-end encryption will vary by abuse type. Instead, she encourages greater consideration of what she calls “content-oblivious” techniques in the ongoing policy debate regarding providers’ anti-abuse obligations and their use of end-to-end encryption.</description></item><item><title>Outside Looking In: Approaches to Content Moderation in End-to-End Encrypted Systems</title><link>/entries/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderatio-3fcad0c7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderatio-3fcad0c7/</guid><description>Authors: Kamara, Seny, Knodel, Mallory, Llansó, Emma, Nojeim, Greg, Qin, Lucy, Thakur, Dhanaraj, Vogus, Caitlin
Published: August 2021
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/outside-looking-in-approaches-to-content-moderation-in-end-to-end-encrypted-systems/
Abstract: A group of researchers at the Center for Technology and Democracy orient the ongoing content moderation/end-to-end-encryption debate within the history of the Crypto Wars and analyze the strength of central competing claims. Content detection, and the obstacle of end-to-end-encryption, is only the latest permutation in the ongoing dialogue between law enforcement investigative capabilities and competing values including privacy, freedom of expression, and secure ecommerce.</description></item><item><title>The Law and Policy of Client-Side Scanning</title><link>/entries/the-law-and-policy-of-client-side-scanning-7598c301/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-law-and-policy-of-client-side-scanning-7598c301/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenzweig, Paul
Published: August 2020
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/law-and-policy-client-side-scanning
Abstract: Paul Rosenzweig, former Deputy Assistant Secretary for Policy in the Department of Homeland Security, and founder of a homeland security consulting company, writes an analysis of client-side scanning published by the Lawfare Institute in cooperation with the Brookings Institute. He concludes that, while client-side scanning offers attractive protective capabilities to meet the rise of online-distributed child pornography via encrypted systems, its adoption at its current nascent stage would be nonetheless undesirable due to technological, legal, and policy uncertainties.</description></item></channel></rss>