<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>International on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/international/</link><description>Recent content in International on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/international/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 10/27/2016</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</guid><description>Published: October 2016
Abstract: On October 27, 2016, a coalition of domestic organizations and experts sent a letter to President Barack Obama in which they urged the White House to respond to a petition using the Administration&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;We the People&amp;rdquo; platform. The petition asked that the Administration &amp;ldquo;[p]ublicly affirm your support for strong encryption,” to “[r]eject any law, policy, or mandate that would undermine our security” online, and to &amp;ldquo;encourage other governments worldwide to do the same.</description></item><item><title>DOJ Plans to Strike Against Encryption While the Techlash Iron Is Hot</title><link>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2020
URL: /blog/2020/02/doj-plans-strike-against-encryption-while-techlash-iron-hot
Abstract: This blog post by Riana Pfefferkorn argues that since 2016, the Department of Justice sought to capitalize on public anti-technology sentiment to weaken encryption. First, the article describes the political climate, shaped by the Apple v FBI case, the role of big tech in various privacy scandals and foreign interference in the 2016 election, and foreign legislation, particularly in Australia and the U.</description></item><item><title>H.R. 4943 - Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act</title><link>/entries/h-r-4943-clarifying-lawful-overseas-use-of-data-ac-f1395da4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/h-r-4943-clarifying-lawful-overseas-use-of-data-ac-f1395da4/</guid><description>Authors: Collins, Doug
Published: February 2018
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/4943
Abstract: On February 6, 2018, Representatives Collins, Jeffries, Issa, DelBene, Marino, Rutherford and Demings introduced H.R. 4943, the “Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act” or the “CLOUD Act.” H.R. 4943 amends title 18 of the United States federal criminal code to “improve law enforcement access to data stored across borders, and for other purposes.” The bill requires electronic communication service (ECS) and remote computer service (RCS) providers to comply with existing preservation, backup and disclosure requirements pertaining to contents of electronic communications and any record or other information pertaining to a customer or subscriber within their possession, regardless of whether the information is located within the United States.</description></item><item><title>Promoting Public Saftey, Privacy, and the Rule of Law Around the World: The Purpose and Impact of the CLOUD Act</title><link>/entries/promoting-public-saftey-privacy-and-the-rule-of-la-062fe8ee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/promoting-public-saftey-privacy-and-the-rule-of-la-062fe8ee/</guid><description>Published: April 2019
Abstract: In April 2019, the Department of Justice published this White Paper on the purpose and impact of the CLOUD Act. The Paper explains the CLOUD Act was enacted to speed access to electronic information held by U.S.-based global providers (communications service providers, “CSPs”) that is critical to foreign partners’ investigations of serious crimes. Specifically, the CLOUD Act is designed to permit those “foreign partners that have robust protections for privacy and civil liberties to enter into executive agreements with the United States to obtain access” this electronic information and evidence.</description></item><item><title>Recommendation of the Council Concerning Guidelines for Cryptography Policy (adopted by the Council at its 895th session on 27 March 1997 [C/M(97)6/PROV])</title><link>/entries/recommendation-of-the-council-concerning-guideline-8821d5fd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/recommendation-of-the-council-concerning-guideline-8821d5fd/</guid><description>Published: May 1997
URL: https://one.oecd.org/document/C(97)62/FINAL/en/pdf</description></item><item><title>The Encryption Debate in the European Union</title><link>/entries/the-encryption-debate-in-the-european-union-6437b4a5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-encryption-debate-in-the-european-union-6437b4a5/</guid><description>Authors: Koomen, Maria and Koomen, Maria
Published: May 2019
URL: https://carnegieendowment.org/2019/05/30/encryption-debate-in-european-union-pub-79220
Abstract: The Encryption Debate in the European Union is a policy brief that describes the intensifying encryption debate in the European Union, the interests and actors involved, and a possible timeline and substance of potential legislation. While encryption had largely thrived in Europe since the 1990s, the occurrence of multiple terror attacks in the late 10’s sparked a debate about encryption and national security within the EU.</description></item><item><title>The Evolution of US Government Restrictions on Using and Exporting Encryption Technologies (U)</title><link>/entries/the-evolution-of-us-government-restrictions-on-usi-2a478a7b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-evolution-of-us-government-restrictions-on-usi-2a478a7b/</guid><description>Authors: Schwartzbeck, Michael
URL: https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/docs/DOC_0006231614.pdf
Abstract: This declassified report outlines the development of encryption technology by the United States government, and how private actors have challenged the government’s monopoly and changed the landscape of encryption. The report begins by detailing the creation of the NSA and the development of cryptography and provides a timeline through key escrow in the 1990s. The article ends by proposing potential paths for the future of cryptography and urging the Clinton Administration to seek an international resolution to require key escrow registration to allow governments a back door while preventing foreign technology as an alternative to complying with American requirements.</description></item><item><title>Travel Guide to the Digital World: Encryption Policy for Human Rights Defenders</title><link>/entries/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-encryption-polic-2d5134d2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-encryption-polic-2d5134d2/</guid><description>Authors: Global Partners Digital
Published: 2017
URL: https://www.gp-digital.org/publication/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-4-encryption-policy-for-human-rights-defenders/
Abstract: This is a guide, aimed at a non-technical audience, seeking to explain the connection between human rights and encryption. The article gives a background on the basics of encryption, and how it affects the day-to-day life of people around the globe, and its impacts on privacy and freedom of expression. Finally, the article outlines the legal and policy background of encryption regulation across the globe and at the international, national, and local levels.</description></item></channel></rss>