<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EFF on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/eff/</link><description>Recent content in EFF on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/eff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FAQ on the FCC CALEA Expansion</title><link>/entries/84/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/84/</guid><description>Published: 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/issues/calea
Abstract: The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994 Congress passed the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) in 1994, which forced telephone companies to redesign their network architectures to make it easier for law enforcement to wiretap digital telephone calls. In 2005, CALEA was expanded by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to include Internet service providers (ISPs) and VoIP services like Skype. A few years later, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) began pushing legislation trying to expand CALEA to all online communications software.</description></item><item><title>Security Win: Burr-Feinstein Proposal Declared “Dead” for This Year</title><link>/entries/16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/16/</guid><description>Published: May 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/05/win-one-security-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-year
Abstract: The anti-security proposal promoted by Senators Burr and Feinstein is “dead,” according to a Reuters report. The news agency spoke to sources within congressional offices, the administration, and the tech sector, who confirmed that the bill “likely will not be introduced this year and, even if it&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>The Burr-Feinstein Proposal Is Simply Anti-Security</title><link>/entries/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/7/</guid><description>Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/04/burr-feinstein-proposal-simply-anti-security
Abstract: Sens. Richard Burr and Dianne Feinstein recently released a draft bill forcing nearly all U.S. companies to decrypt any encrypted data they may handle. Specifically, it would place a new, sweepingly broad duty on device manufacturers, software developers, ISPs, online services and others to decrypt&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>The Human Rights Benefits of Encryption</title><link>/entries/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/6/</guid><description>Authors: Andi Wilson Thompson
Published: March 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption/</description></item><item><title>Worried about Apple? California Has a Bill That Would Disable Encryption on All Phones</title><link>/entries/0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/0/</guid><description>Authors: Andrew Crocker
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/03/worried-about-apple-california-has-bill-would-disable-encryption-all-phones
Abstract: Update (April 8, 2016): The encryption bill has been amended. The changes are discussed in a new post. Smartphone users in California take notice: a new CA State Assembly bill would ban default encryption features on all smartphones. Assembly Bill 1681, introduced in January by Assemblymember Jim&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>