<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EFF on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/eff/</link><description>Recent content in EFF on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/eff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anonymity and Encryption: Comments Submitted to the United Nations Special Rapporteur on the Promotion and Protection of the Right to Freedom of Opinion and Expression</title><link>/entries/anonymity-and-encryption-comments-submitted-to-the-679d1ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/anonymity-and-encryption-comments-submitted-to-the-679d1ec2/</guid><description>Authors: Rodriguez, Katitza
Published: February 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/files/2015/02/10/unanonymity-encryption-eff.pdf
Abstract: The Electron Frontier Foundation’s comments regarding Anonymity and Encryption describe and argue for the benefit of anonymity and encryption. The comments describe what anonymity and digital anonymity are, their relevance to human rights, and policies around the world which either undermine or support the right to anonymity from both private and government actors. Finally, the comments describe encryption and its defend individuals right to encryption.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 10/27/2016</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</guid><description>Published: October 2016
Abstract: On October 27, 2016, a coalition of domestic organizations and experts sent a letter to President Barack Obama in which they urged the White House to respond to a petition using the Administration&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;We the People&amp;rdquo; platform. The petition asked that the Administration &amp;ldquo;[p]ublicly affirm your support for strong encryption,” to “[r]eject any law, policy, or mandate that would undermine our security” online, and to &amp;ldquo;encourage other governments worldwide to do the same.</description></item><item><title>Cracking DES: Secrets of Encryption Research, Wiretap Politics \&amp; Chip Design. How Federal Agencies Subvert Privacy</title><link>/entries/cracking-des-secrets-of-encryption-research-wireta-a4fb65fa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/cracking-des-secrets-of-encryption-research-wireta-a4fb65fa/</guid><description>Authors: Electronic Frontier Foundation
Published: 1998
URL: http://archive.org/details/crackingdessecre00elec
Abstract: In 1998, the Electronic Frontier Foundation, an international non-profit digital rights group dedicated to the promotion of internet civil liberties, published a book detailing the Foundation’s $210,000 research project to build a machine to crack Data Encryption Standard (DES) – a DES Cracker. The book features an overview of the basic architecture of the machine; design and hardware specifications; and technical design specifications, such as the software source code, chip source code, chip simulator source code, and hardware board schematics, which enable any cryptographer to replicate their work.</description></item></channel></rss>