<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NIST on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/nist/</link><description>Recent content in NIST on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/nist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Announcing the Advanced Encryption Standard (AES)</title><link>/entries/103/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/103/</guid><description>Authors: NIST
Published: November 2001
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20030406010431/http://www.csrc.nist.gov/publications/fips/fips197/fips-197.pdf</description></item><item><title>Report on Post-Quantum Cryptography</title><link>/entries/28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/28/</guid><description>Authors: Lily Chen, Stephen Jordan, Yi-Kai Liu, Dustin Moody, Rene Peralta, Ray Perlner, Daniel Smith-Tone
Published: April 2016
URL: https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2016/NIST.IR.8105.pdf
Abstract: In recent years, there has been a substantial amount of research on quantum computers –machines that exploit quantum mechanical phenomena to solve mathematical problems that are difficult or intractable for conventional computers. If large-scale quantum computers are ever built, they will be able to break many of the public-key cryptosystems currently in use.</description></item><item><title>Status report on the first round of the NIST post-quantum cryptography standardization process</title><link>/entries/17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/17/</guid><description>Authors: NIST and Alagic, Gorjan and Alperin-Sheriff, Jacob and Apon, Daniel and Cooper, David and Dang, Quynh and Liu, Yi-Kai and Miller, Carl and Moody, Dustin and Peralta, Rene and Perlner, Ray and Robinson, Angela and Smith-Tone, Daniel
Published: January 2019
URL: https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2019/NIST.IR.8240.pdf
Abstract: The National Institute of Standards and Technology is in the process of selecting one or more public-key cryptographic algorithms through a public competition-like process. The new publickey cryptography standards will specify one or more additional digital signature, public-key encryption, and key-establishment algorithms to augment FIPS 186-4, Digital Signature Standard (DSS), as well as special publications SP 800-56A Revision 2, Recommendation for Pair-Wise Key Establishment Schemes Using Discrete Logarithm Cryptography, and SP 800-56B, Recommendation for Pair-Wise Key-Establishment Schemes Using Integer Factorization.</description></item></channel></rss>