<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Backdoors on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/backdoors/</link><description>Recent content in Backdoors on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/backdoors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apple Will No Longer Unlock Most iPhones, iPads for Police, Even with Search Warrants</title><link>/entries/apple-will-no-longer-unlock-most-iphones-ipads-for-d5b21880/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/apple-will-no-longer-unlock-most-iphones-ipads-for-d5b21880/</guid><description>Authors: Craig Timberg
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/2014/09/17/2612af58-3ed2-11e4-b03f-de718edeb92f_story.html
Abstract: In late 2014, in response to allegations of over-participation in government efforts to collect user information, Apple announced a plan to cease turning over user data to police, even when they have a search a warrant. The move, which was classified as an “engineering solution to a legal quandary,” came in the form of an update to the Apple’s mobile operating system privacy policy and relied primarily upon the encryption automatically placed on Apple mobile devices, via the selection of an access passcode.</description></item><item><title>Beyond Secrets: The Consumer Stake in the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/beyond-secrets-the-consumer-stake-in-the-encryptio-5a9a086a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/beyond-secrets-the-consumer-stake-in-the-encryptio-5a9a086a/</guid><description>Published: December 2017
URL: https://advocacy.consumerreports.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Beyond-Secrets-12.21.17-FINAL.pdf
Abstract: On December 21, 2017, ConsumersUnion and Upturn released this paper on consumers’ stake in the encryption debate. The paper begins with information on cryptography: what it is and how it works. It then discusses the ways in which encryption benefits consumers, including: protecting their health information, safeguarding their financial well-being, facilitating sale software updates, ensuring physical safety, and allowing consumers to communicate with confidence. The purpose of this paper is to educate consumers about the many ways that encryption benefits consumers and the systems and infrastructure consumers rely upon, and the potential costs if encryption were to be compromised.</description></item><item><title>Brief of Amici Curiae Access Now and Wickr Foundation in Support of Apple Inc.'s Motion to Vacate</title><link>/entries/brief-of-amici-curiae-access-now-and-wickr-foundat-c51e7fcb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/brief-of-amici-curiae-access-now-and-wickr-foundat-c51e7fcb/</guid><description>Authors: Wickr Foundation
Abstract: This amicus brief was filed by Access Now and the Wickr Foundation in support of Apple in the Central District of California, asserting that allowing the government to install software to weaken encryption would have far-reaching effects beyond the singular iPhone at hand. The FBI petitioned the court to require Apple to create and install &amp;ldquo;GovtOS&amp;rdquo; which would allow the FBI to work around security features and potentially access encrypted information.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to NIST</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-nist-7f0953e7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-nist-7f0953e7/</guid><description>Authors: Stepanovich, Amie
Published: November 2014
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/archive/Coalition-NIST-Nov2014.pdf
Abstract: In November of 2014, a coalition of companies and civil society organizations wrote to the National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST), President Barack Obama, and Secretary of Commerce, Penny Pritzker to “re-emphasize the importance of creating a process for establishing secure and resilient encryption standards, free from back doors.” The letter was intended to influence the final version of the NIST’s Cryptographic Standards and Guidelines Development Process, through a series of policy recommendations.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 04/11/2016</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-04-11-2016-4b5abd91/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-04-11-2016-4b5abd91/</guid><description>Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2016/04/Encryption-Letter.pdf
Abstract: On April 11, 2016, a coalition of domestic and international organizations and experts sent a letter to President Barack Obama in which they urged the White House to “specifically oppose legislation to undermine security and reiterate the need for a broad statement of support for encryption from the administration”. The letter was sent in response to a draft bill titled “Compliance with Court Order Act of 2016”, which would compel all internet companies and “any person who provides a product or method to facilitate a communication or the processing or storage of data,” to “either undermine the security features they offer users or offer lesser security so as to facilitate government access.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 10/27/2016</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</guid><description>Published: October 2016
Abstract: On October 27, 2016, a coalition of domestic organizations and experts sent a letter to President Barack Obama in which they urged the White House to respond to a petition using the Administration&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;We the People&amp;rdquo; platform. The petition asked that the Administration &amp;ldquo;[p]ublicly affirm your support for strong encryption,” to “[r]eject any law, policy, or mandate that would undermine our security” online, and to &amp;ldquo;encourage other governments worldwide to do the same.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 5/19/2015</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-5-19-2015-ad5d54f2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-5-19-2015-ad5d54f2/</guid><description>Published: May 2015
URL: https://static.newamerica.org/attachments/3138&amp;ndash;113/Encryption_Letter_to_Obama_final_051915.pdf
Abstract: We urge you to reject any proposal that U.S. companies deliberately weaken the security of their products. We request that the White House instead focus on developing policies that will promote rather than undermine the wide adoption of strong encryption technology. Such policies will in turn help to promote and protect cybersecurity, economic growth, and human rights, both here and abroad.</description></item><item><title>Dutch Government Backs Uncrackable Encryption</title><link>/entries/dutch-government-backs-uncrackable-encryption-8169af3a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/dutch-government-backs-uncrackable-encryption-8169af3a/</guid><description>Authors: Robert Hackett
Published: January 2016
URL: https://fortune.com/2016/01/05/dutch-government-encryption-no-backdoors/
Abstract: On January 5, 2016, Fortune published an article about the Dutch government’s decision to not request a backdoor to encryption data and communications. The article noted that the government acknowledged both sides of the backdoor debate, and determined that “it is not desirable at this time to take restrictive regulatory measures with respect to the development, availability, and use of encryption within the Netherlands.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Backdoors Decrease Trust In The Internet</title><link>/entries/encryption-backdoors-decrease-trust-in-the-interne-0da4e63b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-backdoors-decrease-trust-in-the-interne-0da4e63b/</guid><description>Authors: Kolkman, Olaf
Published: May 2015
URL: https://www.internetsociety.org/blog/2015/05/encryption-backdoors-decrease-trust-in-the-internet/
Abstract: In May of 2015, Olaf Kolkman, the Principal of Internet Technology, Policy, and Advocacy at the Internet Society, wrote to express his support for a letter sent to President Barack Obama, by a collection of civil society organizations, corporations, trade associations, and security and policy experts. The letter expressed concern regarding a suggestion by Administration officials that companies should refrain from providing products with strong encryption unless they simultaneously weakened their security “in order to maintain the capability to decrypt their customer’s data at the government’s request.</description></item><item><title>Encryption in the U.S.: Crypto Colloquium Outcomes Report</title><link>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</guid><description>Published: January 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/02/Encryption-in-the-United-States-Crypto-Colloquium-Outcomes-Report.pdf
Abstract: In September of 2017, Access Now, a non-profit dedicated to human rights advocacy in the digital age, hosted the Crypto Colloquium—an invite-only dialogue of civil society, academic experts, technology companies and former U.S. government officials—to discuss challenges associated with U.S. government agencies’ inability to access information on encrypted mobile phones. The Report, produced by Access Now, provides a summary of the key takeaways from the Colloquium, including a section on the “Lessons Learned” in each of the Law and Policy, Security, and Economics sectors.</description></item><item><title>Encryption, Biometrics, and the Status Quo Ante</title><link>/entries/encryption-biometrics-and-the-status-quo-ante-6819368c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-biometrics-and-the-status-quo-ante-6819368c/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenzweig, Paul
Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/encryption-biometrics-and-status-quo-ante
Abstract: On July 6, 2015, Paul Rosenzweig, founder of Red Branch Consulting PLLC, wrote about a paradigm shift in the encryption debate, and offered a solution to deal with the paradigm shift. In 1995, data “could not be maintained in an undecryptable format”, access to data was “achieved through lawful process (either a search warrant or a subpoena)”, and the subject of an investigation received notice.</description></item><item><title>Ex-NSA Chief Thinks the Government is Dead Wrong in Asking Apple for a Backdoor</title><link>/entries/ex-nsa-chief-thinks-the-government-is-dead-wrong-i-8b5c5590/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ex-nsa-chief-thinks-the-government-is-dead-wrong-i-8b5c5590/</guid><description>Authors: Business Insider
Published: February 2016
URL: https://www.businessinsider.com/michael-hayden-encryption-apple-2016-2
Abstract: On February 25, 2016, Business Insider published an article regarding comments made by a former NSA Chief, General Michael Hayden, in which he expressed his rejection of the notion that tech companies should implement a backdoor to encryption on behalf of law enforcement. While he noted that a lack of a backdoor for encryption imposes “an unfair cost”, he said “we are not required to organize our entire national life around the needs of American law enforcement.</description></item><item><title>FBI Blasts Apple, Google for Locking Police out of Phones</title><link>/entries/fbi-blasts-apple-google-for-locking-police-out-of-79e02027/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/fbi-blasts-apple-google-for-locking-police-out-of-79e02027/</guid><description>Authors: Craig Timberg, Greg Miller
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/2014/09/25/68c4e08e-4344-11e4-9a15-137aa0153527_story.html
Abstract: On September 26, 2014, The Washington Post published an article which discussed the FBI’s criticism of Apple and Google for “for developing forms of smartphone encryption so secure that law enforcement officials cannot easily gain access to information stored on the devices &amp;ndash; even when they have valid search warrants.” The article notes that “while the legal and technical changes are fueled by anger over reports of mass surveillance by the National Security Agency, the consequences are being felt most heavily by police detectives, often armed with warrants certifying that a judge has found probable cause that a search of a smartphone will reveal evidence of a crime.</description></item><item><title>FBI Pressuring Google, Facebook to Allow ‘Back Doors’ for Wiretapping</title><link>/entries/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-to-allow-back-doors-71473338/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-to-allow-back-doors-71473338/</guid><description>Authors: Daniel Tencer
Published: November 2010
URL: https://www.rawstory.com/2010/11/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-wiretapping/
Abstract: On November 17, 2010, Raw Story published an article discussing the debate surrounding a proposed expansion of The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994. At the time, FBI Director Robert Mueller placed pressure on technology companies to build “back doors” which would “allow law enforcement to wiretap data on their networks”, in an effort “to expand the FBI’s wiretapping powers to include the latest communications technologies, including social networking sites, voice-over-Internet (VoIP) telephone services and BlackBerries.</description></item><item><title>Feds Put Heat on Web Firms for Master Encryption Keys</title><link>/entries/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-k-c6363e83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-k-c6363e83/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: July 2013
URL: https://www.cnet.com/news/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-keys/
Abstract: In July of 2013, Declan McCullagh, a senior writer for CNET, wrote regarding the continued effort of major U.S. intelligence agencies (the FBI and NSA) to obtain master encryption (SSL) keys used by internet service providers to shield private communications. McCullagh referred to the efforts of the U.S. government as a “technological escalation in the clandestine methods that the FBI and National Security Agency employ when conducting electronic surveillance against Internet users,” and warned of the sheer scope of the information which could be intercepted if such a key were turned over.</description></item><item><title>From Clipper Chip to Smartphones: Unlocking the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-enc-cbe23268/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-enc-cbe23268/</guid><description>Authors: Flatow, Ira
URL: https://www.sciencefriday.com/segments/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-encryption-debate/
Abstract: This Podcast features comments made by security experts and privacy advocates made in the 1990s about the Clipper Chip. It offers a look back into what the policy discussion looked like concurrently with the Clipper Chip proposals. Some of those who previously made comments offer follow-up, looking back at the development of their views and policy positions and how they have developed in the intervening years.</description></item><item><title>Holder Urges Tech Companies to Leave Device Backdoors Open for Police</title><link>/entries/holder-urges-tech-companies-to-leave-device-backdo-1737189d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/holder-urges-tech-companies-to-leave-device-backdo-1737189d/</guid><description>Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2014/09/30/holder-urges-tech-companies-to-leave-device-backdoors-open-for-police/
Abstract: This news article from 2014 features comments from Attorney General Eric Holder urging technology companies to insert back doors into their products because encryption could potentially imperial investigations into kidnapping and sexual predation of children. Holder stated that companies could design technology in such a way that would not burden privacy. This article outlines statements from a top law enforcement official, linking encryption to crimes against children.</description></item><item><title>Issue Brief: A “Backdoor” to Encryption for Government Surveillance</title><link>/entries/issue-brief-a-backdoor-to-encryption-for-governmen-feec9f35/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/issue-brief-a-backdoor-to-encryption-for-governmen-feec9f35/</guid><description>Authors: Hall, Joseph Lorenzo
Published: March 2016
URL: https://cdt.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Issue-brief-A-backdoor-to-encryption-for-government-surveillance-CDT-03032012.pdf
Abstract: On March 3, 2016, the Center for Democracy and Technology published an article about whether or not there should be an encryption “backdoor” for government surveillance. The article discussed the decision by Apple and Google to make their smartphones “encrypted by default”, the desire of the FBI that all encrypted communications services have a “backdoor”, the major problems created by backdoors, including the undermining of user security and harm to United States businesses, rejects the claim that “companies’ increasing adoption of strong encryption by default will suddenly lead to government ‘going dark’ and unable to access critical information”, and factors relevant to whether or not compelled decryption is legal.</description></item><item><title>James Comey, F.B.I. Director, Hints at Action as Cellphone Data Is Locked</title><link>/entries/james-comey-f-b-i-director-hints-at-action-as-cell-f7538b3a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/james-comey-f-b-i-director-hints-at-action-as-cell-f7538b3a/</guid><description>Authors: David E. Sanger, Matt Apuzzo
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2014/10/17/us/politics/fbi-director-in-policy-speech-calls-dark-devices-hindrance-to-crime-solving.html
Abstract: On October 16, 2014, David E. Sanger and Matt Apuzzo wrote for the New York Times regarding F.B.I. Director James Comey’s comments on the potential the Obama administration would seek regulations and laws forcing companies to create an encryption backdoor to unlock photos, emails and contacts stored on cellular devices. The comments came shortly following the decisions of Apple and Google to automatically encrypt the contents of their cellphones—a first among widely used consumer devices—which Comey claimed would hinder intelligence gathering.</description></item><item><title>Keys Under Doormats: Mandating Insecurity by Requiring Government Access to All Data and Communications</title><link>/entries/keys-under-doormats-mandating-insecurity-by-requir-5df4f072/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/keys-under-doormats-mandating-insecurity-by-requir-5df4f072/</guid><description>Authors: Abelson, Harold and Anderson, Ross and Bellovin, Steven M and Benaloh, Josh and Blaze, Matt and Diffie, Whitﬁeld and Gilmore, John and Green, Matthew and Landau, Susan and Neumann, Peter G and Rivest, Ronald L and Schiller, Jeﬀrey I and Schneier, Bruce and Specter, Michael and Weitzner, Daniel J
Published: July 2015
Abstract: On July 7, 2015, a group of computer scientists and security experts published a study to ascertain the likely effects of renewed attempts to mandate back doors of all data for law enforcement.</description></item><item><title>Old Technopanic in New iBottles</title><link>/entries/old-technopanic-in-new-ibottles-50857d54/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/old-technopanic-in-new-ibottles-50857d54/</guid><description>Authors: Julian Sanchez
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.cato.org/blog/old-technopanic-new-ibottles
Abstract: If we aim to preserve an “equilibrium” between government power and citizen privacy, we should accept that it will occasionally close one as well.</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad Idea</title><link>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</guid><description>Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Abstract: In April 2015, OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston was schedule to testify before the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform’s Subcommittee on Information Technology regarding backdoor mandates and potential U.S. policy responses. New America published this blog post, on April 28, 2015, summarizing Bankston’s prepared statement and highlighting the ten key reasons Bankston identified against backdoor mandates. The reasons identified by Bankston were: 1) surveillance backdoors were already rejected as a policy approach two decades ago, including by Congress; 2) it would seriously undermine U.</description></item><item><title>S. 266 - Comprehensive Counter-Terrorism Act of 1991</title><link>/entries/s-266-comprehensive-counter-terrorism-act-of-1991-780b290c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-266-comprehensive-counter-terrorism-act-of-1991-780b290c/</guid><description>Authors: Biden, Joseph
Published: January 1991
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/102nd-congress/senate-bill/266/text
Abstract: Text for S.266 - 102nd Congress (1991-1992): Comprehensive Counter-Terrorism Act of 1991</description></item><item><title>Security “Front Doors” vs. “Back Doors”: A Distinction Without a Difference</title><link>/entries/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-a-distinction-w-27fb709b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-a-distinction-w-27fb709b/</guid><description>Authors: Jeffrey Vagle, Matt Blaze
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.justsecurity.org/16503/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-distinction-difference/
Abstract: This article by Jeffrey Vagle and Matt Blaze discusses FBI Director James Comey’s speeches calling for back doors in encryption for law enforcement and argues that it is technologically infeasible and politically wise. The article details how back doors will eventually be uncovered and lead to vulnerabilities in systems. Finally, the article argues that the language being used to advocate for back doors builds a false sense of security in populations unfamiliar with the technological realities and leads people away from more workable solutions.</description></item><item><title>Senator Backs Off Backdoors</title><link>/entries/senator-backs-off-backdoors-b6e3901e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/senator-backs-off-backdoors-b6e3901e/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: October 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/10/senator-backs-off-backdoors/
Abstract: A senator changes his mind after calling for a prohibition on data-scrambling products without backdoors for government surveillance. Now, he &amp;ldquo;has no intentions&amp;rdquo; of working on such an encryption bill. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>The NSA’s Split-Key Encryption Proposal is Not Serious</title><link>/entries/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-seri-126e61d2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-seri-126e61d2/</guid><description>Authors: Joseph Lorenzo Hall
Published: April 2015
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-serious/
Abstract: The NSA&amp;rsquo;s Split-Key Encryption Proposal is Not Serious discusses the NSA&amp;rsquo;s 2020 proposal to require technology companies to create a &amp;ldquo;golden key,&amp;rdquo; a split-key that would allow the company or the NSA access to encrypted communications. Hall argues that split-key encryption is a technology infeasible, vulnerable, and costly, and would not be able to ensure any data was protected from the NSA.</description></item><item><title>We Need More Protection from Government Surveillance — Not Less</title><link>/entries/we-need-more-protection-from-government-surveillan-33e5e137/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/we-need-more-protection-from-government-surveillan-33e5e137/</guid><description>Authors: McGowan, Iverna, Naranjo, Diego, Koomen, Maria, Beltrà, Guillermo, Preiss, Omri, Massé, Estelle, Cohn, Cindy, Stollmeyer, Alice, Bukovská, Barbora, Dusepulchre, Gaelle, Anderson, Andrew, Skoric, Vanja, Westby, Joe, Keller, Paul
Published: July 2021
URL: https://www.politico.eu/article/we-need-more-protection-government-surveillance-not-less/
Abstract: A group of user- and human-rights advocates jointly write an article published by Politico in response to Catherine de Bolle and Cyrus R. Vance, Jr.s, &amp;ldquo;The Last Refuge of the Criminal: Encypted Smartphones.&amp;rdquo; They describe the importance of encryption to democracy and human rights in the face of increasing pressure by government for tech-company-assisted surveillance, citing multiple groups that depend upon encryption for privacy and physical safety: from investigative journalists to subjects of authoritarian governments to members of the LGBTQ+ community.</description></item><item><title>Why An Encryption Backdoor for Just the "Good Guys" Won't Work</title><link>/entries/why-an-encryption-backdoor-for-just-the-good-guys-918a9e9d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/why-an-encryption-backdoor-for-just-the-good-guys-918a9e9d/</guid><description>Authors: Stepanovich, Amie and Karanicolas, Michael
Published: March 2018
URL: https://www.justsecurity.org/53316/criminalize-security-criminals-secure/
Abstract: Recently, U.S. law enforcement officials have re-energized their push for a technical means to bypass encryption. But seeking to undermine encryption only looks backward instead of focusing on where technology is going. We should be having conversations about new investigative techniques, not trying to preserve the access enjoyed in the days before encryption was so widespread, particularly when so much is at stake in doing so.</description></item></channel></rss>