<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Healthcare on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/healthcare/</link><description>Recent content in Healthcare on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/healthcare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beyond Secrets: The Consumer Stake in the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/beyond-secrets-the-consumer-stake-in-the-encryptio-5a9a086a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/beyond-secrets-the-consumer-stake-in-the-encryptio-5a9a086a/</guid><description>Published: December 2017
URL: https://advocacy.consumerreports.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Beyond-Secrets-12.21.17-FINAL.pdf
Abstract: On December 21, 2017, ConsumersUnion and Upturn released this paper on consumers’ stake in the encryption debate. The paper begins with information on cryptography: what it is and how it works. It then discusses the ways in which encryption benefits consumers, including: protecting their health information, safeguarding their financial well-being, facilitating sale software updates, ensuring physical safety, and allowing consumers to communicate with confidence. The purpose of this paper is to educate consumers about the many ways that encryption benefits consumers and the systems and infrastructure consumers rely upon, and the potential costs if encryption were to be compromised.</description></item><item><title>How Unvalidated Encryption Threatens Patient Data Security</title><link>/entries/how-unvalidated-encryption-threatens-patient-data-f2fafa62/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/how-unvalidated-encryption-threatens-patient-data-f2fafa62/</guid><description>Authors: HealthITSecurity
Published: July 2016
URL: https://healthitsecurity.com/news/how-unvalidated-encryption-threatens-patient-data-security
Abstract: This article argues that failures by regulators to enforce precise encryption rules in data breaches by healthcare providers endanger allow substandard encryption to continue operating, endangering patient data. The article discusses the HIPAA, and subsequently elucidating NIST standards for encryption for healthcare patient data. However, because of leniency enforcement, vendors continue providing inadequate encryption without fear of consequences. The article argues that consistent enforcement of the NIST standards will ensure more secure data protection for healthcare patients.</description></item><item><title>S.1842 - Protecting Personal Health Data Act</title><link>/entries/s-1842-protecting-personal-health-data-act-8bffdbe7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-1842-protecting-personal-health-data-act-8bffdbe7/</guid><description>Authors: Klobuchar, Amy and Murkowski, Lisa
Published: June 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/1842/text
Abstract: To protect the personal health data of all Americans.</description></item></channel></rss>