<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2000s on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/2000s/</link><description>Recent content in 2000s on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/2000s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Clinton Administration Announces New Cybersecurity Proposals</title><link>/entries/clinton-administration-announces-new-cybersecurity-6826eb57/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/clinton-administration-announces-new-cybersecurity-6826eb57/</guid><description>Authors: Libbie Schlatheri
Published: July 2000
Abstract: On July 17, 2000, Libbie Schlatheir, a producer for CNN, issued a report detailing announcements by Clinton Administration officials regarding updates to its policy for encryption exports to the European Union and key trading partners. The updates, attributed largely to a speech by Clinton White House Chief of Staff, John Podesta, at the National Press Club, “liberalize[d] export controls on encryption, allowing more companies to export the technology to more end users… while maintaining a framework necessary to protect [U.</description></item><item><title>Congress Mulls Stiff Crypto Laws</title><link>/entries/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws-50dadb61/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws-50dadb61/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/09/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws/
Abstract: On September 13, 2001, Wired published an article about the impact of 9/11 terrorist attacks on the encryption debate, and declared that “[t]he encryption wars have begun”. The article claims that the balance of the debate between privacy and security “abruptly shifted” in the wake of 9/11, and that “political winds have shifted from business to national security”. The article discusses various Clinton Administration initiatives related to encryption, and highlighted quotes from Congress members who “called for a global prohibition on encryption products without backdoors for government surveillance”.</description></item><item><title>Cryptography and Liberty 2000: An International Survey of Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/cryptography-and-liberty-2000-an-international-sur-3c4921c1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/cryptography-and-liberty-2000-an-international-sur-3c4921c1/</guid><description>Authors: Banisar, David and Madsen, Wayne
Published: 2000
URL: https://epic.org/reports/crypto2000.html/
Abstract: Cryptography and Liberty is a survey by EPIC, a non-profit organization, on governmental encryption and cryptography laws around the world and the impacts of human rights. The survey focused on laws on domestic use of cryptography, disclosure requirements for encryption keys, import and export controls, and which government agencies or entities regulate cryptography and encryption.</description></item><item><title>Disputes on Electronic Message Encryption Take on New Urgency</title><link>/entries/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-6dfb72b1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-6dfb72b1/</guid><description>Authors: Schwartz, John
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2001/09/25/business/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-new-urgency.html
Abstract: This article, Disputes on Electronic Message Encryption Take on New Urgency, written by John Schwartz and published in the New York Times shortly after 9/11, describes how the attack on the World Trade Center, and the possibility that the attackers used encrypted communications in the planning and execution of the attack, renewed debate on law enforcement access to encrypted technologies. The article describes the applicability of key escrow and the Clipper Chip to accessing encrypted communications, and legislative proposals for access proposed in the days after 9/11.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Restrictions</title><link>/entries/encryption-restrictions-54a58dd3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-restrictions-54a58dd3/</guid><description>Authors: Messmer, Ellen
Published: March 2004
URL: https://www.networkworld.com/article/2331257/encryption-restrictions.html
Abstract: In March of 2004, Ellen Messmer, Senior Editor of Network World, wrote regarding global systems of encryption restrictions on imports, exports and use, and the implications for network managers operating globally. Messmer specifically highlighted the mandatory key-sharing program in China, which requires companies to appoint an “encryption contact” to provide all keys to the Chinese government upon request, as an example of foreign encryption policy functioning to disincentive encryption use by foreign corporations operating within a given country.</description></item><item><title>FAQ on the FCC CALEA Expansion</title><link>/entries/faq-on-the-fcc-calea-expansion-cb61ed55/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/faq-on-the-fcc-calea-expansion-cb61ed55/</guid><description>Published: 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/issues/calea
Abstract: In 2014 the Electronic Frontier Foundation published an article on the evolving history of the The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994. Initially, CALEA “forced telephone companies to redesign their network architectures to make it easier for law enforcement to wiretap digital telephone calls.” In 2004, several law enforcement agencies petitioned the FCC to expand the scope of CALEA to all Internet communications services, and the FCC issued a final rule which expanded CALEA “to broadband Internet access providers and managed VoIP systems.</description></item><item><title>Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) 197: Advanced Encryption Standard</title><link>/entries/federal-information-processing-standards-fips-197-d91011f8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/federal-information-processing-standards-fips-197-d91011f8/</guid><description>Authors: NIST
Published: November 2001
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20030406010431/http://www.csrc.nist.gov/publications/fips/fips197/fips-197.pdf
Abstract: The Advanced Encryption Standard (AES), officially published on November 26, 2001, provides a Computer Security Standard (Cryptography), for use by Federal departments and agencies when an agency determines that sensitive (unclassified) information requires cryptographic protection. The standard may also be used and adopted by non-Federal Government organizations. The AES specifies Federal Information Process Standards’ (FIPS’) approved cryptographic algorithm that can be used to protect electronic data.</description></item><item><title>Lawful Access – Consultation Document</title><link>/entries/lawful-access-consultation-document-a8b104aa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/lawful-access-consultation-document-a8b104aa/</guid><description>Published: August 2002
URL: https://www.justice.gc.ca/eng/cons/la-al/consult.html
Abstract: On August 25, 2002, the Canadian Department of Justice published a consultation document on Lawful Access, an “important and well-established technique used by law enforcement and national security agencies to conduct investigations” involving the interception of communications and search and seizure of information pursuant to legislative and criminal code authorizations. The Department of Justice described tool as essential in the “prevention, investigation and prosecution of serious offences and the investigation of threats to the security of Canada.</description></item><item><title>Request for Comments: Revisions to Encryption Items</title><link>/entries/request-for-comments-revisions-to-encryption-items-0c68d1bf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/request-for-comments-revisions-to-encryption-items-0c68d1bf/</guid><description>Authors: Lewis, James A.
Published: January 2000</description></item><item><title>Secrets or Shields to Share? New Dilemmas for Dual Use Technology Development and the Quest for military and Commercial Advantage in the Digital Age</title><link>/entries/secrets-or-shields-to-share-new-dilemmas-for-dual-34d6ebbe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/secrets-or-shields-to-share-new-dilemmas-for-dual-34d6ebbe/</guid><description>Authors: Stowsky, Jay
Published: February 2003</description></item><item><title>Senator Backs Off Backdoors</title><link>/entries/senator-backs-off-backdoors-b6e3901e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/senator-backs-off-backdoors-b6e3901e/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: October 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/10/senator-backs-off-backdoors/
Abstract: A senator changes his mind after calling for a prohibition on data-scrambling products without backdoors for government surveillance. Now, he &amp;ldquo;has no intentions&amp;rdquo; of working on such an encryption bill. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>Techies Urge Senator To Drop Encryption Key Plan</title><link>/entries/techies-urge-senator-to-drop-encryption-key-plan-7c42e2b5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/techies-urge-senator-to-drop-encryption-key-plan-7c42e2b5/</guid><description>Authors: Brian Krebs
Published: October 2001
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20011011022244/http://www.newsbytes.com/news/01/170592.html
Abstract: This article details a letter sent by privacy advocates to Senator Judd Gregg in response to a speech he made days after September 11, condemning encryption. Senator Gregg called for quasi-judicial rulemaking requiring backdoors, stating that it was likely that the 9/11 attackers likely used encryption in emails to plan the attack. Meanwhile, advocates stressed the impracticality of requiring a back door, as well as the risk of holding all passwords in one central location, in case that is hacked.</description></item><item><title>Timeline: The U.S. Government and Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/timeline-the-u-s-government-and-cybersecurity-5f7be48e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/timeline-the-u-s-government-and-cybersecurity-5f7be48e/</guid><description>Published: May 2003
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/articles/A50606-2002Jun26.html
Abstract: This article offers a short timeline of government actions to curb the hacking of government computer systems. This article was prescient given the panic the Y2K bug that was creating in the vulnerabilities of government systems.</description></item><item><title>US Encryption Export Regualtion: US to EU: Me Too! — The United States Amends Its Export Controls on Encrption, Responding to Recent Developments in the European Union</title><link>/entries/us-encryption-export-regualtion-us-to-eu-me-too-th-169deed5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/us-encryption-export-regualtion-us-to-eu-me-too-th-169deed5/</guid><description>Authors: Thomsen II, Roszel C and Paytas, Antoinette D
Published: January 2001
URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0267364901001030
Abstract: This paper reviews the most recent changes to the US export controls on encryption items (referred to herein as the “US Regulations”) that were published in the US Federal Register on 19 October, 2000.1165 Fed. Reg. 62600 (2000). It describes how the decision by the European Union (EU) Council of Ministers on 22 June 2000, to create a license free zone for exports of encryption (and other) items (referred to herein as the “EU Regulations”) provided the initial stimulus for these changes.</description></item><item><title>Who Holds the Key? – A Comparative Study of US and European Encryption Policies</title><link>/entries/who-holds-the-key-a-comparative-study-of-us-and-eu-2e2a0618/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/who-holds-the-key-a-comparative-study-of-us-and-eu-2e2a0618/</guid><description>Authors: Andrews, Sarah
Published: June 2000
URL: https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/soc/law/elj/jilt/2000_2/andrews/
Abstract: This paper from 2000 by Sarah Andrews details the arguments for and against the use of encryption. In favor of encryption, the paper discusses the increased need for assurances of confidentiality in email and internet communication, as well as fraud. Against its use, the article discusses hindrances to law enforcement and the concealment of crimes. Finally, this article looks at the competing approaches of regulators in the U.</description></item></channel></rss>