<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2000s on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/2000s/</link><description>Recent content in 2000s on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/2000s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Announcing the Advanced Encryption Standard (AES)</title><link>/entries/11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/11/</guid><description>Authors: NIST
Published: November 2001
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20030406010431/http://www.csrc.nist.gov/publications/fips/fips197/fips-197.pdf</description></item><item><title>CALEA</title><link>/entries/144/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/144/</guid><description>Authors: EFF
Published: 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/issues/calea
Abstract: The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994 Congress passed the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) in 1994, which forced telephone companies to redesign their network architectures to make it easier for law enforcement to wiretap digital telephone calls. In 2005, CALEA was expanded by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to include Internet service providers (ISPs) and VoIP services like Skype.</description></item><item><title>Clinton Administration announces new cyber security proposals</title><link>/entries/102/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/102/</guid><description>Authors: Libbie Schlatheri
Published: July 2000</description></item><item><title>Congress Mulls Stiff Crypto Laws</title><link>/entries/38/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/38/</guid><description>Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/09/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws/
Abstract: Some lawmakers say encryption laws can let terrorists plot attacks such as Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s assaults on the East Coast. Congress is considering a crypto-crackdown. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>Cryptography and Liberty 2000</title><link>/entries/115/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/115/</guid><description>Authors: Wayne Madsen, David Banisar
Published: 2000
URL: https://epic.org/reports/crypto2000.html/</description></item><item><title>Disputes on Electronic Message Encryption Take On New Urgency</title><link>/entries/154/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/154/</guid><description>Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2001/09/25/business/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-new-urgency.html
Abstract: Attacks of Sept 11 renew debate on how strongly public&amp;ndash;and by extension terrorists and other criminals&amp;ndash;should be able to encrypt their electronic messages; technology of scrambling data and messages has become crucial element of computer security for businesses and consumers; officials of law enforcement and intelligence agencies have long warned lawmakers that they were unable to break strongest encryption products, and that crimes eventually would be committed that might otherwise have been prevented; FBI has not said publicly whether hijackers who attacked World Trade Center and Pentagon even used encryption to cloak their communications; Philip R Zimmermann, creator of popular encryption programs, known as PGP, says he would be surprised if this were not case; Sen Judd Gregg says he will not make specific legislative proposal until he sees what Atty Gen John Ashcroft includes in final version of his broad anti-terrorism bill; says he wants to see legislation to order encryption companies that sell products in US to include back door that would allow government access when terrorist uses encyption (M)</description></item><item><title>Encryption restrictions</title><link>/entries/19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/19/</guid><description>Published: March 2004
URL: https://www.networkworld.com/article/2331257/encryption-restrictions.html
Abstract: Regulations regarding the import and export of encryption products affect buying decisions worldwide.</description></item><item><title>Techies Urge Senator To Drop Encryption Key Plan</title><link>/entries/153/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/153/</guid><description>Authors: Brian Krebs
Published: October 2001
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20011011022244/http://www.newsbytes.com/news/01/170592.html</description></item><item><title>US Encryption Export Regualtion: US to EU: Me Too! — The United States Amends Its Export Controls on Encrption, Responding to Recent Developments in the European Union</title><link>/entries/29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/29/</guid><description>Published: January 2001
URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0267364901001030
Abstract: This paper reviews the most recent changes to the US export controls on encryption items (referred to herein as the “US Regulations”) that were published in the US Federal Register on 19 October, 2000.1165 Fed. Reg. 62600 (2000). It describes how the decision by the European Union (EU) Council of Ministers on 22 June 2000, to create a license free zone for exports of encryption (and other) items (referred to herein as the “EU Regulations”) provided the initial stimulus for these changes.</description></item><item><title>Who Holds the Key? – A Comparative Study of US and European Encryption Policies</title><link>/entries/161/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/161/</guid><description>Authors: Sarah Andrews
Published: June 2000
URL: https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/soc/law/elj/jilt/2000_2/andrews/
Abstract: With everyday transactions now being carried out electronically, people need to trust that their private communications are not intercepted or altered as they make their way across global networks. Encryption is currently the only reliable means of securing the confidentiality of such communications and can help citizens and businesses defend themselves against fraud, electronic vandalism and the improper disclosure of confidential information.</description></item></channel></rss>