<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Office of Cybersecurity on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/office-of-cybersecurity/</link><description>Recent content in Office of Cybersecurity on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/office-of-cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>H.R. 2545 - Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/h-r-2545-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-a-2d6fd580/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/h-r-2545-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-a-2d6fd580/</guid><description>Authors: Cummings, Elijah E. and Krishnamoorthi, Raja
Published: May 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/2545/text
Abstract: On May 7, 2019, Representatives Cummings and Krishnamoorthi introduced H.R. 2545, the Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019. H.R. 2545 sought to create an Office of Cybersecurity at the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) for “supervision of data security at consumer reporting agencies, to require the promulgation of regulations establishing standards for effective cybersecurity for effective cybersecurity at consumer reporting agencies, to impose penalties on credit reporting agencies for cybersecurity breaches that put sensitive consumer data at risk, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>S. 1336 - Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/s-1336-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-act-e1fa535f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-1336-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-act-e1fa535f/</guid><description>Authors: Warren, Elizabeth and Warner
Published: May 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/1336/text
Abstract: To create an Office of Cybersecurity at the Federal Trade Commission for supervision of data security at consumer reporting agencies, to require the promulgation of regulations establishing standards for effective cybersecurity at consumer reporting agencies, to impose penalties on credit reporting agencies for cybersecurity breaches that put sensitive consumer data at risk, and for other purposes.</description></item></channel></rss>