<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Human Rights on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/human-rights/</link><description>Recent content in Human Rights on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/human-rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anonymity and Encryption: Comments Submitted to the United Nations Special Rapporteur on the Promotion and Protection of the Right to Freedom of Opinion and Expression</title><link>/entries/anonymity-and-encryption-comments-submitted-to-the-679d1ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/anonymity-and-encryption-comments-submitted-to-the-679d1ec2/</guid><description>Authors: Rodriguez, Katitza
Published: February 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/files/2015/02/10/unanonymity-encryption-eff.pdf
Abstract: The Electron Frontier Foundation’s comments regarding Anonymity and Encryption describe and argue for the benefit of anonymity and encryption. The comments describe what anonymity and digital anonymity are, their relevance to human rights, and policies around the world which either undermine or support the right to anonymity from both private and government actors. Finally, the comments describe encryption and its defend individuals right to encryption.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 5/19/2015</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-5-19-2015-ad5d54f2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-5-19-2015-ad5d54f2/</guid><description>Published: May 2015
URL: https://static.newamerica.org/attachments/3138&amp;ndash;113/Encryption_Letter_to_Obama_final_051915.pdf
Abstract: We urge you to reject any proposal that U.S. companies deliberately weaken the security of their products. We request that the White House instead focus on developing policies that will promote rather than undermine the wide adoption of strong encryption technology. Such policies will in turn help to promote and protect cybersecurity, economic growth, and human rights, both here and abroad.</description></item><item><title>Cryptography and Liberty 2000: An International Survey of Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/cryptography-and-liberty-2000-an-international-sur-3c4921c1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/cryptography-and-liberty-2000-an-international-sur-3c4921c1/</guid><description>Authors: Banisar, David and Madsen, Wayne
Published: 2000
URL: https://epic.org/reports/crypto2000.html/
Abstract: Cryptography and Liberty is a survey by EPIC, a non-profit organization, on governmental encryption and cryptography laws around the world and the impacts of human rights. The survey focused on laws on domestic use of cryptography, disclosure requirements for encryption keys, import and export controls, and which government agencies or entities regulate cryptography and encryption.</description></item><item><title>Encryption is a Human Rights issue: Your Privacy and Pree Speech Depend on It</title><link>/entries/encryption-is-a-human-rights-issue-your-privacy-an-62451d82/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-is-a-human-rights-issue-your-privacy-an-62451d82/</guid><description>Authors: Amul Kalia
Published: December 2016
URL: https://www.learnliberty.org/blog/encryption-is-a-human-rights-issue-your-privacy-and-free-speech-depend-on-it/
Abstract: In December of 2016, Amul Kalia, a staff member of the Electronic Frontier Foundation, wrote, emphasizing the importance of encryption, through the lens of American history. Kalia highlighted the less technologically advanced uses of encrypted communications implored by the Founding Fathers of the United States (Thomas Jefferson, George Washington, and James Madison), such as coded messaging and ciphers, to argue that encryption is “crucial to a free society.</description></item><item><title>Human Rights and Encryption</title><link>/entries/human-rights-and-encryption-380229a2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/human-rights-and-encryption-380229a2/</guid><description>Authors: U.N. Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization
Published: 2016
URL: https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000246527
Abstract: This study from the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization outlines the benefits of encryption to human rights, the legality of interference with free and strong encryption, and gives best practices for nations and other stakeholders. This study offers case studies in various member states, including Germany, the United States, India, and Brazil, and looks at both legal restrictions on encryption as well as legal measures which promote its adoption.</description></item><item><title>International Human Rights Organizations Express Privacy Concerns About Canadian Cryptography Policy</title><link>/entries/international-human-rights-organizations-express-p-07872304/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/international-human-rights-organizations-express-p-07872304/</guid><description>Authors: Electronic Frontier Canada
Published: April 1998
URL: http://www.efc.ca/pages/pr/efc-pr.27apr98.html
Abstract: On April 27, 1998, Electronic Frontier Canada, Canada’s leading online civil liberties group, issued a press release regarding the 23 civil liberty and human rights organizations—all members of the Global Internet Liberty Campaign—who signed a letter urging the Canadian government to liberalize its cryptography policy. The letter, which was issued in response to an Industry Canada report which listed possible scenarios for government regulation of encryption hardware and software, emphasized the freedom of expression, freedom of association, and privacy rights protected by cryptography.</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad Idea</title><link>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</guid><description>Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Abstract: In April 2015, OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston was schedule to testify before the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform’s Subcommittee on Information Technology regarding backdoor mandates and potential U.S. policy responses. New America published this blog post, on April 28, 2015, summarizing Bankston’s prepared statement and highlighting the ten key reasons Bankston identified against backdoor mandates. The reasons identified by Bankston were: 1) surveillance backdoors were already rejected as a policy approach two decades ago, including by Congress; 2) it would seriously undermine U.</description></item><item><title>Report of the Special Rapporteur on the promotion and protection of the right to freedom of opinion and expression, David Kaye</title><link>/entries/report-of-the-special-rapporteur-on-the-promotion-8c9333a5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/report-of-the-special-rapporteur-on-the-promotion-8c9333a5/</guid><description>Authors: Kaye, David
Published: May 2015
URL: https://www.undocs.org/A/HRC/29/32
Abstract: On June 19, 2018, the United Nations’ Special Rapporteur on the promotion and protection of the right to freedom of opinion and expression issued a report regarding Liberia’s protections of the right to freedom of opinion and expression. The aim of the visit and subsequent report was “to assess the situation as regards the right to freedom of expression in [Liberia], in particular the issues of press freedom, media independence and diversity, and access to information.</description></item><item><title>Submission of the Citizen Lab (Munk School of Global Affairs, University of Toronto) to the United Nations Special Rapporteur on Violence Against Women, Its Causes and Consequences, Ms. Dubravka Šimonović</title><link>/entries/submission-of-the-citizen-lab-munk-school-of-globa-8208d51f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/submission-of-the-citizen-lab-munk-school-of-globa-8208d51f/</guid><description>Published: November 2017
URL: https://citizenlab.ca/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Final-UNSRVAG-CitizenLab.pdf
Abstract: This report, submitted to the o the United Nations Special Rapporteur on violence against women, details how gender-based violence can be perpetrated through technology and how encryption should be part of the solution to prevent such violence. The report offers case studies of gendered violence in Canada and proposes solutions. Among those solutions, encryption can offer privacy and anonymity to victims, as well as advocates.</description></item><item><title>The Human Rights Benefits of Encryption</title><link>/entries/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption-9be91f1d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption-9be91f1d/</guid><description>Authors: Andi Wilson Thompson
Published: March 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/the-human-rights-benefits-of-encryption/
Abstract: The Human Rights Benefits of Encryption is a blog post detailing public interest organizations&amp;rsquo; efforts to have encryption recognized as a right by the UN Human Rights Council. This article describes submissions by a multitude of public interest organizations—including the ACLU, Human Rights Watch, and technology-specific organizations—and their arguments for the importance of encryption to free expression, privacy, and human rights.</description></item><item><title>Travel Guide to the Digital World: Encryption Policy for Human Rights Defenders</title><link>/entries/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-encryption-polic-d0a50ee7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-encryption-polic-d0a50ee7/</guid><description>Authors: Global Partners Digital, Stepanovich, Amie, Wingfield, Richard
Published: 2017
URL: https://www.gp-digital.org/publication/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-4-encryption-policy-for-human-rights-defenders/
Abstract: This is a guide, aimed at a non-technical audience, seeking to explain the connection between human rights and encryption. The article gives a background on the basics of encryption, and how it affects the day-to-day life of people around the globe, and its impacts on privacy and freedom of expression. Finally, the article outlines the legal and policy background of encryption regulation across the globe and at the international, national, and local levels.</description></item><item><title>We Need More Protection from Government Surveillance — Not Less</title><link>/entries/we-need-more-protection-from-government-surveillan-33e5e137/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/we-need-more-protection-from-government-surveillan-33e5e137/</guid><description>Authors: McGowan, Iverna, Naranjo, Diego, Koomen, Maria, Beltrà, Guillermo, Preiss, Omri, Massé, Estelle, Cohn, Cindy, Stollmeyer, Alice, Bukovská, Barbora, Dusepulchre, Gaelle, Anderson, Andrew, Skoric, Vanja, Westby, Joe, Keller, Paul
Published: July 2021
URL: https://www.politico.eu/article/we-need-more-protection-government-surveillance-not-less/
Abstract: A group of user- and human-rights advocates jointly write an article published by Politico in response to Catherine de Bolle and Cyrus R. Vance, Jr.s, &amp;ldquo;The Last Refuge of the Criminal: Encypted Smartphones.&amp;rdquo; They describe the importance of encryption to democracy and human rights in the face of increasing pressure by government for tech-company-assisted surveillance, citing multiple groups that depend upon encryption for privacy and physical safety: from investigative journalists to subjects of authoritarian governments to members of the LGBTQ+ community.</description></item><item><title>Who Holds the Key? – A Comparative Study of US and European Encryption Policies</title><link>/entries/who-holds-the-key-a-comparative-study-of-us-and-eu-1cf69bed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/who-holds-the-key-a-comparative-study-of-us-and-eu-1cf69bed/</guid><description>Authors: Sarah Andrews
Published: June 2000
URL: https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/soc/law/elj/jilt/2000_2/andrews/
Abstract: This paper from 2000 by Sarah Andrews details the arguments for and against the use of encryption. In favor of encryption, the paper discusses the increased need for assurances of confidentiality in email and internet communication, as well as fraud. Against its use, the article discusses hindrances to law enforcement and the concealment of crimes. Finally, this article looks at the competing approaches of regulators in the U.</description></item></channel></rss>