<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Law Enforcement on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/law-enforcement/</link><description>Recent content in Law Enforcement on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/law-enforcement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Judicial Framework for Evaluating Network Investigative Techniques</title><link>/entries/a-judicial-framework-for-evaluating-network-invest-f6ee8147/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/a-judicial-framework-for-evaluating-network-invest-f6ee8147/</guid><description>Authors: Hennessey, Susan and Weaver, Nicholas
Published: July 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/judicial-framework-evaluating-network-investigative-techniques
Abstract: This article in Lawfare by Susan Hennessey and Nicholas Weaver discusses the use of the NIT in the Playpen investigation, whether the government must disclose an NIT so that defendants may receive a fair trial, and proposes questions that courts should ask when evaluating disclosure of an NIT going forward. First, this article gives a background on the Playpen investigation, and the use of an NIT in the investigation, and background on NITs generally.</description></item><item><title>Attorney General William P. Barr Delivers Keynote Address at the International Conference on Cyber Security</title><link>/entries/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-a-55f805a8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-a-55f805a8/</guid><description>Authors: Barr, William
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-address-international-conference-cyber
Abstract: Former Attorney General William Barr delivered the keynote address at the International Conference on Cyber Security in 2019. In the speech, Barr describes encryption as a technology that gives cover to criminals, particularly drug cartels, and prevents law enforcement from solving crimes. Barr insinuates that the Fourth Amendment, through balancing personal privacy and public safety, may not allow so-called “warrant-proof encryption” and requests backdoors be added to encryption to allow law enforcement access to encrypted messages through pursuant to warrants.</description></item><item><title>Australian Government Passes Contentious Encryption Law</title><link>/entries/australian-government-passes-contentious-encryptio-6d9e9517/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/australian-government-passes-contentious-encryptio-6d9e9517/</guid><description>Authors: Tarabay, Jamie
Published: June 2018
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/06/world/australia/encryption-bill-nauru.html
Abstract: On December 6, 2018, the New York Times published an article about Australia’s passage of the Telecommunications and Other Legislation Amendment (Assistance and Access) Act 2018 (TOLA Act), which requires technology companies to grant law enforcement access to encrypted messages. The article’s main focus was relaying the arguments of the opponents and proponents of the bill. Opponents of the bill believe it compromises the privacy of Australians, could lead to abuse, and will encourage other countries to follow suit.</description></item><item><title>Clinton Administration Encryption Policy Statement \&amp; Press Briefing</title><link>/entries/clinton-administration-encryption-policy-statement-cdde72d2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/clinton-administration-encryption-policy-statement-cdde72d2/</guid><description>Published: September 1998
URL: https://congressional.proquest.com/congressional</description></item><item><title>Demystifying U.S. Encryption Export Controls</title><link>/entries/demystifying-u-s-encryption-export-controls-22620d22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/demystifying-u-s-encryption-export-controls-22620d22/</guid><description>Authors: James B. Altman, William McGlone
Published: 1996
URL: https://heinonline.org/HOL/P?h=hein.journals/aulr46&amp;amp;i=507
Abstract: This 1996 law review article by James Altman and William McGlone seeks to offer practical insights on export controls of encryption software and the underlying policy consideration. First, this article establishes the landscape of encryption in global business and trade. Second, the article explains the U.S. export controls and licensing requirements in place in 1996, including the scope of laws, agency jurisdiction.</description></item><item><title>Deputy Attorney General Rod J. Rosenstein Delivers Remarks at the Global Cyber Security Summit</title><link>/entries/deputy-attorney-general-rod-j-rosenstein-delivers-a3df0cc4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/deputy-attorney-general-rod-j-rosenstein-delivers-a3df0cc4/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenstein, Rod
Published: October 2017
URL: https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/deputy-attorney-general-rod-j-rosenstein-delivers-remarks-global-cyber-security-summit
Abstract: This speech by Deputy Attorney General Rod J. Rosenstein at the Global Cyber Security Summit in 2017 argues that competitive forces lead technology companies and the makers of encrypted technologies to resist cooperation with law enforcement. The speech details global cybersecurity threats, and how government programs, such as the Department of Defense and Department of justice have developed programs to help counter cyber attacks.</description></item><item><title>Encryption and the First Amendment</title><link>/entries/encryption-and-the-first-amendment-333ee479/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-and-the-first-amendment-333ee479/</guid><description>Authors: Samoriski, Jan H. and Huffman, John L. and Trauth, Denise M.
Published: September 1997
URL: https://doi.org/10.1080/10811689709368633
Abstract: This law review article by Jan H. Samoriski, John L. Huffman, and Denise M. Trauth describes finds that Clinton Administration proposals on encryption policy, including the Clipper Chip initiatives, encryption key escrow, and domestic restrictions on encryption infringe on the privacy interests of individuals and likely violate the First Amendment. The article first described the development of encryption policy through the &amp;rsquo;90s.</description></item><item><title>Encryption, Biometrics, and the Status Quo Ante</title><link>/entries/encryption-biometrics-and-the-status-quo-ante-6819368c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-biometrics-and-the-status-quo-ante-6819368c/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenzweig, Paul
Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/encryption-biometrics-and-status-quo-ante
Abstract: On July 6, 2015, Paul Rosenzweig, founder of Red Branch Consulting PLLC, wrote about a paradigm shift in the encryption debate, and offered a solution to deal with the paradigm shift. In 1995, data “could not be maintained in an undecryptable format”, access to data was “achieved through lawful process (either a search warrant or a subpoena)”, and the subject of an investigation received notice.</description></item><item><title>Encryption: A 21st Century National Security Dilemma</title><link>/entries/encryption-a-21st-century-national-security-dilemm-bc971f67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-a-21st-century-national-security-dilemm-bc971f67/</guid><description>Authors: Ackerman, Wystan M.
Published: July 1998
URL: https://doi.org/10.1080/13600869855487
Abstract: In 1998, an article was published in the International Review of Law, Computers &amp;amp; Technology, which advocated for the implementation of a federal encryption scheme which utilizes export controls and a key recovery system. Export controls should be used to address issues with gathering foreign intelligence for national security matters, and a key recovery system should be used to meet the needs of law enforcement when they conduct investigations.</description></item><item><title>Ex-MI5 Chief Warns Against Crackdown on Encrypted Messaging Apps</title><link>/entries/ex-mi5-chief-warns-against-crackdown-on-encrypted-9cfea775/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ex-mi5-chief-warns-against-crackdown-on-encrypted-9cfea775/</guid><description>Authors: Grierson, Jamie
Published: August 2017
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/aug/11/ex-mi5-chief-warns-against-crackdown-encrypted-messaging-apps
Abstract: On August 11, 2017, The Guardian published an article regarding comments made by a former head of MI5, Lord Evans, who does “not support a clampdown on use of encryption”. Instead, Lord Evans pointed to other, greater threats than encryption, including the state of cybersecurity as a whole, cybersecurity for the internet of things, and attacks on British democracy from foreign actors like Russia.</description></item><item><title>Feds Put Heat on Web Firms for Master Encryption Keys</title><link>/entries/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-k-c6363e83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-k-c6363e83/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: July 2013
URL: https://www.cnet.com/news/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-keys/
Abstract: In July of 2013, Declan McCullagh, a senior writer for CNET, wrote regarding the continued effort of major U.S. intelligence agencies (the FBI and NSA) to obtain master encryption (SSL) keys used by internet service providers to shield private communications. McCullagh referred to the efforts of the U.S. government as a “technological escalation in the clandestine methods that the FBI and National Security Agency employ when conducting electronic surveillance against Internet users,” and warned of the sheer scope of the information which could be intercepted if such a key were turned over.</description></item><item><title>First and Fifth Amendment Challenges to Export Controls on Encryption: Bernstein and Karn</title><link>/entries/first-and-fifth-amendment-challenges-to-export-con-41c9888c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/first-and-fifth-amendment-challenges-to-export-con-41c9888c/</guid><description>Authors: Pilkington, Laura M.
Published: 1996
URL: https://heinonline.org/HOL/P?h=hein.journals/saclr37&amp;amp;i=177</description></item><item><title>H.R. 4943 - Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act</title><link>/entries/h-r-4943-clarifying-lawful-overseas-use-of-data-ac-f1395da4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/h-r-4943-clarifying-lawful-overseas-use-of-data-ac-f1395da4/</guid><description>Authors: Collins, Doug
Published: February 2018
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/4943
Abstract: On February 6, 2018, Representatives Collins, Jeffries, Issa, DelBene, Marino, Rutherford and Demings introduced H.R. 4943, the “Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act” or the “CLOUD Act.” H.R. 4943 amends title 18 of the United States federal criminal code to “improve law enforcement access to data stored across borders, and for other purposes.” The bill requires electronic communication service (ECS) and remote computer service (RCS) providers to comply with existing preservation, backup and disclosure requirements pertaining to contents of electronic communications and any record or other information pertaining to a customer or subscriber within their possession, regardless of whether the information is located within the United States.</description></item><item><title>NSA Isn’t the Going Dark Solution, Part I: Richard Clarke Gets It Wrong</title><link>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-cl-976df318/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-cl-976df318/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/nsa-isnt-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-clarke-gets-it-wrong
Abstract: Let’s start with a point that will be significant emotional satisfaction to many readers: Richard Clarke was dead wrong. In a remarkable statement last week, the former Clinton and early Bush administration counterterrorism official told NPR’s Morning Edition:</description></item><item><title>NSA Isn’t the Going Dark Solution, Part II: There’s No Such Thing As Magic</title><link>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-9863433f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-9863433f/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/nsa-isnt-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-such-thing-magic
Abstract: In Part I of this series, I noted the tendency of commentators—without any actual knowledge—to assert that NSA could simply break into a given locked iPhone.</description></item><item><title>Prepared Statement by Senator Chuck Grassley, Hearing On “Going Dark: Encryption, Technology, and the Balance Between Public Safety and Privacy</title><link>/entries/prepared-statement-by-senator-chuck-grassley-heari-63a8fa1c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/prepared-statement-by-senator-chuck-grassley-heari-63a8fa1c/</guid><description>Authors: Grassley, Chuck
Published: July 2015
Abstract: On July 8, 2015, Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, Senator Chuck Grassley, addressed a Senate hearing, inquiring “whether recent technological changes have upset the balance between public safety and privacy.” Of particular focus for Senator Grassley was responding to law enforcement questions of “whether the laws Congress has enacted over the years to adapt [the framework of the Fourth Amendment] to changing technology, such as the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act, or CALEA, are adequate to the task [of preserving the rule of law, ensuring the maintenance of public safety, and protecting individual privacy and civil liberties].</description></item><item><title>Promoting Public Saftey, Privacy, and the Rule of Law Around the World: The Purpose and Impact of the CLOUD Act</title><link>/entries/promoting-public-saftey-privacy-and-the-rule-of-la-062fe8ee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/promoting-public-saftey-privacy-and-the-rule-of-la-062fe8ee/</guid><description>Published: April 2019
Abstract: In April 2019, the Department of Justice published this White Paper on the purpose and impact of the CLOUD Act. The Paper explains the CLOUD Act was enacted to speed access to electronic information held by U.S.-based global providers (communications service providers, “CSPs”) that is critical to foreign partners’ investigations of serious crimes. Specifically, the CLOUD Act is designed to permit those “foreign partners that have robust protections for privacy and civil liberties to enter into executive agreements with the United States to obtain access” this electronic information and evidence.</description></item><item><title>Questions for Apple</title><link>/entries/questions-for-apple-b3e6b97c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/questions-for-apple-b3e6b97c/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey, Benjamin Wittes
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/questions-apple
Abstract: On March 1, 2016, Susan Hennessey and Benjamin Wittes, Executive Editor and Editor in Chief of Lawfare, wrote in Lawfare regarding a House Judiciary Committee hearing at which both FBI Director James Comey and Apple General Counsel Bruce Sewell were scheduled to testify on going dark matters. Hennessey and Wittes published a series of questions for Apple. The questions covered a range of topics, including anticipated impacts on Apple stemming from China’s 2015 Counterterrorism Law and Apple’s rationale for declining to comply with requests from law enforcement to decrypt their devices.</description></item><item><title>Report of the Attorney General's Cyber Digital Task Force</title><link>/entries/report-of-the-attorney-general-s-cyber-digital-tas-7bcf0590/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/report-of-the-attorney-general-s-cyber-digital-tas-7bcf0590/</guid><description>Published: July 2018
Abstract: In February of 2018, the Attorney General established a Cyber-Digital Task force within the U.S. Department of Justice and tasked it with answer two foundational questions. First, “how is the Department responding to cyber threats?” Second, “how can federal law enforcement more effectively accomplish its mission in this important and rapidly evolving area?” This Report addresses the first question. The Report begins with a focus on malign foreign influence operations, before expanding into a discussion of other cyber-enabled threats.</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Encryption</title><link>/entries/rethinking-encryption-b0065e9b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/rethinking-encryption-b0065e9b/</guid><description>Authors: Baker, Jim
Published: October 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/rethinking-encryption
Abstract: This article written by Jim Baker encourages law enforcement officials in the U.S. to embrace encryption due to cybersecurity threats, particularly from china. The article begins by describing the issues of going dark to law enforcement, and quotes officials such as Attorney General William Barr encouraging Congress to legislate around encryption. However, because Congress has failed to act in light of such pressures, it is possible action will never occur.</description></item><item><title>Security Win: Burr-Feinstein Proposal Declared “Dead” for This Year</title><link>/entries/security-win-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-728401be/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-win-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-728401be/</guid><description>Authors: Reitman, rainey
Published: May 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/05/win-one-security-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-year
Abstract: This post from the Electronic Frontier Foundation details how proposed legislation from Senators Burr and Feinstein was not going to be introduced, which was seen as a win by many privacy advocates. The article explains the proposal, which would mandate backdoors, and then describes that although it would not advance, many others like it were still being proposed or debated.</description></item><item><title>Security “Front Doors” vs. “Back Doors”: A Distinction Without a Difference</title><link>/entries/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-a-distinction-w-27fb709b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-a-distinction-w-27fb709b/</guid><description>Authors: Jeffrey Vagle, Matt Blaze
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.justsecurity.org/16503/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-distinction-difference/
Abstract: This article by Jeffrey Vagle and Matt Blaze discusses FBI Director James Comey’s speeches calling for back doors in encryption for law enforcement and argues that it is technologically infeasible and politically wise. The article details how back doors will eventually be uncovered and lead to vulnerabilities in systems. Finally, the article argues that the language being used to advocate for back doors builds a false sense of security in populations unfamiliar with the technological realities and leads people away from more workable solutions.</description></item><item><title>Statement of General Keith B. Alexander, Commander, United States Cyber Command, Before the Senate Committee on Armed Services</title><link>/entries/statement-of-general-keith-b-alexander-commander-u-d467327a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/statement-of-general-keith-b-alexander-commander-u-d467327a/</guid><description>Authors: Alexander, Keith B.
Published: March 2013</description></item><item><title>The Burr-Feinstein Proposal Is Simply Anti-Security</title><link>/entries/the-burr-feinstein-proposal-is-simply-anti-securit-e9e5d5f1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-burr-feinstein-proposal-is-simply-anti-securit-e9e5d5f1/</guid><description>Authors: Cohn, Cindy
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/04/burr-feinstein-proposal-simply-anti-security
Abstract: This article described proposed legislation that would require technology companies—including device manufacturers, software developers, ISPs, and others—to decrypt data if ordered to do so by any court at any time. Further, because the proposed actions are not feasible, and if the law were enacted it would harm Americans’ privacy, all while foreign alternatives would still be available. The article argues that because the proposal is so far removed from any technologically feasible solution, it demonstrates how out of touch key regulators are with the reality of encryption.</description></item><item><title>The Encryption Tightrope: Balancing Americans' Security and Privacy</title><link>/entries/the-encryption-tightrope-balancing-americans-secur-8372b960/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-encryption-tightrope-balancing-americans-secur-8372b960/</guid><description>Published: March 2016
Abstract: On March 1, 2016, the House Judiciary Committee of the 114th Congress held a hearing entitled, The Encryption Tightrope: Balancing Americans’ Security and Privacy. The key focus of the hearing was answering the question: How do we deploy ever stronger, more effective encryption without unduly preventing lawful access to communications of criminals and terrorists intent on doing us harm? The Committee began the hearing by nothing its chief concern, that “[a]doption of new communications technologies by those intending harm to the American people is outpacing law enforcement’s technological capability to access those communications in legitimate criminal and national security investigations.</description></item><item><title>The Five Eyes Statement on Encryption: Things Are Seldom What They Seem</title><link>/entries/the-five-eyes-statement-on-encryption-things-are-s-be5639a2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-five-eyes-statement-on-encryption-things-are-s-be5639a2/</guid><description>Authors: Landau, Susan
Published: September 2018
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/five-eyes-statement-encryption-things-are-seldom-what-they-seem
Abstract: This report from Lawfare details a summit of law enforcement officials from the Five Eyes intelligence alliance—made up of Australia, Canada, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, and the United States—and argues that the rhetoric espoused was far less troubling than it seemed. At the summit, Australian officials detailed an aggressive stance against encryption. However, by ignoring technical realities, the policy proposals are rendered toothless.</description></item><item><title>The Risks of “Responsible Encryption”</title><link>/entries/the-risks-of-responsible-encryption-149c012c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-risks-of-responsible-encryption-149c012c/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2018
Abstract: The Risks of “Responsible Encryption” critiques “responsible encryption,” a term developed used by US law enforcement officials describing a general policy of government access to encrypted materials. The article begins by detailing the origins of the terms and their use by government officials, then seeks to define the scope of the term and possible technical definitions. Next, the paper warns of the risks of exceptional access, including increased key usage and access, authentication of exceptional access requests at scale, the economic and competitive effects on US technology companies, and the limitations of exceptional access capabilities.</description></item><item><title>The Way Forward: Working Together to Tackle Cybercrime</title><link>/entries/the-way-forward-working-together-to-tackle-cybercr-9b44953b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-way-forward-working-together-to-tackle-cybercr-9b44953b/</guid><description>Authors: Wray, Christopher
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/speeches/the-way-forward-working-together-to-tackle-cybercrime
Abstract: These remarks, given by Cristopher Wray, former director of the FBI at the 2019 FBI International Conference on Cyber Security, offer an insight into the goals and capabilities of the FBI. Director Wray describes the capabilities of the FBI to combat cybersecurity, the dangers of foreign influence, and the foreign development of cyber technology. Then, Director Wray argues how encryption impedes law enforcement, describes specific crimes where encrypted information hindered an FBI investigation, and argues that lawful access to encrypted materials is increasingly necessary to law enforcement investigations.</description></item><item><title>US Encryption Export Regualtion: US to EU: Me Too! — The United States Amends Its Export Controls on Encrption, Responding to Recent Developments in the European Union</title><link>/entries/us-encryption-export-regualtion-us-to-eu-me-too-th-169deed5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/us-encryption-export-regualtion-us-to-eu-me-too-th-169deed5/</guid><description>Authors: Thomsen II, Roszel C and Paytas, Antoinette D
Published: January 2001
URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0267364901001030
Abstract: This paper reviews the most recent changes to the US export controls on encryption items (referred to herein as the “US Regulations”) that were published in the US Federal Register on 19 October, 2000.1165 Fed. Reg. 62600 (2000). It describes how the decision by the European Union (EU) Council of Ministers on 22 June 2000, to create a license free zone for exports of encryption (and other) items (referred to herein as the “EU Regulations”) provided the initial stimulus for these changes.</description></item></channel></rss>