<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Law Enforcement on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/law-enforcement/</link><description>Recent content in Law Enforcement on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/law-enforcement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Judicial Framework for Evaluating Network Investigative Techniques</title><link>/entries/101/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/101/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey, Nicholas Weaver
Published: July 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/judicial-framework-evaluating-network-investigative-techniques
Tags: 2010s Child Exploitation FBI Going Dark Law Enforcement NIT Abstract: At Motherboard, Joseph Cox reports that defense attorneys representing dozens of defendants nabbed in an FBI child pornography sting have pooled their resources in a “national working group.” A Network Investigative Technique (NIT) conducted on the child pornography website Playpen resulted in the arrest of well over 100 perpetrators, many of whom are now arguing their cases in court.</description></item><item><title>Attorney General William P. Barr Delivers Keynote Address at the International Conference on Cyber Security</title><link>/entries/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/2/</guid><description>Authors: Barr, William
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-address-international-conference-cyber
Tags: 2010s Amendment IV Attorney General William P. Barr Department of Justice Law Enforcement Probable Cause</description></item><item><title>Australian Government Passes Contentious Encryption Law</title><link>/entries/127/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/127/</guid><description>Authors: Tarabay, Jamie
Published: June 2018
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/06/world/australia/encryption-bill-nauru.html
Tags: Australia Five Eyes Law Enforcement Abstract: The law, opposed by privacy advocates, requires tech companies to provide law enforcement and security agencies with access to encrypted communications.</description></item><item><title>Clinton Administration Encryption Policy Statement \&amp; Press Briefing</title><link>/entries/117/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/117/</guid><description>Authors: President Clinton
Published: September 1998
URL: https://congressional.proquest.com/congressional
Tags: 1990s Clinton Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls Law Enforcement Security White House</description></item><item><title>Compliance with Court Orders Act of 2016 (Discussion Draft)</title><link>/entries/43/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/43/</guid><description>Authors: Feinstein, Dianne and Burr, Richard
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.feinstein.senate.gov/public/index.cfm?a=files.serve&amp;amp;File_id=5B990532-CC7F-427F-9942-559E73EB8BFB
Tags: 2010s Compliance with Court Orders Act Going Dark Law Enforcement US Congress Abstract: Dianne Feinstein</description></item><item><title>Demystifying U.S. Encryption Export Controls</title><link>/entries/151/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/151/</guid><description>Authors: James B. Altman, William McGlone
Published: 1996
URL: https://heinonline.org/HOL/P?h=hein.journals/aulr46&amp;amp;i=507
Tags: 1990s Export Controls Keys Law Enforcement</description></item><item><title>Deputy Attorney General Rod J. Rosenstein Delivers Remarks at the Global Cyber Security Summit</title><link>/entries/107/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/107/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenstein, Rod
Published: October 2017
URL: https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/deputy-attorney-general-rod-j-rosenstein-delivers-remarks-global-cyber-security-summit
Tags: 2010s Government Policy Law Enforcement</description></item><item><title>Encryption and the First Amendment</title><link>/entries/177/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/177/</guid><description>Authors: Samoriski, Jan H. and Huffman, John L. and Trauth, Denise M.
Published: September 1997
URL: https://doi.org/10.1080/10811689709368633
Tags: 1990s Amendment I Clinton Law Enforcement Abstract: Recently, only secret government agencies were concerned about cryptography. It now is an important matter for many individuals and businesses who use the Internet. That has led to an intense effort on the part of several governmental agencies to control cryptography. This article provides an explanation of the evolution of cryptography, a synopsis of the evolving cryptography debate, an examination of the different interests represented within the debate and a framework for analyzing the First Amendment issues that are involved.</description></item><item><title>Encryption, Biometrics, and the Status Quo Ante</title><link>/entries/176/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/176/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenzweig, Paul
Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/encryption-biometrics-and-status-quo-ante
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Biometric Encryption Law Enforcement Think Tank Abstract: As the recent indirect debate between FBI Director James Comey and co-blogger Susan Landau makes clear, the underlying premises of the encryption issue are highly contested. The Senate will continue the debate this week with a hearing before the Judiciary Committee on July 8 at which our own Herb Lin (among others) will testify and another hearing before the Intelligence Committee.</description></item><item><title>Encryption: A 21st Century National Security Dilemma</title><link>/entries/189/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/189/</guid><description>Authors: Ackerman, Wystan M.
Published: July 1998
URL: https://doi.org/10.1080/13600869855487
Tags: 1990s Clinton Export Controls Law Enforcement Abstract: As the 21st century approaches, encryption is presenting a national security dilemma in the US. While the use of strong encryption for computerized data is essential in protecting our nation, widespread, unregulated encryption poses serious problems on two levels: encryption could inhibit the government&amp;rsquo;s ability to enforce the law as well as gather foreign intelligence.</description></item><item><title>Ex-MI5 Chief Warns Against Crackdown on Encrypted Messaging Apps</title><link>/entries/93/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/93/</guid><description>Authors: Grierson, Jamie
Published: August 2017
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/aug/11/ex-mi5-chief-warns-against-crackdown-encrypted-messaging-apps
Tags: 2010s Law Enforcement Mobile UK News UK Security and Counter-Terrorism Abstract: Jonathan Evans says although encryption services have hampered terrorism fight he does not support curtailment of its use</description></item><item><title>Feds Put Heat on Web Firms for Master Encryption Keys</title><link>/entries/144/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/144/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: July 2013
URL: https://www.cnet.com/news/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-keys/
Tags: 2010s Backdoors CNET Keys Law Enforcement Abstract: Whether the FBI and NSA have the legal authority to obtain the master keys that companies use for Web encryption remains an open question, but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t stopped the U.S. government from trying.</description></item><item><title>First and Fifth Amendment Challenges to Export Controls on Encryption: Bernstein and Karn</title><link>/entries/190/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/190/</guid><description>Authors: Pilkington, Laura M.
Published: 1996
URL: https://heinonline.org/HOL/P?h=hein.journals/saclr37&amp;amp;i=177
Tags: 1990s Clinton Export Controls Law Enforcement National Security</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Encryption, Technology, and the Balance Between Public Safety and Privacy</title><link>/entries/201/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/201/</guid><description>Authors: Committee on the Judiciary
Published: July 2015
Tags: 2010s Child Exploitation FBI Going Dark Hearing Law Enforcement</description></item><item><title>H.R. 4943 - Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act</title><link>/entries/37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/37/</guid><description>Authors: Collins, Doug
Published: February 2018
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/4943
Tags: 2010s Bill CLOUD Act Data Storage Foreign International Law Enforcement US Congress</description></item><item><title>NSA Isn’t the Going Dark Solution, Part I: Richard Clarke Gets It Wrong</title><link>/entries/165/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/165/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/nsa-isnt-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-clarke-gets-it-wrong
Tags: 2010s Going Dark Law Enforcement NSA Abstract: Let’s start with a point that will be significant emotional satisfaction to many readers: Richard Clarke was dead wrong. In a remarkable statement last week, the former Clinton and early Bush administration counterterrorism official told NPR’s Morning Edition:</description></item><item><title>NSA Isn’t the Going Dark Solution, Part II: There’s No Such Thing As Magic</title><link>/entries/164/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/164/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/nsa-isnt-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-such-thing-magic
Tags: 2010s Going Dark Law Enforcement NSA Abstract: In Part I of this series, I noted the tendency of commentators—without any actual knowledge—to assert that NSA could simply break into a given locked iPhone.</description></item><item><title>Promoting Public Saftey, Privacy, and the Rule of Law Around the World: The Purpose and Impact of the CLOUD Act</title><link>/entries/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/7/</guid><description>Published: April 2019
Tags: 2010s CLOUD Act Department of Justice Foreign International Law Enforcement</description></item><item><title>Questions for Apple</title><link>/entries/162/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/162/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey, Benjamin Wittes
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/questions-apple
Tags: 2010s Going Dark Law Enforcement Abstract: The House Judiciary Committee at 1:00 pm is holding a hearing at which FBI Director James Comey and Apple General Counsel Bruce Sewell will both testify on going dark matters. Here&amp;rsquo;s the live video: The other day, Stewart Baker wrote this sardonic but serious piece in which he posed some questions for Apple.</description></item><item><title>Report of the Attorney General's Cyber Digital Task Force</title><link>/entries/44/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/44/</guid><description>Authors: U.S. Department of Justice
Published: July 2018
Tags: 2010s Department of Justice Going Dark Law Enforcement Abstract: In February of 2018, the Attorney General established a Cyber-Digital Task force within the U.S. Department of Justice and tasked it with answer two foundational questions. First, “how is the Department responding to cyber threats?” Second, “how can federal law enforcement more effectively accomplish its mission in this important and rapidly evolving area?</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Encryption</title><link>/entries/195/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/195/</guid><description>Authors: Baker, Jim
Published: October 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/rethinking-encryption
Tags: 2010 Amendment IV Attorney General William P. Barr CLOUD Act Cybersecurity Going Dark Law Enforcement Public Safety Abstract: I. Embrace Reality and Deal With It</description></item><item><title>Security Win: Burr-Feinstein Proposal Declared “Dead” for This Year</title><link>/entries/159/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/159/</guid><description>Authors: Reitman, rainey
Published: May 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/05/win-one-security-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-year
Tags: 2010s Going Dark Law Enforcement Abstract: The anti-security proposal promoted by Senators Burr and Feinstein is “dead,” according to a Reuters report. The news agency spoke to sources within congressional offices, the administration, and the tech sector, who confirmed that the bill “likely will not be introduced this year and, even if it&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Security “Front Doors” vs. “Back Doors”: A Distinction Without a Difference</title><link>/entries/160/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/160/</guid><description>Authors: Jeffrey Vagle, Matt Blaze
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.justsecurity.org/16503/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-distinction-difference/
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Backdoors-Feasibility Clipper Chip Golden Key James Comey Law Enforcement Mobile Abstract: Thursday, FBI Director James Comey delivered a talk at the Brookings Institution, titled “Going Dark: Are Technology, Privacy, and Public Safety on a Collision Course?” His thesis did not stray too far from his (and others’) recent calls for limitations on software from companies like Google and Apple that employs strong cryptography that even the …</description></item><item><title>Statement of General Keith B. Alexander, Commander, United States Cyber Command, Before the Senate Committee on Armed Services</title><link>/entries/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/6/</guid><description>Authors: Alexander, Keith B.
Published: March 2013
Tags: 2010s Cyber Command Law Enforcement National Security</description></item><item><title>The Burr-Feinstein Proposal Is Simply Anti-Security</title><link>/entries/156/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/156/</guid><description>Authors: Cohn, Cindy
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/04/burr-feinstein-proposal-simply-anti-security
Tags: 2010s Going Dark Law Enforcement Abstract: Sens. Richard Burr and Dianne Feinstein recently released a draft bill forcing nearly all U.S. companies to decrypt any encrypted data they may handle. Specifically, it would place a new, sweepingly broad duty on device manufacturers, software developers, ISPs, online services and others to decrypt&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>The Encryption Tightrope: Balancing Americans' Security and Privacy</title><link>/entries/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/10/</guid><description>Published: March 2016
Tags: 2010s Going Dark Hearing Law Enforcement</description></item><item><title>The Five Eyes Statement on Encryption: Things Are Seldom What They Seem</title><link>/entries/67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/67/</guid><description>Published: September 2018
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/five-eyes-statement-encryption-things-are-seldom-what-they-seem
Tags: 2010s Canada Five Eyes Law Enforcement NZ Abstract: Earlier this September, law enforcement officials from the Five Eyes intelligence alliance—made up of Australia, Canada, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, and the United States—met in Australia and issued a Statement of Principles on Access to Evidence and Encryption.</description></item><item><title>The Risks of “Responsible Encryption”</title><link>/entries/64/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/64/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2018
Tags: 2010s Exceptional Access Government Access Law Enforcement Responsible Encryption Stanford CIS Abstract: Federal law enforcement officials in the United States have recently renewed their periodic demands for legislation to regulate encryption. While they offer few technical specifics, their general proposal—that vendors must retain the ability to decrypt for law enforcement the devices they manufacture or communications their services transmit—presents intractable problems that would-be regulators must not ignore.</description></item><item><title>The Way Forward: Working Together to Tackle Cybercrime</title><link>/entries/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/4/</guid><description>Authors: Wray, Christopher
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/speeches/the-way-forward-working-together-to-tackle-cybercrime
Tags: 2010s FBI Law Enforcement User-Controller Encryption Abstract: FBI Director Christopher Wray’s remarks at the Fordham University - FBI International Conference on Cyber Security, New York City, New York</description></item><item><title>US Encryption Export Regualtion: US to EU: Me Too! — The United States Amends Its Export Controls on Encrption, Responding to Recent Developments in the European Union</title><link>/entries/187/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/187/</guid><description>Authors: Thomsen II, Roszel C and Paytas, Antoinette D
Published: January 2001
URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0267364901001030
Tags: 2000s Export Controls Law Enforcement Abstract: This paper reviews the most recent changes to the US export controls on encryption items (referred to herein as the “US Regulations”) that were published in the US Federal Register on 19 October, 2000.1165 Fed. Reg. 62600 (2000). It describes how the decision by the European Union (EU) Council of Ministers on 22 June 2000, to create a license free zone for exports of encryption (and other) items (referred to herein as the “EU Regulations”) provided the initial stimulus for these changes.</description></item></channel></rss>