<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Government Access on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/government-access/</link><description>Recent content in Government Access on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/government-access/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>As Encryption Spreads, U.S. Grapples with Clash Between Privacy, Security</title><link>/entries/as-encryption-spreads-u-s-grapples-with-clash-betw-c9f820a1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/as-encryption-spreads-u-s-grapples-with-clash-betw-c9f820a1/</guid><description>Authors: Nakashima, Ellen and Gellman, Barton
Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/as-encryption-spreads-us-worries-about-access-to-data-for-investigations/2015/04/10/7c1c7518-d401-11e4-a62f-ee745911a4ff_story.html
Abstract: Ellen Nakashima and Barton Gellman explore the Obama Administration’s handling of and resistance to calls within the Intelligence and Law Enforcement communities to pressure technology companies, such as Apple, to build “back door” access to encrypted user data. The article explores numerous alternative options which were being considered by the White House, such as setting up mirror accounts or compelling companies to back up data to a company server (which would be subject to decryption with a warrant), yet identifies considerable challenges associated with each of the proposed methods.</description></item><item><title>Compliance with Court Orders Act of 2016 - Draft</title><link>/entries/compliance-with-court-orders-act-of-2016-draft-517e2d28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/compliance-with-court-orders-act-of-2016-draft-517e2d28/</guid><description>Authors: Burr, Richard, Feinstein, Dianne
URL: https://www.feinstein.senate.gov/public/index.cfm/2016/4/intelligence-committee-leaders-release-discussion-draft-of-encryption-legislation</description></item><item><title>DOJ Plans to Strike Against Encryption While the Techlash Iron Is Hot</title><link>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2020
URL: /blog/2020/02/doj-plans-strike-against-encryption-while-techlash-iron-hot
Abstract: This blog post by Riana Pfefferkorn argues that since 2016, the Department of Justice sought to capitalize on public anti-technology sentiment to weaken encryption. First, the article describes the political climate, shaped by the Apple v FBI case, the role of big tech in various privacy scandals and foreign interference in the 2016 election, and foreign legislation, particularly in Australia and the U.</description></item><item><title>FBI Blasts Apple, Google for Locking Police out of Phones</title><link>/entries/fbi-blasts-apple-google-for-locking-police-out-of-79e02027/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/fbi-blasts-apple-google-for-locking-police-out-of-79e02027/</guid><description>Authors: Craig Timberg, Greg Miller
Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/2014/09/25/68c4e08e-4344-11e4-9a15-137aa0153527_story.html
Abstract: On September 26, 2014, The Washington Post published an article which discussed the FBI’s criticism of Apple and Google for “for developing forms of smartphone encryption so secure that law enforcement officials cannot easily gain access to information stored on the devices &amp;ndash; even when they have valid search warrants.” The article notes that “while the legal and technical changes are fueled by anger over reports of mass surveillance by the National Security Agency, the consequences are being felt most heavily by police detectives, often armed with warrants certifying that a judge has found probable cause that a search of a smartphone will reveal evidence of a crime.</description></item><item><title>FBI Pressuring Google, Facebook to Allow ‘Back Doors’ for Wiretapping</title><link>/entries/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-to-allow-back-doors-71473338/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-to-allow-back-doors-71473338/</guid><description>Authors: Daniel Tencer
Published: November 2010
URL: https://www.rawstory.com/2010/11/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-wiretapping/
Abstract: On November 17, 2010, Raw Story published an article discussing the debate surrounding a proposed expansion of The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994. At the time, FBI Director Robert Mueller placed pressure on technology companies to build “back doors” which would “allow law enforcement to wiretap data on their networks”, in an effort “to expand the FBI’s wiretapping powers to include the latest communications technologies, including social networking sites, voice-over-Internet (VoIP) telephone services and BlackBerries.</description></item><item><title>Holder Urges Tech Companies to Leave Device Backdoors Open for Police</title><link>/entries/holder-urges-tech-companies-to-leave-device-backdo-1737189d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/holder-urges-tech-companies-to-leave-device-backdo-1737189d/</guid><description>Published: September 2014
URL: https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2014/09/30/holder-urges-tech-companies-to-leave-device-backdoors-open-for-police/
Abstract: This news article from 2014 features comments from Attorney General Eric Holder urging technology companies to insert back doors into their products because encryption could potentially imperial investigations into kidnapping and sexual predation of children. Holder stated that companies could design technology in such a way that would not burden privacy. This article outlines statements from a top law enforcement official, linking encryption to crimes against children.</description></item><item><title>James Comey, F.B.I. Director, Hints at Action as Cellphone Data Is Locked</title><link>/entries/james-comey-f-b-i-director-hints-at-action-as-cell-f7538b3a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/james-comey-f-b-i-director-hints-at-action-as-cell-f7538b3a/</guid><description>Authors: David E. Sanger, Matt Apuzzo
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2014/10/17/us/politics/fbi-director-in-policy-speech-calls-dark-devices-hindrance-to-crime-solving.html
Abstract: On October 16, 2014, David E. Sanger and Matt Apuzzo wrote for the New York Times regarding F.B.I. Director James Comey’s comments on the potential the Obama administration would seek regulations and laws forcing companies to create an encryption backdoor to unlock photos, emails and contacts stored on cellular devices. The comments came shortly following the decisions of Apple and Google to automatically encrypt the contents of their cellphones—a first among widely used consumer devices—which Comey claimed would hinder intelligence gathering.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Secrets</title><link>/entries/keeping-secrets-73be089b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/keeping-secrets-73be089b/</guid><description>Authors: Corrigan-Gibbs, Henry
Published: December 2014
URL: https://stanfordmag.org/contents/keeping-secrets
Abstract: On November 6, 2014, Stanford Magazine published an article about a group of researchers at Stanford who, at the International Symposium on Information Theory on October 10, 1997, ended “the U.S. government’s longstanding domestic monopoly on cryptography”. Prior to the symposium, the group received a letter from an NSA employee who told the group that “merely publishing a scientific paper on cryptography would be the legal equivalent of exporting nuclear weapons to a foreign country.</description></item><item><title>S. 266 - Comprehensive Counter-Terrorism Act of 1991</title><link>/entries/s-266-comprehensive-counter-terrorism-act-of-1991-780b290c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-266-comprehensive-counter-terrorism-act-of-1991-780b290c/</guid><description>Authors: Biden, Joseph
Published: January 1991
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/102nd-congress/senate-bill/266/text
Abstract: Text for S.266 - 102nd Congress (1991-1992): Comprehensive Counter-Terrorism Act of 1991</description></item><item><title>Surveillance Costs: The NSA's Impact on the Economy, Internet Freedom \&amp; Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/surveillance-costs-the-nsa-s-impact-on-the-economy-5c789458/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/surveillance-costs-the-nsa-s-impact-on-the-economy-5c789458/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle and Bankston, Kevin and Greene, Robyn and Morgus, Robert
Published: July 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/policy-papers/surveillance-costs-the-nsas-impact-on-the-economy-internet-freedom-cybersecurity/
Abstract: It has been over a year since The Guardian reported the first story on the National Security Agency’s surveillance programs based on the leaks from former NSA contractor Edward Snowden, yet the national conversation remains largely mired in a simplistic debate over the tradeoffs between national security and individual privacy. It is time to start weighing the overall costs and benefits more broadly.</description></item><item><title>The Risks of “Responsible Encryption”</title><link>/entries/the-risks-of-responsible-encryption-149c012c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-risks-of-responsible-encryption-149c012c/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2018
Abstract: The Risks of “Responsible Encryption” critiques “responsible encryption,” a term developed used by US law enforcement officials describing a general policy of government access to encrypted materials. The article begins by detailing the origins of the terms and their use by government officials, then seeks to define the scope of the term and possible technical definitions. Next, the paper warns of the risks of exceptional access, including increased key usage and access, authentication of exceptional access requests at scale, the economic and competitive effects on US technology companies, and the limitations of exceptional access capabilities.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Tries to Make It Easier to Wiretap the Internet</title><link>/entries/u-s-tries-to-make-it-easier-to-wiretap-the-interne-7c6b8243/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/u-s-tries-to-make-it-easier-to-wiretap-the-interne-7c6b8243/</guid><description>Authors: Savage, Charlie
Published: September 2010
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2010/09/27/us/27wiretap.html
Abstract: This New York Times article by Charlie Savage reports on planned legislation by the Obama administration which would allow for the US government to decrypt select communications and prevent going dark. The article discusses how encryption has worked in recent law enforcement investigations, and why the government finds such a technology necessary. The article discusses the feasibility of different possible elements of the proposed law, including attempting to regulate encryption technology coming from abroad.</description></item></channel></rss>