<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bill on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/bill/</link><description>Recent content in Bill on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/bill/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>H.R. 2545 - Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/8/</guid><description>Authors: Cummings, Elijah E. and Krishnamoorthi
Published: May 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/2545/text
Tags: 2010s Bill Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019 Federal Trade Commission Office of Cybersecurity US Congress Abstract: To create an Office of Cybersecurity at the Federal Trade Commission for supervision of data security at consumer reporting agencies, to require the promulgation of regulations establishing standards for effective cybersecurity at consumer reporting agencies, to impose penalties on credit reporting agencies for cybersecurity breaches that put sensitive consumer data at risk, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>H.R. 4170 - Ensuring National Constitutional Rights for Your Private Telecommunicatyions Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/7/</guid><description>Authors: Lieu, Ted and DelBene and Jordan
Published: August 2019
Tags: 2019 Bill ENCRYPT Act of 2019 Federalism State&amp;#39;s Rights US Congress Abstract: A Bill To preempt State data security vulnerability manfates and decryption requirements.</description></item><item><title>H.R. 4943 - Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act or CLOUD ACT</title><link>/entries/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/6/</guid><description>Authors: Collins, Doug
Published: February 2018
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/4943
Tags: 2010s Bill CLOUD Act Data Storage Foreign International Law Enforcement US Congress Abstract: Summary of H.R.4943 - 115th Congress (2017-2018): CLOUD Act</description></item><item><title>H.R. 4978 - Online Privacy Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/5/</guid><description>Authors: Eshoo, Anna G. and Lofgren
Published: December 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/4978/text
Tags: 2019 Bill Data Protection Online Privacy Act of 2019 Privacy Rights US Congress Abstract: To provide for individual rights relating to privacy of personal information, to establish privacy and security requirements for covered entities relating to personal information, and to establish an agency to be known as the United States Digital Privacy Agency to enforce such rights and requirements, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>S.1336 - Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/3/</guid><description>Authors: Warren, Elizabeth and Warner
Published: May 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/1336/text
Tags: 2010s Bill Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019 Federal Trade Commission Office of Cybersecurity US Congress Abstract: To create an Office of Cybersecurity at the Federal Trade Commission for supervision of data security at consumer reporting agencies, to require the promulgation of regulations establishing standards for effective cybersecurity at consumer reporting agencies, to impose penalties on credit reporting agencies for cybersecurity breaches that put sensitive consumer data at risk, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>S.1842 - Protecting Personal Health Data Act</title><link>/entries/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/2/</guid><description>Authors: Klobuchar, Amy and Murkowski
Published: June 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/1842/text
Tags: 2010s Bill Encryption Standards Healthcare Policy Protecting Personal Health Data Act US Congress Abstract: To protect the personal health data of all Americans.</description></item><item><title>S.2889 - National Security and Personal Data Protection Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/1/</guid><description>Authors: Hawley and Cotton and Rubio
Published: November 2019
Tags: 2010s Bill Cybersecurity Foreign Investment National Security and Personal Data Protection Act of 2019 Security Requirements US Congress Abstract: To safeguard data of Americans from foreign governments that pose risks to national security by imposing data security requirements and strengthening review of foreign investments, and for other purposes.</description></item></channel></rss>