<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bill on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/bill/</link><description>Recent content in Bill on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/bill/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>H.R. 2545 - Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/h-r-2545-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-a-2d6fd580/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/h-r-2545-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-a-2d6fd580/</guid><description>Authors: Cummings, Elijah E. and Krishnamoorthi, Raja
Published: May 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/2545/text
Abstract: On May 7, 2019, Representatives Cummings and Krishnamoorthi introduced H.R. 2545, the Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019. H.R. 2545 sought to create an Office of Cybersecurity at the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) for “supervision of data security at consumer reporting agencies, to require the promulgation of regulations establishing standards for effective cybersecurity for effective cybersecurity at consumer reporting agencies, to impose penalties on credit reporting agencies for cybersecurity breaches that put sensitive consumer data at risk, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>H.R. 4170 - Ensuring National Constitutional Rights for Your Private Telecommunications Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/h-r-4170-ensuring-national-constitutional-rights-f-808a9c8d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/h-r-4170-ensuring-national-constitutional-rights-f-808a9c8d/</guid><description>Authors: Lieu, Ted and DelBene, Suzan and Jordan, Jim
Published: August 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/116/bills/hr4170/BILLS-116hr4170ih.pdf
Abstract: The ENCRYPT Act of 2019, introduced into the Senate with bipartisan support, seeks to preempt state and local governments from compelling private companies to weaken encryption or insert backdoors. Therefore, this bill would make encryption policy the subject of federal law and out of the hands of state and local lawmakers.</description></item><item><title>H.R. 4943 - Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act</title><link>/entries/h-r-4943-clarifying-lawful-overseas-use-of-data-ac-f1395da4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/h-r-4943-clarifying-lawful-overseas-use-of-data-ac-f1395da4/</guid><description>Authors: Collins, Doug
Published: February 2018
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/4943
Abstract: On February 6, 2018, Representatives Collins, Jeffries, Issa, DelBene, Marino, Rutherford and Demings introduced H.R. 4943, the “Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act” or the “CLOUD Act.” H.R. 4943 amends title 18 of the United States federal criminal code to “improve law enforcement access to data stored across borders, and for other purposes.” The bill requires electronic communication service (ECS) and remote computer service (RCS) providers to comply with existing preservation, backup and disclosure requirements pertaining to contents of electronic communications and any record or other information pertaining to a customer or subscriber within their possession, regardless of whether the information is located within the United States.</description></item><item><title>H.R. 4978 - Online Privacy Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/h-r-4978-online-privacy-act-of-2019-7c0e40e7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/h-r-4978-online-privacy-act-of-2019-7c0e40e7/</guid><description>Authors: Eshoo, Anna G. and Lofgren, Zoe
Published: December 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/4978/text
Abstract: On November 5, 2019, Representatives Eshoo and Lofgren introduced H.R. 4978, the Online Privacy Act of 2019. H.R. 4978 sought to incorporate elements of the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) into federal law. As such, the bill aimed to “provide for individual rights relating to privacy of personal information, to establish privacy and security requirements for covered entities relating to personal information, and to establish an agency to be known as the United States Digital Privacy Agency to enforce such rights and requirements, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>S. 1336 - Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/s-1336-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-act-e1fa535f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-1336-data-breach-prevention-and-compensation-act-e1fa535f/</guid><description>Authors: Warren, Elizabeth and Warner
Published: May 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/1336/text
Abstract: To create an Office of Cybersecurity at the Federal Trade Commission for supervision of data security at consumer reporting agencies, to require the promulgation of regulations establishing standards for effective cybersecurity at consumer reporting agencies, to impose penalties on credit reporting agencies for cybersecurity breaches that put sensitive consumer data at risk, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>S. 2889 - National Security and Personal Data Protection Act of 2019</title><link>/entries/s-2889-national-security-and-personal-data-protect-a7b6e85d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-2889-national-security-and-personal-data-protect-a7b6e85d/</guid><description>Authors: Hawley, Josh and Cotton, Tom and Rubio, Marco
Published: November 2019
Abstract: To safeguard data of Americans from foreign governments that pose risks to national security by imposing data security requirements and strengthening review of foreign investments, and for other purposes.</description></item><item><title>S.1842 - Protecting Personal Health Data Act</title><link>/entries/s-1842-protecting-personal-health-data-act-8bffdbe7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-1842-protecting-personal-health-data-act-8bffdbe7/</guid><description>Authors: Klobuchar, Amy and Murkowski, Lisa
Published: June 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/1842/text
Abstract: To protect the personal health data of all Americans.</description></item></channel></rss>