<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terrorism on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/terrorism/</link><description>Recent content in Terrorism on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/terrorism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Flawed Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/a-flawed-encryption-policy-3f11b295/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/a-flawed-encryption-policy-3f11b295/</guid><description>Published: April 1996
URL: https://search.proquest.com/docview/430685501/fulltext/2EA1B6B49BC74036PQ/1?accountid=14503
Abstract: An editorial contends that the new White House proposal to keep high-powered encryption software out of the hands of foreign terrorists and criminals is needlessly restrictive and probably unworkable. The editorial says that the technology, which is legal in the US, is a good way for honest citizens to prevent crime and should be disseminated domestically and abroad.</description></item><item><title>Congress Mulls Stiff Crypto Laws</title><link>/entries/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws-ca916492/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws-ca916492/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/09/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws/
Abstract: Some lawmakers say encryption laws can let terrorists plot attacks such as Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s assaults on the East Coast. Congress is considering a crypto-crackdown. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>Disputes on Electronic Message Encryption Take on New Urgency</title><link>/entries/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-0c54a3d9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-0c54a3d9/</guid><description>Authors: Schwartz, John
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2001/09/25/business/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-new-urgency.html
Abstract: Attacks of Sept 11 renew debate on how strongly public&amp;ndash;and by extension terrorists and other criminals&amp;ndash;should be able to encrypt their electronic messages; technology of scrambling data and messages has become crucial element of computer security for businesses and consumers; officials of law enforcement and intelligence agencies have long warned lawmakers that they were unable to break strongest encryption products, and that crimes eventually would be committed that might otherwise have been prevented; FBI has not said publicly whether hijackers who attacked World Trade Center and Pentagon even used encryption to cloak their communications; Philip R Zimmermann, creator of popular encryption programs, known as PGP, says he would be surprised if this were not case; Sen Judd Gregg says he will not make specific legislative proposal until he sees what Atty Gen John Ashcroft includes in final version of his broad anti-terrorism bill; says he wants to see legislation to order encryption companies that sell products in US to include back door that would allow government access when terrorist uses encyption (M)</description></item><item><title>Encryption under fire: discussion on threats to private messaging w/ Head of WhatsApp Will Cathcart</title><link>/entries/encryption-under-fire-discussion-on-threats-to-pri-702ca3cd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-under-fire-discussion-on-threats-to-pri-702ca3cd/</guid><description>Published: July 2020
URL: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y1LSFQo_07w</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Lawful Electronic Surveillance in the Face of New Technologies</title><link>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-56088dbf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-56088dbf/</guid><description>Authors: Valerie Caproni
Published: February 2011
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/testimony/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-face-of-new-technologies
Abstract: Statement Before the House Judiciary Committee, Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security</description></item></channel></rss>