<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terrorism on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/terrorism/</link><description>Recent content in Terrorism on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/terrorism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Flawed Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/a-flawed-encryption-policy-766f7f2f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/a-flawed-encryption-policy-766f7f2f/</guid><description>Published: April 1996
URL: https://search.proquest.com/docview/430685501/fulltext/2EA1B6B49BC74036PQ/1?accountid=14503
Abstract: This editorial in the New York Times argues that the Clinton Administration’s proposal to prevent the dissemination of encryption software to terrorists or criminals was both unworkable and presented risks to US commerce. The article discusses how industry and public interest advocates rejected the Administration’s proposals based on concerns about censorship, and the unworkability of the plan on practical grounds, including foreign unwillingness to acquiesce to potential surveillance by the U.</description></item><item><title>Compliance with Court Orders Act of 2016 - Draft</title><link>/entries/compliance-with-court-orders-act-of-2016-draft-517e2d28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/compliance-with-court-orders-act-of-2016-draft-517e2d28/</guid><description>Authors: Burr, Richard, Feinstein, Dianne
URL: https://www.feinstein.senate.gov/public/index.cfm/2016/4/intelligence-committee-leaders-release-discussion-draft-of-encryption-legislation</description></item><item><title>Congress Mulls Stiff Crypto Laws</title><link>/entries/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws-50dadb61/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws-50dadb61/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/09/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws/
Abstract: On September 13, 2001, Wired published an article about the impact of 9/11 terrorist attacks on the encryption debate, and declared that “[t]he encryption wars have begun”. The article claims that the balance of the debate between privacy and security “abruptly shifted” in the wake of 9/11, and that “political winds have shifted from business to national security”. The article discusses various Clinton Administration initiatives related to encryption, and highlighted quotes from Congress members who “called for a global prohibition on encryption products without backdoors for government surveillance”.</description></item><item><title>Disputes on Electronic Message Encryption Take on New Urgency</title><link>/entries/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-6dfb72b1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-6dfb72b1/</guid><description>Authors: Schwartz, John
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2001/09/25/business/disputes-on-electronic-message-encryption-take-on-new-urgency.html
Abstract: This article, Disputes on Electronic Message Encryption Take on New Urgency, written by John Schwartz and published in the New York Times shortly after 9/11, describes how the attack on the World Trade Center, and the possibility that the attackers used encrypted communications in the planning and execution of the attack, renewed debate on law enforcement access to encrypted technologies. The article describes the applicability of key escrow and the Clipper Chip to accessing encrypted communications, and legislative proposals for access proposed in the days after 9/11.</description></item><item><title>Encryption under fire: discussion on threats to private messaging w/ Head of WhatsApp Will Cathcart</title><link>/entries/encryption-under-fire-discussion-on-threats-to-pri-6bbe4ed7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-under-fire-discussion-on-threats-to-pri-6bbe4ed7/</guid><description>Published: July 2020
URL: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y1LSFQo_07w</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Lawful Electronic Surveillance in the Face of New Technologies</title><link>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-5165cb74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-5165cb74/</guid><description>Authors: Valerie Caproni
Published: February 2011
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/testimony/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-face-of-new-technologies
Abstract: On February 17, 2001, Valeria Caproni, General Counsel, Federal Bureau of Investigation, testified before the House Judiciary Committee, Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security. In her testimony, Caproni discussed the “Going Dark” problem facing law enforcement. The “legal authorities [the FBI has] for intercepting electronic communications are adequate”, but the government often does not have the “practical ability to actually intercept those communications”.</description></item></channel></rss>