<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CLOUD Act on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/cloud-act/</link><description>Recent content in CLOUD Act on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/cloud-act/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>H.R. 4943 - Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act</title><link>/entries/h-r-4943-clarifying-lawful-overseas-use-of-data-ac-f1395da4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/h-r-4943-clarifying-lawful-overseas-use-of-data-ac-f1395da4/</guid><description>Authors: Collins, Doug
Published: February 2018
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/4943
Abstract: On February 6, 2018, Representatives Collins, Jeffries, Issa, DelBene, Marino, Rutherford and Demings introduced H.R. 4943, the “Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act” or the “CLOUD Act.” H.R. 4943 amends title 18 of the United States federal criminal code to “improve law enforcement access to data stored across borders, and for other purposes.” The bill requires electronic communication service (ECS) and remote computer service (RCS) providers to comply with existing preservation, backup and disclosure requirements pertaining to contents of electronic communications and any record or other information pertaining to a customer or subscriber within their possession, regardless of whether the information is located within the United States.</description></item><item><title>Promoting Public Saftey, Privacy, and the Rule of Law Around the World: The Purpose and Impact of the CLOUD Act</title><link>/entries/promoting-public-saftey-privacy-and-the-rule-of-la-062fe8ee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/promoting-public-saftey-privacy-and-the-rule-of-la-062fe8ee/</guid><description>Published: April 2019
Abstract: In April 2019, the Department of Justice published this White Paper on the purpose and impact of the CLOUD Act. The Paper explains the CLOUD Act was enacted to speed access to electronic information held by U.S.-based global providers (communications service providers, “CSPs”) that is critical to foreign partners’ investigations of serious crimes. Specifically, the CLOUD Act is designed to permit those “foreign partners that have robust protections for privacy and civil liberties to enter into executive agreements with the United States to obtain access” this electronic information and evidence.</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Encryption</title><link>/entries/rethinking-encryption-b0065e9b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/rethinking-encryption-b0065e9b/</guid><description>Authors: Baker, Jim
Published: October 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/rethinking-encryption
Abstract: This article written by Jim Baker encourages law enforcement officials in the U.S. to embrace encryption due to cybersecurity threats, particularly from china. The article begins by describing the issues of going dark to law enforcement, and quotes officials such as Attorney General William Barr encouraging Congress to legislate around encryption. However, because Congress has failed to act in light of such pressures, it is possible action will never occur.</description></item></channel></rss>