<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amendment IV on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/amendment-iv/</link><description>Recent content in Amendment IV on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/amendment-iv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Attorney General William P. Barr Delivers Keynote Address at the International Conference on Cyber Security</title><link>/entries/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-a-55f805a8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-a-55f805a8/</guid><description>Authors: Barr, William
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/attorney-general-william-p-barr-delivers-keynote-address-international-conference-cyber
Abstract: Former Attorney General William Barr delivered the keynote address at the International Conference on Cyber Security in 2019. In the speech, Barr describes encryption as a technology that gives cover to criminals, particularly drug cartels, and prevents law enforcement from solving crimes. Barr insinuates that the Fourth Amendment, through balancing personal privacy and public safety, may not allow so-called “warrant-proof encryption” and requests backdoors be added to encryption to allow law enforcement access to encrypted messages through pursuant to warrants.</description></item><item><title>Protecting the Fourth Amendment in the Information Age: A Response to Robert Litt</title><link>/entries/protecting-the-fourth-amendment-in-the-information-5c78fc7e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/protecting-the-fourth-amendment-in-the-information-5c78fc7e/</guid><description>Authors: Cohn, Cindy
Published: 2016
Abstract: On July 27, 2016, the Yale Law Journal Forum published a short essay that agrees in part and disagrees in part with Robert Litt’s, General Counsel of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, “new analysis for the Fourth Amendment in the Information Age”. The author rejected Litt’s proposal that the “reasonable expectation of privacy” test “should simply be eliminated”, and analyzed why Litt’s proposed balancing test is not a suitable replacement.</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Encryption</title><link>/entries/rethinking-encryption-b0065e9b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/rethinking-encryption-b0065e9b/</guid><description>Authors: Baker, Jim
Published: October 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/rethinking-encryption
Abstract: This article written by Jim Baker encourages law enforcement officials in the U.S. to embrace encryption due to cybersecurity threats, particularly from china. The article begins by describing the issues of going dark to law enforcement, and quotes officials such as Attorney General William Barr encouraging Congress to legislate around encryption. However, because Congress has failed to act in light of such pressures, it is possible action will never occur.</description></item><item><title>the People of the State of Colorado v. Shaun R. Davis</title><link>/entries/the-people-of-the-state-of-colorado-v-shaun-r-davi-ca69bf48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-people-of-the-state-of-colorado-v-shaun-r-davi-ca69bf48/</guid><description>Published: April 2019
Abstract: In Colorado v. Davis, the Colorado Supreme Court held that using a passcode given to police officers to execute a search warrant on a smartphone did not violate the Fourth Amendment. In this case, a criminal defendant had given his cellphone passcode to police officers during his arrest so they could call his girlfriend. Later, after law enforcement received a warrant to search the phone, the passcode was used to search the phone.</description></item></channel></rss>