<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clipper Chip on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/clipper-chip/</link><description>Recent content in Clipper Chip on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/clipper-chip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Clipper Chip to Smartphones: Unlocking the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-enc-cbe23268/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-enc-cbe23268/</guid><description>Authors: Flatow, Ira
URL: https://www.sciencefriday.com/segments/from-clipper-chip-to-smartphones-unlocking-the-encryption-debate/
Abstract: This Podcast features comments made by security experts and privacy advocates made in the 1990s about the Clipper Chip. It offers a look back into what the policy discussion looked like concurrently with the Clipper Chip proposals. Some of those who previously made comments offer follow-up, looking back at the development of their views and policy positions and how they have developed in the intervening years.</description></item><item><title>It Came from Planet Clipper: The Battle Over Cryptographic Key "Escrow"</title><link>/entries/it-came-from-planet-clipper-the-battle-over-crypto-351f4ef6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/it-came-from-planet-clipper-the-battle-over-crypto-351f4ef6/</guid><description>Authors: Froomkin, A Michael
Published: 1996
Abstract: In 1996, the University of Chicago Legal Forum published an article about the various phases of “the U.S. government’s recent attempts to keep the cryptography genie in the bottle in the face of increasing commercial and political pressure to loosen or abolish cryptographic export control.” The article discusses the export control regime for cryptography, the changing goals of U.S. cryptography policy, a summary of the Clipper chip initiative, an overview of the proposal for software-based key escrow, an in-depth exploration of “recent technical and political changes that make the current export control policy increasingly difficult to maintain”, and concludes with a discussion of trust and Congress’ role in this policy formation.</description></item><item><title>Security “Front Doors” vs. “Back Doors”: A Distinction Without a Difference</title><link>/entries/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-a-distinction-w-27fb709b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-a-distinction-w-27fb709b/</guid><description>Authors: Jeffrey Vagle, Matt Blaze
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.justsecurity.org/16503/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-distinction-difference/
Abstract: This article by Jeffrey Vagle and Matt Blaze discusses FBI Director James Comey’s speeches calling for back doors in encryption for law enforcement and argues that it is technologically infeasible and politically wise. The article details how back doors will eventually be uncovered and lead to vulnerabilities in systems. Finally, the article argues that the language being used to advocate for back doors builds a false sense of security in populations unfamiliar with the technological realities and leads people away from more workable solutions.</description></item><item><title>The Clipper Chip</title><link>/entries/the-clipper-chip-edd3daa1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-clipper-chip-edd3daa1/</guid><description>Authors: Electronic Privacy Information Center
Published: 1994
URL: https://epic.org/crypto/clipper/
Abstract: This announcement regarding the Clipper Chip announces the Electronic Privacy Information Center’s attempt to challenge the national security classification of the Clipper Chip algorithm, so the algorithm may be evaluated by civilians. It provides a guide to the relevant documents explaining the organization’s positions.</description></item><item><title>The Metaphor is the Key: Cryptography, The Clipper Chip, and the Constitution</title><link>/entries/the-metaphor-is-the-key-cryptography-the-clipper-c-9a3caf0b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-metaphor-is-the-key-cryptography-the-clipper-c-9a3caf0b/</guid><description>Authors: Froomkin, Michael A.
Published: 1996
URL: http://osaka.law.miami.edu/~froomkin/articles/clipper.htm</description></item></channel></rss>