<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CALEA on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/calea/</link><description>Recent content in CALEA on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/calea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deep Dive into Crypto “Exceptional Access” Mandates: Effective or Constitutional—Pick One</title><link>/entries/108/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/108/</guid><description>Authors: and
Published: August 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/08/deep-dive-crypto-exceptional-access-mandates-effective-or-constitutional-pick-one
Tags: 2010s CALEA Abstract: Readers of these pages will be familiar with the debate going on between government officials and technologists around the world about law enforcement’s perceived need to access the content of any and all encrypted communications.[fn]This debate often combines and indeed confuses encryption of&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>FAQ on the FCC CALEA Expansion</title><link>/entries/185/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/185/</guid><description>Published: 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/issues/calea
Tags: 1990s 2000s 2010s CALEA Abstract: The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994 Congress passed the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) in 1994, which forced telephone companies to redesign their network architectures to make it easier for law enforcement to wiretap digital telephone calls. In 2005, CALEA was expanded by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to include Internet service providers (ISPs) and VoIP services like Skype.</description></item><item><title>FBI Pressuring Google, Facebook to Allow ‘Back Doors’ for Wiretapping</title><link>/entries/174/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/174/</guid><description>Authors: Daniel Tencer
Published: November 2010
URL: https://www.rawstory.com/2010/11/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-wiretapping/
Tags: 2010s Backdoors CALEA Going Dark Government Access</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Lawful Electronic Surveillance in the Face of New Technologies</title><link>/entries/172/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/172/</guid><description>Authors: Valerie Caproni
Published: February 2011
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/testimony/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-face-of-new-technologies
Tags: 2010s CALEA Going Dark National Security Terrorism Abstract: Statement Before the House Judiciary Committee, Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security</description></item><item><title>U.S. Tries to Make It Easier to Wiretap the Internet</title><link>/entries/153/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/153/</guid><description>Authors: Savage, Charlie
Published: September 2010
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2010/09/27/us/27wiretap.html
Tags: 2010s CALEA Going Dark Government Access Mobile Surveillance Abstract: Officials are preparing to seek sweeping new regulations, arguing they are losing their capability to track suspects.</description></item></channel></rss>