<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CALEA on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/calea/</link><description>Recent content in CALEA on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/calea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deep Dive into Crypto “Exceptional Access” Mandates: Effective or Constitutional—Pick One</title><link>/entries/deep-dive-into-crypto-exceptional-access-mandates-4ed0e169/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/deep-dive-into-crypto-exceptional-access-mandates-4ed0e169/</guid><description>Authors: Cardozo, Nate and Crocker, Andrew
Published: August 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/08/deep-dive-crypto-exceptional-access-mandates-effective-or-constitutional-pick-one
Abstract: Deep Dive into Crypto “Exceptional Access” Mandates: Effective or Constitutional—Pick One by Andrew Crocker and Nate Cardozo argues that any exceptional access mandate would violate the First Amendment. The article is responding to a plethora of news coverage, citing law enforcement officials and detailing law enforcement’s need for “exceptional access” to allow government access to all encrypted materials. The article next argues that any exceptional access would require government control over the development of encryption software, which is speech, and would therefore violate the First Amendment’s ban on prior restraint.</description></item><item><title>FAQ on the FCC CALEA Expansion</title><link>/entries/faq-on-the-fcc-calea-expansion-cb61ed55/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/faq-on-the-fcc-calea-expansion-cb61ed55/</guid><description>Published: 2015
URL: https://www.eff.org/issues/calea
Abstract: In 2014 the Electronic Frontier Foundation published an article on the evolving history of the The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994. Initially, CALEA “forced telephone companies to redesign their network architectures to make it easier for law enforcement to wiretap digital telephone calls.” In 2004, several law enforcement agencies petitioned the FCC to expand the scope of CALEA to all Internet communications services, and the FCC issued a final rule which expanded CALEA “to broadband Internet access providers and managed VoIP systems.</description></item><item><title>FBI Pressuring Google, Facebook to Allow ‘Back Doors’ for Wiretapping</title><link>/entries/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-to-allow-back-doors-71473338/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-to-allow-back-doors-71473338/</guid><description>Authors: Daniel Tencer
Published: November 2010
URL: https://www.rawstory.com/2010/11/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-wiretapping/
Abstract: On November 17, 2010, Raw Story published an article discussing the debate surrounding a proposed expansion of The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994. At the time, FBI Director Robert Mueller placed pressure on technology companies to build “back doors” which would “allow law enforcement to wiretap data on their networks”, in an effort “to expand the FBI’s wiretapping powers to include the latest communications technologies, including social networking sites, voice-over-Internet (VoIP) telephone services and BlackBerries.</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Lawful Electronic Surveillance in the Face of New Technologies</title><link>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-5165cb74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-5165cb74/</guid><description>Authors: Valerie Caproni
Published: February 2011
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/testimony/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-face-of-new-technologies
Abstract: On February 17, 2001, Valeria Caproni, General Counsel, Federal Bureau of Investigation, testified before the House Judiciary Committee, Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security. In her testimony, Caproni discussed the “Going Dark” problem facing law enforcement. The “legal authorities [the FBI has] for intercepting electronic communications are adequate”, but the government often does not have the “practical ability to actually intercept those communications”.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Tries to Make It Easier to Wiretap the Internet</title><link>/entries/u-s-tries-to-make-it-easier-to-wiretap-the-interne-7c6b8243/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/u-s-tries-to-make-it-easier-to-wiretap-the-interne-7c6b8243/</guid><description>Authors: Savage, Charlie
Published: September 2010
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2010/09/27/us/27wiretap.html
Abstract: This New York Times article by Charlie Savage reports on planned legislation by the Obama administration which would allow for the US government to decrypt select communications and prevent going dark. The article discusses how encryption has worked in recent law enforcement investigations, and why the government finds such a technology necessary. The article discusses the feasibility of different possible elements of the proposed law, including attempting to regulate encryption technology coming from abroad.</description></item></channel></rss>