<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Keys on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/keys/</link><description>Recent content in Keys on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/keys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Demystifying U.S. Encryption Export Controls</title><link>/entries/131/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/131/</guid><description>Published: 1996
URL: https://heinonline.org/HOL/P?h=hein.journals/aulr46&amp;amp;i=507</description></item><item><title>Feds put heat on Web firms for master encryption keys</title><link>/entries/166/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/166/</guid><description>Published: July 2013
URL: https://www.cnet.com/news/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-keys/
Abstract: Whether the FBI and NSA have the legal authority to obtain the master keys that companies use for Web encryption remains an open question, but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t stopped the U.S. government from trying.</description></item><item><title>How secure is AES against brute force attacks?</title><link>/entries/39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/39/</guid><description>Published: May 2012
URL: https://www.eetimes.com/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks/
Abstract: This article describes the strength of the cryptographic system against brute force attacks with different key sizes and the time it takes to successfully mount a brute force attack factoring future advancements in processing speeds.</description></item><item><title>mandating insecurity by requiring government access to all data and communications</title><link>/entries/171/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/171/</guid><description>Published: July 2015
Abstract: Twenty years ago, law enforcement organizations lobbied to require data and communication services to engineer their products to guarantee law enforcement access to all data. After lengthy debate and vigorous predictions of enforcement channels “going dark,” these attempts to regulate the emerging Internet were abandoned. In the intervening years, innovation on the Internet ﬂourished, and law enforcement agencies found new and more eﬀective means of accessing vastly larger quantities of data.</description></item></channel></rss>