<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Keys on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/keys/</link><description>Recent content in Keys on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/keys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Demystifying U.S. Encryption Export Controls</title><link>/entries/demystifying-u-s-encryption-export-controls-22620d22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/demystifying-u-s-encryption-export-controls-22620d22/</guid><description>Authors: James B. Altman, William McGlone
Published: 1996
URL: https://heinonline.org/HOL/P?h=hein.journals/aulr46&amp;amp;i=507
Abstract: This 1996 law review article by James Altman and William McGlone seeks to offer practical insights on export controls of encryption software and the underlying policy consideration. First, this article establishes the landscape of encryption in global business and trade. Second, the article explains the U.S. export controls and licensing requirements in place in 1996, including the scope of laws, agency jurisdiction.</description></item><item><title>Feds Put Heat on Web Firms for Master Encryption Keys</title><link>/entries/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-k-c6363e83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-k-c6363e83/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: July 2013
URL: https://www.cnet.com/news/feds-put-heat-on-web-firms-for-master-encryption-keys/
Abstract: In July of 2013, Declan McCullagh, a senior writer for CNET, wrote regarding the continued effort of major U.S. intelligence agencies (the FBI and NSA) to obtain master encryption (SSL) keys used by internet service providers to shield private communications. McCullagh referred to the efforts of the U.S. government as a “technological escalation in the clandestine methods that the FBI and National Security Agency employ when conducting electronic surveillance against Internet users,” and warned of the sheer scope of the information which could be intercepted if such a key were turned over.</description></item><item><title>How secure is AES Against Brute Force Attacks?</title><link>/entries/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks-a76070ac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks-a76070ac/</guid><description>Authors: Arora, Mohit
Published: May 2012
URL: https://www.eetimes.com/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks/
Abstract: In May of 2012, Mohit Arora, Sr. Systems Engineer &amp;amp; Security Architect for Freescale Semiconductor, wrote for the EE Times regarding the security of Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) against brute force attacks. Arora analyzed the system’s strength against brute force attacks with different key sizes and projected advancements in processing speeds. Ultimately, Arora concluded that “even with a supercomputer, it would take 1 billion years to crack the 128-bit AES keying using [a] brute force attack,” and thus deemed AES “safe against any brute force attack.</description></item><item><title>Keys Under Doormats: Mandating Insecurity by Requiring Government Access to All Data and Communications</title><link>/entries/keys-under-doormats-mandating-insecurity-by-requir-5df4f072/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/keys-under-doormats-mandating-insecurity-by-requir-5df4f072/</guid><description>Authors: Abelson, Harold and Anderson, Ross and Bellovin, Steven M and Benaloh, Josh and Blaze, Matt and Diffie, Whitﬁeld and Gilmore, John and Green, Matthew and Landau, Susan and Neumann, Peter G and Rivest, Ronald L and Schiller, Jeﬀrey I and Schneier, Bruce and Specter, Michael and Weitzner, Daniel J
Published: July 2015
URL: https://dspace.mit.edu/bitstream/handle/1721.1/97690/MIT-CSAIL-TR-2015-026.pdf
Abstract: On July 7, 2015, a group of computer scientists and security experts published a study to ascertain the likely effects of renewed attempts to mandate back doors of all data for law enforcement.</description></item></channel></rss>