<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Canada on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/canada/</link><description>Recent content in Canada on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/canada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>'Five Eyes' Security Alliance Calls for Access to Encrypted Material</title><link>/entries/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/18/</guid><description>Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.reuters.com/article/us-security-fiveeyes-britain-idUSKCN1UP199
Abstract: The U.S.-led &amp;ldquo;Five Eyes&amp;rdquo; intelligence alliance said on Tuesday that te&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>A Cryptography Policy Framework for Electronic Commerce: Building Canada's Information Economy and Society</title><link>/entries/114/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/114/</guid><description>Published: 1998</description></item><item><title>Encryption Policy a Crowd Pleaser</title><link>/entries/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/27/</guid><description>Authors: Jeff Leiper
Published: November 1998
URL: http://search.proquest.com/docview/217686754?pq-origsite=summon
Abstract: At a meeting earlier this year by concerned industry players, the government was told that proposed restrictions were impractical because criminals had access to offshore encryption products. Further, the wait for a concrete policy was hurting business because companies were unsure of what they&amp;rsquo;d be allowed to sell. Shipping delays were costing money, officials from companies like kyberpass Corp. insisted. At the time, officials weren&amp;rsquo;t entirely frustrated.</description></item><item><title>The Five Eyes Statement on Encryption: Things Are Seldom What They Seem</title><link>/entries/144/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/144/</guid><description>Published: September 2018
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/five-eyes-statement-encryption-things-are-seldom-what-they-seem
Abstract: Earlier this September, law enforcement officials from the Five Eyes intelligence alliance—made up of Australia, Canada, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, and the United States—met in Australia and issued a Statement of Principles on Access to Evidence and Encryption.</description></item></channel></rss>