<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lawfare on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/lawfare/</link><description>Recent content in Lawfare on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/lawfare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Judicial Framework for Evaluating Network Investigative Techniques</title><link>/entries/90/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/90/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey, Nicholas Weaver
Published: July 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/judicial-framework-evaluating-network-investigative-techniques
Abstract: At Motherboard, Joseph Cox reports that defense attorneys representing dozens of defendants nabbed in an FBI child pornography sting have pooled their resources in a “national working group.” A Network Investigative Technique (NIT) conducted on the child pornography website Playpen resulted in the arrest of well over 100 perpetrators, many of whom are now arguing their cases in court.</description></item><item><title>Encryption, Biometrics, and the Status Quo Ante</title><link>/entries/78/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/78/</guid><description>Authors: Rosenzweig, Paul
Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/encryption-biometrics-and-status-quo-ante
Abstract: As the recent indirect debate between FBI Director James Comey and co-blogger Susan Landau makes clear, the underlying premises of the encryption issue are highly contested. The Senate will continue the debate this week with a hearing before the Judiciary Committee on July 8 at which our own Herb Lin (among others) will testify and another hearing before the Intelligence Committee.</description></item><item><title>NSA Isn’t the Going Dark Solution, Part I: Richard Clarke Gets It Wrong</title><link>/entries/65/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/65/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/nsa-isnt-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-clarke-gets-it-wrong
Abstract: Let’s start with a point that will be significant emotional satisfaction to many readers: Richard Clarke was dead wrong. In a remarkable statement last week, the former Clinton and early Bush administration counterterrorism official told NPR’s Morning Edition:</description></item><item><title>NSA Isn’t the Going Dark Solution, Part II: There’s No Such Thing As Magic</title><link>/entries/64/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/64/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/nsa-isnt-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-such-thing-magic
Abstract: In Part I of this series, I noted the tendency of commentators—without any actual knowledge—to assert that NSA could simply break into a given locked iPhone.</description></item><item><title>Questions for Apple</title><link>/entries/60/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/60/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey, Benjamin Wittes
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/questions-apple
Abstract: The House Judiciary Committee at 1:00 pm is holding a hearing at which FBI Director James Comey and Apple General Counsel Bruce Sewell will both testify on going dark matters. Here&amp;rsquo;s the live video: The other day, Stewart Baker wrote this sardonic but serious piece in which he posed some questions for Apple. We have a few of our own:</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Encryption</title><link>/entries/172/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/172/</guid><description>Authors: Baker, Jim
Published: October 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/rethinking-encryption
Abstract: I. Embrace Reality and Deal With It</description></item></channel></rss>