<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>World News on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/world-news/</link><description>Recent content in World News on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/world-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Revealed: How US and UK Spy Agencies Defeat Internet Privacy and Security</title><link>/entries/140/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/140/</guid><description>Authors: Ball, James and Borger, Julian and Greenwald, Glenn
Published: September 2013
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/sep/05/nsa-gchq-encryption-codes-security
Tags: 2010s Data and Computer Security GCHQ Intelligence NSA Surveillance The NSA files UK News World News Abstract: • NSA and GCHQ unlock encryption used to protect emails, banking and medical records• $250m-a-year US program works covertly with tech companies to insert weaknesses into products• Security experts say programs &amp;lsquo;undermine the fabric of the internet&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>Secret US Cybersecurity Report: Encryption Vital to Protect Private Data</title><link>/entries/57/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/57/</guid><description>Authors: Ball, James
Published: January 2015
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/jan/15/-sp-secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-protect-data-cameron-paris-attacks
Tags: 2010s GCHQ NSA National Security Snowden Surveillance The NSA files UK News UK Security and Counter-Terrorism World News Abstract: Newly uncovered Snowden document contrasts with British PM’s vow to crack down on encrypted messaging after Paris attacks</description></item><item><title>SS7 Hack Explained: What Can You Do About It?</title><link>/entries/59/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/59/</guid><description>Authors: Gibbs, Samuel
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/apr/19/ss7-hack-explained-mobile-phone-vulnerability-snooping-texts-calls
Tags: 2020s Data and Computer Security Hacking Mobile SS7 Surveillance Telecoms World News Abstract: A vulnerability means hackers can read texts, listen to calls and track mobile phone users. What are the implications and how can you protect yourself from snooping?</description></item></channel></rss>