<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Australia on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/australia/</link><description>Recent content in Australia on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/australia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Australian Government Passes Contentious Encryption Law</title><link>/entries/australian-government-passes-contentious-encryptio-6d9e9517/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/australian-government-passes-contentious-encryptio-6d9e9517/</guid><description>Authors: Tarabay, Jamie
Published: June 2018
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/06/world/australia/encryption-bill-nauru.html
Abstract: On December 6, 2018, the New York Times published an article about Australia’s passage of the Telecommunications and Other Legislation Amendment (Assistance and Access) Act 2018 (TOLA Act), which requires technology companies to grant law enforcement access to encrypted messages. The article’s main focus was relaying the arguments of the opponents and proponents of the bill. Opponents of the bill believe it compromises the privacy of Australians, could lead to abuse, and will encourage other countries to follow suit.</description></item><item><title>Big reputation: What the Australian Parliament Can Learn from Taylor Swift</title><link>/entries/big-reputation-what-the-australian-parliament-can-642ff3e3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/big-reputation-what-the-australian-parliament-can-642ff3e3/</guid><description>Authors: Stepanovich, Amie
Published: February 2019
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/big-reputation-what-the-australian-parliament-can-learn-from-taylor-swift/
Abstract: On January 26, 2019, Access Now published an article about Australia’s passage of the draconian Telecommunications and Other Legislation Amendment (Assistance and Access Bill) Act 2018, which requires technology companies to grant law enforcement hack devices and access to encrypted messages, without judicial oversight. At the time the article was written, the bill called for further review, which opened up the potential to add “amendments, safeguards, and transparency requirements” to the bill.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to Members of Australia's Parliament</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-members-of-australia-s-parliam-65b62b0b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-members-of-australia-s-parliam-65b62b0b/</guid><description>Published: July 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/07/Australia-Encryption-Coalition-Letter.pdf
Abstract: On July 17, 2018 a coalition of domestic and international organizations and experts sent a letter to Australia’s parliament, urging it to not pass the Telecommunications and Other Legislation Amendment (Assistance and Access) Act 2018 (TOLA Act), which would require technology companies to grant law enforcement access to encrypted messages. The letter stresses the direct and indirect consequences of Australia’s proposed TOLA Act, should it pass.</description></item><item><title>The Role of Encryption in Australia</title><link>/entries/the-role-of-encryption-in-australia-4e0f543e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-role-of-encryption-in-australia-4e0f543e/</guid><description>Authors: O&amp;rsquo;Shea, Lizzie and Thomas, Elise
Published: January 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/01/Crypto-Australia-Memo.pdf
Abstract: Encryption is essential to Australia’s modern digital society, economy, and cyber security, and it is only effective if it is strong and robust.
Strong encryption serves Australia’s national interests by protecting governments, communities, and the economy from criminal, terrorist, and state-sponsored attacks.
Encryption will only become more important for protecting Australian interests as technology advances in the coming decades.</description></item></channel></rss>