<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Regulated Encryption on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/regulated-encryption/</link><description>Recent content in Regulated Encryption on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/regulated-encryption/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Last Refuge of the Criminal: Encrypted Smartphones</title><link>/entries/the-last-refuge-of-the-criminal-encrypted-smartpho-ba7ee311/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-last-refuge-of-the-criminal-encrypted-smartpho-ba7ee311/</guid><description>Authors: de Bolle, Catherine, Vance, Cyrus R., Jr.
Published: July 2021
URL: https://www.politico.eu/article/the-last-refuge-of-the-criminal-encrypted-smartphones-data-privacy/
Abstract: Catherine de Bolle and Cyrus R. Vance, Jr., write in Politico that encrypted devices—particularly encrypted smartphones—pose an intolerable impediment to law enforcement, the pursuit of justice, and vindication of victims and their families. They argue that criminals exploit unregulated encryption to perpetrate a variety of crimes, from ransomware to child sex trafficking, and that the ability to lawfully access devices is overwhelmingly frustrated by judges, policies, and budgets.</description></item><item><title>We Need More Protection from Government Surveillance — Not Less</title><link>/entries/we-need-more-protection-from-government-surveillan-3c66d9c0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/we-need-more-protection-from-government-surveillan-3c66d9c0/</guid><description>Authors: McGowan, Iverna and Naranjo, Diego and Koomen, Maria and Beltrà, Guillermo and Preiss, Omri and Massé, Estelle and Cohn, Cindy and Stollmeyer, Alice and Bukovská, Barbora and Dusepulchre, Gaelle and Anderson, Andrew and Skoric, Vanja and Westby, Joe and Keller, Paul
Published: July 2021
URL: https://www.politico.eu/article/we-need-more-protection-government-surveillance-not-less/
Abstract: A group of user- and human-rights advocates jointly write an article published by Politico in response to Catherine de Bolle and Cyrus R.</description></item></channel></rss>