<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Backdoors-Feasibility on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/backdoors-feasibility/</link><description>Recent content in Backdoors-Feasibility on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/backdoors-feasibility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Security “Front Doors” vs. “Back Doors”: A Distinction Without a Difference</title><link>/entries/150/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/150/</guid><description>Authors: Jeffrey Vagle, Matt Blaze
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.justsecurity.org/16503/security-front-doors-vs-back-doors-distinction-difference/
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Backdoors-Feasibility Clipper Chip Golden Key James Comey Law Enforcement Mobile Abstract: Thursday, FBI Director James Comey delivered a talk at the Brookings Institution, titled “Going Dark: Are Technology, Privacy, and Public Safety on a Collision Course?” His thesis did not stray too far from his (and others’) recent calls for limitations on software from companies like Google and Apple that employs strong cryptography that even the …</description></item><item><title>The NSA’s Split-Key Encryption Proposal is Not Serious</title><link>/entries/144/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/144/</guid><description>Authors: Joseph Lorenzo Hall
Published: April 2015
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-serious/
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Backdoors-Feasibility Center for Democracy and Technology Foreign Concerns Going Dark Abstract: The US Government has been busy on the encryption front in both positive and negative ways. On the positive front, there is a major effort underway to move all government websites to HTTPS; I’ll discuss that in a future post. But on the problematic and negative side of the ledger, we once again turn to …</description></item></channel></rss>