<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Access Now on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/access-now/</link><description>Recent content in Access Now on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/access-now/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 10/27/2016</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</guid><description>Published: October 2016
Abstract: On October 27, 2016, a coalition of domestic organizations and experts sent a letter to President Barack Obama in which they urged the White House to respond to a petition using the Administration&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;We the People&amp;rdquo; platform. The petition asked that the Administration &amp;ldquo;[p]ublicly affirm your support for strong encryption,” to “[r]eject any law, policy, or mandate that would undermine our security” online, and to &amp;ldquo;encourage other governments worldwide to do the same.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Summit 2.0 Outcomes Report Track 1</title><link>/entries/crypto-summit-2-0-outcomes-report-track-1-f3204001/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/crypto-summit-2-0-outcomes-report-track-1-f3204001/</guid><description>Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2016/07/CS2.0_Outcomes_Track1.pdf
Abstract: AccessNow published a summary of the Crypto Summit 2.0, the second of two summits, which occurred on March 30, 2016 in Silicon Valley. The goal of this conference was to build off the key questions identified in Crypto Summit 1.0. The group identified four policy tracks to focus on in the second summit. The first policy track entails the “roles and responsibilities in an encrypted world”.</description></item><item><title>Encryption in the U.S.: Crypto Colloquium Outcomes Report</title><link>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</guid><description>Published: January 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/02/Encryption-in-the-United-States-Crypto-Colloquium-Outcomes-Report.pdf
Abstract: In September of 2017, Access Now, a non-profit dedicated to human rights advocacy in the digital age, hosted the Crypto Colloquium—an invite-only dialogue of civil society, academic experts, technology companies and former U.S. government officials—to discuss challenges associated with U.S. government agencies’ inability to access information on encrypted mobile phones. The Report, produced by Access Now, provides a summary of the key takeaways from the Colloquium, including a section on the “Lessons Learned” in each of the Law and Policy, Security, and Economics sectors.</description></item><item><title>The Role of Encryption in Australia</title><link>/entries/the-role-of-encryption-in-australia-4e0f543e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-role-of-encryption-in-australia-4e0f543e/</guid><description>Authors: O&amp;rsquo;Shea, Lizzie and Thomas, Elise
Published: January 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/01/Crypto-Australia-Memo.pdf
Abstract: Encryption is essential to Australia’s modern digital society, economy, and cyber security, and it is only effective if it is strong and robust.
Strong encryption serves Australia’s national interests by protecting governments, communities, and the economy from criminal, terrorist, and state-sponsored attacks.
Encryption will only become more important for protecting Australian interests as technology advances in the coming decades.</description></item></channel></rss>