<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Five Eyes on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/five-eyes/</link><description>Recent content in Five Eyes on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/five-eyes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>'Five Eyes' Security Alliance Calls for Access to Encrypted Material</title><link>/entries/five-eyes-security-alliance-calls-for-access-to-en-c3db0c94/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/five-eyes-security-alliance-calls-for-access-to-en-c3db0c94/</guid><description>Authors: Hosenball, Mark and Holden, Michael
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.reuters.com/article/us-security-fiveeyes-britain-idUSKCN1UP199
Abstract: In July of 2019, Reuters Staff reported on a statement made that week by the Five Eyes Intelligence Alliance that “Tech companies should include mechanisms in the design of their encrypted products and services whereby governments, acting with appropriate legal authority, can obtain access to data in a readable and usable format.” Following a two-day summit in London, the five allied States reached an agreement with tech industry officials to “collaborate with the Five Eyes on a set of voluntary principles .</description></item><item><title>Australian Government Passes Contentious Encryption Law</title><link>/entries/australian-government-passes-contentious-encryptio-6d9e9517/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/australian-government-passes-contentious-encryptio-6d9e9517/</guid><description>Authors: Tarabay, Jamie
Published: June 2018
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/06/world/australia/encryption-bill-nauru.html
Abstract: On December 6, 2018, the New York Times published an article about Australia’s passage of the Telecommunications and Other Legislation Amendment (Assistance and Access) Act 2018 (TOLA Act), which requires technology companies to grant law enforcement access to encrypted messages. The article’s main focus was relaying the arguments of the opponents and proponents of the bill. Opponents of the bill believe it compromises the privacy of Australians, could lead to abuse, and will encourage other countries to follow suit.</description></item><item><title>Canada’s New and Irresponsible Encryption Policy: How the Government of Canada’s New Policy Threatens Charter Rights, Cybersecurity, Economic Growth, and Foreign Policy</title><link>/entries/canadas-new-and-irresponsible-encryption-policy-ho-c1d6da72/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/canadas-new-and-irresponsible-encryption-policy-ho-c1d6da72/</guid><description>Authors: Parsons, Christopher
Published: August 2019
URL: https://citizenlab.ca/2019/08/canadas-new-and-irresponsible-encryption-policy-how-the-government-of-canadas-new-policy-threatens-charter-rights-cybersecurity-economic-growth-and-foreign-policy/
Abstract: This article by Christopher Parsons argues that a 2019 Canadian ministerial communique weakens encryption. First, the article provides background on the history of Canadian encryption policy and the 2019 ministerial communique, and how its proposed policy would weaken encryption and require that private companies add backdoors for the Canadian government. Next, the article details the government&amp;rsquo;s justifications for the policy, and how they fail to justify the weakening of encryption.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to Ministers Responsible for the Five Eyes Security Community</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-ministers-responsible-for-the-c239cb16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-ministers-responsible-for-the-c239cb16/</guid><description>Published: June 2017
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2017/07/Five-eyes-open-letter.pdf
Abstract: In June of 2017, a coalition of 83 civil society organizations and eminent individuals wrote to the Ministers Responsible for the Five Eyes Security Community to “emphasize the importance of national policies that encourage and facilitate the development and use of strong encryption.” The coalition expressed concern with a joint communiqué – published following a Five Eyes meeting – expressing a commitment to exploring solutions to the “perceived impediment posed by encryption to investigative objectives” and plans “to press technology firms to share encrypted data with security agencies.</description></item><item><title>The Five Eyes Statement on Encryption: Things Are Seldom What They Seem</title><link>/entries/the-five-eyes-statement-on-encryption-things-are-s-be5639a2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-five-eyes-statement-on-encryption-things-are-s-be5639a2/</guid><description>Authors: Landau, Susan
Published: September 2018
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/five-eyes-statement-encryption-things-are-seldom-what-they-seem
Abstract: This report from Lawfare details a summit of law enforcement officials from the Five Eyes intelligence alliance—made up of Australia, Canada, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, and the United States—and argues that the rhetoric espoused was far less troubling than it seemed. At the summit, Australian officials detailed an aggressive stance against encryption. However, by ignoring technical realities, the policy proposals are rendered toothless.</description></item><item><title>Travel Guide to the Digital World: Encryption Policy for Human Rights Defenders</title><link>/entries/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-encryption-polic-2d5134d2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-encryption-polic-2d5134d2/</guid><description>Authors: Global Partners Digital
Published: 2017
URL: https://www.gp-digital.org/publication/travel-guide-to-the-digital-world-4-encryption-policy-for-human-rights-defenders/
Abstract: This is a guide, aimed at a non-technical audience, seeking to explain the connection between human rights and encryption. The article gives a background on the basics of encryption, and how it affects the day-to-day life of people around the globe, and its impacts on privacy and freedom of expression. Finally, the article outlines the legal and policy background of encryption regulation across the globe and at the international, national, and local levels.</description></item><item><title>“Five Eyes” Governments Respond to Coalition Demands to Stop Undermining Encryption</title><link>/entries/five-eyes-governments-respond-to-coalition-demands-c670f1bb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/five-eyes-governments-respond-to-coalition-demands-c670f1bb/</guid><description>Authors: Cyphers, Bennett and Stepanovich, Amie
Published: October 2017
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/five-eyes-governments-respond-coalition-demands-stop-undermining-encryption/
Abstract: Status update on the Five Eyes governments&amp;rsquo; position on encryptionIn October of 2017, Amie Stepanovich and Bennett Cyphers of Access Now, wrote regarding the organization’s decision to join the more than 80 members of civil society from the “Five Eyes” countries in a letter calling on government leaders to protect strong encryption, and the responses received to date. The letter called for “an unequivocal rejection of laws, policies or other mandates or practices—including secret agreements with companies—that limit access to or undermine encryption and other secure communications tools and technologies.</description></item></channel></rss>