<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Going Dark on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/going-dark/</link><description>Recent content in Going Dark on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/going-dark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Judicial Framework for Evaluating Network Investigative Techniques</title><link>/entries/a-judicial-framework-for-evaluating-network-invest-f6ee8147/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/a-judicial-framework-for-evaluating-network-invest-f6ee8147/</guid><description>Authors: Hennessey, Susan and Weaver, Nicholas
Published: July 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/judicial-framework-evaluating-network-investigative-techniques
Abstract: This article in Lawfare by Susan Hennessey and Nicholas Weaver discusses the use of the NIT in the Playpen investigation, whether the government must disclose an NIT so that defendants may receive a fair trial, and proposes questions that courts should ask when evaluating disclosure of an NIT going forward. First, this article gives a background on the Playpen investigation, and the use of an NIT in the investigation, and background on NITs generally.</description></item><item><title>Breaking: FBI Admits its Claims of “Going Dark” Were Overblown, Based on Bad Math</title><link>/entries/breaking-fbi-admits-its-claims-of-going-dark-were-b620adf1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/breaking-fbi-admits-its-claims-of-going-dark-were-b620adf1/</guid><description>Published: May 2018
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/press-releases/breaking-fbi-admits-its-claims-going-dark-were-overblown-based-bad-math/
Abstract: The Open Technology Institute released a statement regarding a Washington Post report that the FBI overstated “the number of encrypted mobile devices it could not unlock in 2017.” While the FBI had previously claimed there were 7,775 such devices, the FBI later clarified that the real number was around 1,200. Kevin Bankston, the Director of New America’s Open Technology Institute, issued a statement which called for Congressional investigation into the false numbers and arguing that the FBI’s requests for backdoors should be met with skepticism.</description></item><item><title>Congress, Not the Attorney General, Should Decide the Future of Encryption</title><link>/entries/congress-not-the-attorney-general-should-decide-th-61477972/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/congress-not-the-attorney-general-should-decide-th-61477972/</guid><description>Authors: Rozenshtein, Alan Z.
Published: February 2020
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/congress-not-attorney-general-should-decide-future-encryption
Abstract: Alan Z. Rozenshtein, Associate Professor of Law at the University of Minnesota Law School, warns of the dangers of forgoing end-to-end encryption, an anticipated consequence of the powers granted to the attorney general, in the circulating draft of the EARN IT Act. Rozenshtein argues, “the question of whether to permit ubiquitous encryption is the sort of high-level policy decision that is best handled not by the executive branch but by Congress,” recommends against the legislature “shirk[ing] its responsibility to make this tough decision,” and, in the context of the Act, calls for the exclusion of anything encryption-related from the list of best practices.</description></item><item><title>Debate: Law Enforcement vs. Smartphone Encryption</title><link>/entries/debate-law-enforcement-vs-smartphone-encryption-d2d753c0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/debate-law-enforcement-vs-smartphone-encryption-d2d753c0/</guid><description>Authors: New America
Published: November 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/events/debate-on-law-enforcement-vs-smartphone-encryption/
Abstract: This debate features former government officials, technologists, and privacy advocates about encryption being offered as a default on smartphones. One side argues that this move will deprive law enforcement of the ability to seek evidence, even with a warrant, and discusses the possible near for congressional action to require companies to allow law enforcement access. The other side argues that such laws would undermine security and privacy, and disadvantage US technology makers.</description></item><item><title>Don’t Panic: Making Progress on the “Going Dark” Debate</title><link>/entries/dont-panic-making-progress-on-the-going-dark-debat-092ae356/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/dont-panic-making-progress-on-the-going-dark-debat-092ae356/</guid><description>Published: February 2016
Abstract: In September of 2016, the Federal Partnership for Interoperable Communications (FPIC), produced a report on the key reasons, implications, and considerations associated with the encryption of critical portions of public safety communication systems, Considerations for Encryption in Public Safety Radio Systems. As a supplement to that report, the FPIC published this two-page fact sheet, which provides a summary of the report and the policy justifications for its recommendations.</description></item><item><title>FBI Pressuring Google, Facebook to Allow ‘Back Doors’ for Wiretapping</title><link>/entries/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-to-allow-back-doors-71473338/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-to-allow-back-doors-71473338/</guid><description>Authors: Daniel Tencer
Published: November 2010
URL: https://www.rawstory.com/2010/11/fbi-pressuring-google-facebook-wiretapping/
Abstract: On November 17, 2010, Raw Story published an article discussing the debate surrounding a proposed expansion of The Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994. At the time, FBI Director Robert Mueller placed pressure on technology companies to build “back doors” which would “allow law enforcement to wiretap data on their networks”, in an effort “to expand the FBI’s wiretapping powers to include the latest communications technologies, including social networking sites, voice-over-Internet (VoIP) telephone services and BlackBerries.</description></item><item><title>Federal Bureau of Investigation: FY 2010 Budget Request</title><link>/entries/federal-bureau-of-investigation-fy-2010-budget-req-f44e795f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/federal-bureau-of-investigation-fy-2010-budget-req-f44e795f/</guid><description>Authors: FBI
URL: https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/jmd/legacy/2014/04/12/fbi-bud-summary.pdf
Abstract: The FBI’s FY 2010 budget request proposed a roughly $560.3 million (or 7.7%) increase in funding from the preceding year. Included within this requested increase in funding were plans to increase total positions by 1,389—adding 407 new agents—and program enhancements to a number of FBI projects. Most notable among the program enhancements, in the context of encryption, was a requested $9 million increase (to the $233.</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Are Technology, Privacy, and Public Safety on a Collision Course?</title><link>/entries/going-dark-are-technology-privacy-and-public-safet-b115d093/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/going-dark-are-technology-privacy-and-public-safet-b115d093/</guid><description>Authors: Comey, James
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/speeches/going-dark-are-technology-privacy-and-public-safety-on-a-collision-course
Abstract: This speech by FBI Director James Comey, offered at the Brooking Institute in 2014, discusses the challenges that encryption and going dark present to law enforcement. Director Comey discusses how a proliferation in digital data and communication are increasingly encrypted, and how law enforcement is technologically incapable of keeping up. Further, CALEA is not equipped to offer fair access to newer forms of technology.</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Lawful Electronic Surveillance in the Face of New Technologies</title><link>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-5165cb74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-5165cb74/</guid><description>Authors: Valerie Caproni
Published: February 2011
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/testimony/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-face-of-new-technologies
Abstract: On February 17, 2001, Valeria Caproni, General Counsel, Federal Bureau of Investigation, testified before the House Judiciary Committee, Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security. In her testimony, Caproni discussed the “Going Dark” problem facing law enforcement. The “legal authorities [the FBI has] for intercepting electronic communications are adequate”, but the government often does not have the “practical ability to actually intercept those communications”.</description></item><item><title>NSA Isn’t the Going Dark Solution, Part I: Richard Clarke Gets It Wrong</title><link>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-cl-976df318/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-cl-976df318/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/nsa-isnt-going-dark-solution-part-i-richard-clarke-gets-it-wrong
Abstract: Let’s start with a point that will be significant emotional satisfaction to many readers: Richard Clarke was dead wrong. In a remarkable statement last week, the former Clinton and early Bush administration counterterrorism official told NPR’s Morning Edition:</description></item><item><title>NSA Isn’t the Going Dark Solution, Part II: There’s No Such Thing As Magic</title><link>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-9863433f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/nsa-isnt-the-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-9863433f/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/nsa-isnt-going-dark-solution-part-ii-theres-no-such-thing-magic
Abstract: In Part I of this series, I noted the tendency of commentators—without any actual knowledge—to assert that NSA could simply break into a given locked iPhone.</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad Idea</title><link>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</guid><description>Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Abstract: In April 2015, OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston was schedule to testify before the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform’s Subcommittee on Information Technology regarding backdoor mandates and potential U.S. policy responses. New America published this blog post, on April 28, 2015, summarizing Bankston’s prepared statement and highlighting the ten key reasons Bankston identified against backdoor mandates. The reasons identified by Bankston were: 1) surveillance backdoors were already rejected as a policy approach two decades ago, including by Congress; 2) it would seriously undermine U.</description></item><item><title>Prepared Statement by Senator Chuck Grassley, Hearing On “Going Dark: Encryption, Technology, and the Balance Between Public Safety and Privacy</title><link>/entries/prepared-statement-by-senator-chuck-grassley-heari-63a8fa1c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/prepared-statement-by-senator-chuck-grassley-heari-63a8fa1c/</guid><description>Authors: Grassley, Chuck
Published: July 2015
Abstract: On July 8, 2015, Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, Senator Chuck Grassley, addressed a Senate hearing, inquiring “whether recent technological changes have upset the balance between public safety and privacy.” Of particular focus for Senator Grassley was responding to law enforcement questions of “whether the laws Congress has enacted over the years to adapt [the framework of the Fourth Amendment] to changing technology, such as the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act, or CALEA, are adequate to the task [of preserving the rule of law, ensuring the maintenance of public safety, and protecting individual privacy and civil liberties].</description></item><item><title>Questions for Apple</title><link>/entries/questions-for-apple-b3e6b97c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/questions-for-apple-b3e6b97c/</guid><description>Authors: Susan Hennessey, Benjamin Wittes
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/questions-apple
Abstract: On March 1, 2016, Susan Hennessey and Benjamin Wittes, Executive Editor and Editor in Chief of Lawfare, wrote in Lawfare regarding a House Judiciary Committee hearing at which both FBI Director James Comey and Apple General Counsel Bruce Sewell were scheduled to testify on going dark matters. Hennessey and Wittes published a series of questions for Apple. The questions covered a range of topics, including anticipated impacts on Apple stemming from China’s 2015 Counterterrorism Law and Apple’s rationale for declining to comply with requests from law enforcement to decrypt their devices.</description></item><item><title>Report of the Attorney General's Cyber Digital Task Force</title><link>/entries/report-of-the-attorney-general-s-cyber-digital-tas-7bcf0590/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/report-of-the-attorney-general-s-cyber-digital-tas-7bcf0590/</guid><description>Published: July 2018
Abstract: In February of 2018, the Attorney General established a Cyber-Digital Task force within the U.S. Department of Justice and tasked it with answer two foundational questions. First, “how is the Department responding to cyber threats?” Second, “how can federal law enforcement more effectively accomplish its mission in this important and rapidly evolving area?” This Report addresses the first question. The Report begins with a focus on malign foreign influence operations, before expanding into a discussion of other cyber-enabled threats.</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Encryption</title><link>/entries/rethinking-encryption-b0065e9b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/rethinking-encryption-b0065e9b/</guid><description>Authors: Baker, Jim
Published: October 2019
URL: https://www.lawfareblog.com/rethinking-encryption
Abstract: This article written by Jim Baker encourages law enforcement officials in the U.S. to embrace encryption due to cybersecurity threats, particularly from china. The article begins by describing the issues of going dark to law enforcement, and quotes officials such as Attorney General William Barr encouraging Congress to legislate around encryption. However, because Congress has failed to act in light of such pressures, it is possible action will never occur.</description></item><item><title>Security Win: Burr-Feinstein Proposal Declared “Dead” for This Year</title><link>/entries/security-win-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-728401be/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-win-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-728401be/</guid><description>Authors: Reitman, rainey
Published: May 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/05/win-one-security-burr-feinstein-proposal-declared-dead-year
Abstract: This post from the Electronic Frontier Foundation details how proposed legislation from Senators Burr and Feinstein was not going to be introduced, which was seen as a win by many privacy advocates. The article explains the proposal, which would mandate backdoors, and then describes that although it would not advance, many others like it were still being proposed or debated.</description></item><item><title>Security, Surveillance And The Truth About Going Dark</title><link>/entries/security-surveillance-and-the-truth-about-going-da-639358d3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-surveillance-and-the-truth-about-going-da-639358d3/</guid><description>Authors: Blech, Richard
Published: July 2019
URL: https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2019/07/25/security-surveillance-and-the-truth-about-going-dark/
Abstract: This article details a meeting among government officials on whether to ban the public availability and explores similar proposals from the past. The article details how encryption policy frequently debates back doors and the balance between security and surveillance. The article argues that as surveillance technology becomes increasingly prevalent, security must be prioritized.</description></item><item><title>The Burr-Feinstein Proposal Is Simply Anti-Security</title><link>/entries/the-burr-feinstein-proposal-is-simply-anti-securit-e9e5d5f1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-burr-feinstein-proposal-is-simply-anti-securit-e9e5d5f1/</guid><description>Authors: Cohn, Cindy
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/04/burr-feinstein-proposal-simply-anti-security
Abstract: This article described proposed legislation that would require technology companies—including device manufacturers, software developers, ISPs, and others—to decrypt data if ordered to do so by any court at any time. Further, because the proposed actions are not feasible, and if the law were enacted it would harm Americans’ privacy, all while foreign alternatives would still be available. The article argues that because the proposal is so far removed from any technologically feasible solution, it demonstrates how out of touch key regulators are with the reality of encryption.</description></item><item><title>The Encryption Tightrope: Balancing Americans' Security and Privacy</title><link>/entries/the-encryption-tightrope-balancing-americans-secur-8372b960/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-encryption-tightrope-balancing-americans-secur-8372b960/</guid><description>Published: March 2016
Abstract: On March 1, 2016, the House Judiciary Committee of the 114th Congress held a hearing entitled, The Encryption Tightrope: Balancing Americans’ Security and Privacy. The key focus of the hearing was answering the question: How do we deploy ever stronger, more effective encryption without unduly preventing lawful access to communications of criminals and terrorists intent on doing us harm? The Committee began the hearing by nothing its chief concern, that “[a]doption of new communications technologies by those intending harm to the American people is outpacing law enforcement’s technological capability to access those communications in legitimate criminal and national security investigations.</description></item><item><title>The NSA’s Split-Key Encryption Proposal is Not Serious</title><link>/entries/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-seri-126e61d2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-seri-126e61d2/</guid><description>Authors: Joseph Lorenzo Hall
Published: April 2015
URL: https://cdt.org/insights/the-nsas-split-key-encryption-proposal-is-not-serious/
Abstract: The NSA&amp;rsquo;s Split-Key Encryption Proposal is Not Serious discusses the NSA&amp;rsquo;s 2020 proposal to require technology companies to create a &amp;ldquo;golden key,&amp;rdquo; a split-key that would allow the company or the NSA access to encrypted communications. Hall argues that split-key encryption is a technology infeasible, vulnerable, and costly, and would not be able to ensure any data was protected from the NSA.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Tries to Make It Easier to Wiretap the Internet</title><link>/entries/u-s-tries-to-make-it-easier-to-wiretap-the-interne-7c6b8243/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/u-s-tries-to-make-it-easier-to-wiretap-the-interne-7c6b8243/</guid><description>Authors: Savage, Charlie
Published: September 2010
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2010/09/27/us/27wiretap.html
Abstract: This New York Times article by Charlie Savage reports on planned legislation by the Obama administration which would allow for the US government to decrypt select communications and prevent going dark. The article discusses how encryption has worked in recent law enforcement investigations, and why the government finds such a technology necessary. The article discusses the feasibility of different possible elements of the proposed law, including attempting to regulate encryption technology coming from abroad.</description></item></channel></rss>