<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Encryption Standards on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/encryption-standards/</link><description>Recent content in Encryption Standards on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/encryption-standards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Considerations for Encryption in Public Safety Radio Systems</title><link>/entries/considerations-for-encryption-in-public-safety-rad-7298abf0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/considerations-for-encryption-in-public-safety-rad-7298abf0/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: September 2016
URL: https://www.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/publications/20160830_fact_sheet_considerations_final_draft508_0.pdf
Abstract: In September of 2016, at the request of the public safety community, the Federal Partnership for Interoperable Communications (FPIC), produced a report on the key reasons, implications, and considerations associated with the encryption of critical portions of public safety communication systems. Among the key considerations for policy and stakeholders were what to encrypt; how to encrypt; the impact on Interoperability; public information access; and general cost considerations.</description></item><item><title>Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) 197: Advanced Encryption Standard</title><link>/entries/federal-information-processing-standards-fips-197-d91011f8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/federal-information-processing-standards-fips-197-d91011f8/</guid><description>Authors: NIST
Published: November 2001
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20030406010431/http://www.csrc.nist.gov/publications/fips/fips197/fips-197.pdf
Abstract: The Advanced Encryption Standard (AES), officially published on November 26, 2001, provides a Computer Security Standard (Cryptography), for use by Federal departments and agencies when an agency determines that sensitive (unclassified) information requires cryptographic protection. The standard may also be used and adopted by non-Federal Government organizations. The AES specifies Federal Information Process Standards’ (FIPS’) approved cryptographic algorithm that can be used to protect electronic data.</description></item><item><title>Guidelines for Encryption in Land Mobile Radio Systems</title><link>/entries/guidelines-for-encryption-in-land-mobile-radio-sys-b0ed6104/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/guidelines-for-encryption-in-land-mobile-radio-sys-b0ed6104/</guid><description>Published: February 2016
URL: https://www.dhs.gov/publication/encryption
Abstract: On February 8, 2016, the Federal Partnership for Interoperable Communications (FPIC) published guidelines for encryption in land mobile radio (LRM) systems for state, local, and tribal public safety entities. The report discusses the background of public safety entities and encryption, high-level technical information about encryption, types of encryption algorithms for public safety, cryptographic algorithms, and issues with interoperability. The goal of the guidelines was to get rid of confusion and competing information “regarding voice and data encryption” in LMR systems for the state, local, and tribal public safety entities.</description></item><item><title>S.1842 - Protecting Personal Health Data Act</title><link>/entries/s-1842-protecting-personal-health-data-act-8bffdbe7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/s-1842-protecting-personal-health-data-act-8bffdbe7/</guid><description>Authors: Klobuchar, Amy and Murkowski, Lisa
Published: June 2019
URL: https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/1842/text
Abstract: To protect the personal health data of all Americans.</description></item><item><title>Standards Setting and Federal Information Policy: The Escrowed Encryption Standard (EES)</title><link>/entries/standards-setting-and-federal-information-policy-t-0fafb4ad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/standards-setting-and-federal-information-policy-t-0fafb4ad/</guid><description>Authors: Gegner, Karen E. and Veeder, Stacy B.
Published: January 1994
URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0740624X94900183
Abstract: The controversial Escrowed Encryption Standard, recently adopted as a Federal Information Processing Standard (FIPS), has polarized some stakeholders both within and outside government and has also raised disturbing questions about the role of Federal agencies in the standards-setting process. This article explores the relationship between standards and Federal information policy and examines the balance between national security and law enforcement concerns, on the one hand, and privacy rights and U.</description></item></channel></rss>