<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Surveillance on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/surveillance/</link><description>Recent content in Surveillance on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/surveillance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Federal Bureau of Investigation: 2010 Budget Request at a Glance</title><link>/entries/182/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/182/</guid><description>Published: 2010
URL: https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/jmd/legacy/2014/04/12/fbi-bud-summary.pdf
Tags: 2010s Going Dark Mobile National Security Surveillance</description></item><item><title>IC on the Record, Video: ODNI General Counsel Robert Litt</title><link>/entries/161/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/161/</guid><description>Authors: Robert Litt
Published: February 2015
URL: https://icontherecord.tumblr.com/post/110099240063/video-odni-general-counsel-robert-litt-speaks-on
Tags: 2010s National Security Personal Privacy Surveillance Abstract: VIDEO: ODNI General Counsel Robert Litt Speaks on Intelligence Surveillance Reform at the Brookings Institute</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad IDea</title><link>/entries/48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/48/</guid><description>Authors: New America: OTI
Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Tags: 2010s Amendment I Backdoors Cybersecurity Economic Impact Foreign Concerns Going Dark Human Rights OTI Primer SAFE Act Surveillance Abstract: In testimony before House Oversight and Government Reform Committee today, Bankston pushes back against legislative fixes to limit the avail</description></item><item><title>Revealed: How US and UK Spy Agencies Defeat Internet Privacy and Security</title><link>/entries/120/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/120/</guid><description>Authors: Ball, James and Borger, Julian and Greenwald, Glenn
Published: September 2013
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/sep/05/nsa-gchq-encryption-codes-security
Tags: 2010s Data and Computer Security GCHQ Intelligence NSA Surveillance The NSA files UK News World News Abstract: • NSA and GCHQ unlock encryption used to protect emails, banking and medical records• $250m-a-year US program works covertly with tech companies to insert weaknesses into products• Security experts say programs &amp;lsquo;undermine the fabric of the internet&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>Secret US Cybersecurity Report: Encryption Vital to Protect Private Data</title><link>/entries/39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/39/</guid><description>Authors: Ball, James
Published: January 2015
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/jan/15/-sp-secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-protect-data-cameron-paris-attacks
Tags: 2010s GCHQ NSA National Security Snowden Surveillance The NSA files UK News UK Security and Counter-Terrorism World News Abstract: Newly uncovered Snowden document contrasts with British PM’s vow to crack down on encrypted messaging after Paris attacks</description></item><item><title>SS7 Hack Explained: What Can You Do About It?</title><link>/entries/35/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/35/</guid><description>Authors: Gibbs, Samuel
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/apr/19/ss7-hack-explained-mobile-phone-vulnerability-snooping-texts-calls
Tags: 2020s Data and Computer Security Hacking Mobile SS7 Surveillance Telecoms World News Abstract: A vulnerability means hackers can read texts, listen to calls and track mobile phone users. What are the implications and how can you protect yourself from snooping?</description></item><item><title>U.S. Tries to Make It Easier to Wiretap the Internet</title><link>/entries/144/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/144/</guid><description>Authors: Savage, Charlie
Published: September 2010
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2010/09/27/us/27wiretap.html
Tags: 2010s CALEA Going Dark Government Access Mobile Surveillance Abstract: Officials are preparing to seek sweeping new regulations, arguing they are losing their capability to track suspects.</description></item></channel></rss>