<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Surveillance on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/surveillance/</link><description>Recent content in Surveillance on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/surveillance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Federal Bureau of Investigation: FY 2010 Budget Request</title><link>/entries/federal-bureau-of-investigation-fy-2010-budget-req-f44e795f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/federal-bureau-of-investigation-fy-2010-budget-req-f44e795f/</guid><description>Authors: FBI
URL: https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/jmd/legacy/2014/04/12/fbi-bud-summary.pdf
Abstract: The FBI’s FY 2010 budget request proposed a roughly $560.3 million (or 7.7%) increase in funding from the preceding year. Included within this requested increase in funding were plans to increase total positions by 1,389—adding 407 new agents—and program enhancements to a number of FBI projects. Most notable among the program enhancements, in the context of encryption, was a requested $9 million increase (to the $233.</description></item><item><title>IC on the Record, Video: ODNI General Counsel Robert Litt</title><link>/entries/ic-on-the-record-video-odni-general-counsel-robert-f1f2db82/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ic-on-the-record-video-odni-general-counsel-robert-f1f2db82/</guid><description>Authors: Robert Litt
Published: February 2015
URL: https://icontherecord.tumblr.com/post/110099240063/video-odni-general-counsel-robert-litt-speaks-on
Abstract: On February 4, 2015, Robert Litt, General Counsel, Office of the Director of National Intelligence, gave a talk titled “U.S. Intelligence Community Surveillance One Year After President Obama’s [January 2014] Address” at the Brookings Institute. Litt discussed issues related to transparency in intelligent activities, limitations on surveillance, bulk collection of data, incidental collection of data, protection for non-American citizens, and the future.</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad Idea</title><link>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</guid><description>Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Abstract: In April 2015, OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston was schedule to testify before the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform’s Subcommittee on Information Technology regarding backdoor mandates and potential U.S. policy responses. New America published this blog post, on April 28, 2015, summarizing Bankston’s prepared statement and highlighting the ten key reasons Bankston identified against backdoor mandates. The reasons identified by Bankston were: 1) surveillance backdoors were already rejected as a policy approach two decades ago, including by Congress; 2) it would seriously undermine U.</description></item><item><title>Revealed: How US and UK Spy Agencies Defeat Internet Privacy and Security</title><link>/entries/revealed-how-us-and-uk-spy-agencies-defeat-interne-6703184c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/revealed-how-us-and-uk-spy-agencies-defeat-interne-6703184c/</guid><description>Authors: Ball, James and Borger, Julian and Greenwald, Glenn
Published: September 2013
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/sep/05/nsa-gchq-encryption-codes-security
Abstract: • NSA and GCHQ unlock encryption used to protect emails, banking and medical records• $250m-a-year US program works covertly with tech companies to insert weaknesses into products• Security experts say programs &amp;lsquo;undermine the fabric of the internet&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>Secret US Cybersecurity Report: Encryption Vital to Protect Private Data</title><link>/entries/secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-vital-to-9703fda8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-vital-to-9703fda8/</guid><description>Authors: Ball, James
Published: January 2015
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/jan/15/-sp-secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-protect-data-cameron-paris-attacks
Abstract: Newly uncovered Snowden document contrasts with British PM’s vow to crack down on encrypted messaging after Paris attacks</description></item><item><title>SS7 Hack Explained: What Can You Do About It?</title><link>/entries/ss7-hack-explained-what-can-you-do-about-it-2ca330ad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ss7-hack-explained-what-can-you-do-about-it-2ca330ad/</guid><description>Authors: Gibbs, Samuel
Published: April 2016
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/apr/19/ss7-hack-explained-mobile-phone-vulnerability-snooping-texts-calls
Abstract: This article explains the SS7 hack—which allowed hackers to listen to phone calls, read texts, and track mobile phones—recounts what lead to the hack, and gives solutions for people to protect their data. The article, geared towards a law audience, explains how systems can be hacked and what can be done about it, both by a consumer and by companies and the government.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Tries to Make It Easier to Wiretap the Internet</title><link>/entries/u-s-tries-to-make-it-easier-to-wiretap-the-interne-7c6b8243/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/u-s-tries-to-make-it-easier-to-wiretap-the-interne-7c6b8243/</guid><description>Authors: Savage, Charlie
Published: September 2010
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2010/09/27/us/27wiretap.html
Abstract: This New York Times article by Charlie Savage reports on planned legislation by the Obama administration which would allow for the US government to decrypt select communications and prevent going dark. The article discusses how encryption has worked in recent law enforcement investigations, and why the government finds such a technology necessary. The article discusses the feasibility of different possible elements of the proposed law, including attempting to regulate encryption technology coming from abroad.</description></item></channel></rss>