<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Global on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/global/</link><description>Recent content in Global on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/global/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crypto Summit 2.0 Outcomes Report Track 2</title><link>/entries/crypto-summit-2-0-outcomes-report-track-2-d37df90e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/crypto-summit-2-0-outcomes-report-track-2-d37df90e/</guid><description>Authors: Augusto Liguori Filho, Carlos and Kenzo dos Santos, Guilherme and Favaretto Salvador, João Pedro and Guimarães, Tatiane B.
URL: http://www.fgv.br/direitosp/cryptomap/eng/#home
Abstract: The “CryptoMap” is an interactive digital map project, conducted by the Center for Education and Research in Innovation (CEPI) at Fundação Getulio Vargas São Paulo Law School (FGV Direito SP), in Brazil, that seeks to map the international debate on encryption regulation. Each of the 40 countries on the map features a clickable “CryptoPedia” entry (a short summary of the country’s encryption policies), alongside an access link to a “Descriptive Pill,” which describes the country’s domestic privacy policies, encryption regulations, and the government’s access to encrypted data in greater detail.</description></item><item><title>Cryptography and Liberty 2000: An International Survey of Encryption Policy</title><link>/entries/cryptography-and-liberty-2000-an-international-sur-3c4921c1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/cryptography-and-liberty-2000-an-international-sur-3c4921c1/</guid><description>Authors: Banisar, David and Madsen, Wayne
Published: 2000
URL: https://epic.org/reports/crypto2000.html/
Abstract: Cryptography and Liberty is a survey by EPIC, a non-profit organization, on governmental encryption and cryptography laws around the world and the impacts of human rights. The survey focused on laws on domestic use of cryptography, disclosure requirements for encryption keys, import and export controls, and which government agencies or entities regulate cryptography and encryption.</description></item><item><title>Encryption and Globalization</title><link>/entries/encryption-and-globalization-9e3100e9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-and-globalization-9e3100e9/</guid><description>Authors: Swire, Peter P. and Ahmad, Kenesa
Published: 2012
URL: http://www.ssrn.com/abstract=1960602
Abstract: This law review article by Peter Swire and Kenesa Ahmad discusses changes to Indian and Chinese encryption laws. The article begins by describing the development of U.S. encryption laws, mainly focusing on the crypto wars and the United States&amp;rsquo; eventual embrace of encryption. However, the article then discusses globalization that has taken place since the 1990s, and how policy positions developed during the crypto wars are no longer sufficient when considering the increased interconnectedness of the world.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Restrictions</title><link>/entries/encryption-restrictions-54a58dd3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-restrictions-54a58dd3/</guid><description>Authors: Messmer, Ellen
Published: March 2004
URL: https://www.networkworld.com/article/2331257/encryption-restrictions.html
Abstract: In March of 2004, Ellen Messmer, Senior Editor of Network World, wrote regarding global systems of encryption restrictions on imports, exports and use, and the implications for network managers operating globally. Messmer specifically highlighted the mandatory key-sharing program in China, which requires companies to appoint an “encryption contact” to provide all keys to the Chinese government upon request, as an example of foreign encryption policy functioning to disincentive encryption use by foreign corporations operating within a given country.</description></item><item><title>Human Rights and Encryption</title><link>/entries/human-rights-and-encryption-380229a2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/human-rights-and-encryption-380229a2/</guid><description>Authors: U.N. Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization
Published: 2016
URL: https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000246527
Abstract: This study from the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization outlines the benefits of encryption to human rights, the legality of interference with free and strong encryption, and gives best practices for nations and other stakeholders. This study offers case studies in various member states, including Germany, the United States, India, and Brazil, and looks at both legal restrictions on encryption as well as legal measures which promote its adoption.</description></item><item><title>International Human Rights Organizations Express Privacy Concerns About Canadian Cryptography Policy</title><link>/entries/international-human-rights-organizations-express-p-07872304/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/international-human-rights-organizations-express-p-07872304/</guid><description>Authors: Electronic Frontier Canada
Published: April 1998
URL: http://www.efc.ca/pages/pr/efc-pr.27apr98.html
Abstract: On April 27, 1998, Electronic Frontier Canada, Canada’s leading online civil liberties group, issued a press release regarding the 23 civil liberty and human rights organizations—all members of the Global Internet Liberty Campaign—who signed a letter urging the Canadian government to liberalize its cryptography policy. The letter, which was issued in response to an Industry Canada report which listed possible scenarios for government regulation of encryption hardware and software, emphasized the freedom of expression, freedom of association, and privacy rights protected by cryptography.</description></item><item><title>Sources: We Were Pressured to Weaken the Mobile Security in the 80's</title><link>/entries/sources-we-were-pressured-to-weaken-the-mobile-sec-d482f436/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/sources-we-were-pressured-to-weaken-the-mobile-sec-d482f436/</guid><description>Authors: Færaas, Arild
Published: January 2014
URL: https://www.aftenposten.no/article/ap-Olkl.html
Abstract: This article details how the A5/1-encryption standard, used to secure mobile phones, was made intentionally weaker than it could have been. Four men involved with the invention of the encryption standard detailed the political agreements that lead to the standard being weaker than technologically possible, as the encryption standard had been made 54 bit, rather than 128 bit. This encryption standard, they argued, could have at least delayed NSA hacking of the encryption.</description></item><item><title>The Shifting Landscape of Global Internet Censorship</title><link>/entries/the-shifting-landscape-of-global-internet-censorsh-92d9e491/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-shifting-landscape-of-global-internet-censorsh-92d9e491/</guid><description>Authors: Zittrain, Jonathan L. and Faris, Robert and Noman, Helmi and Clark, Justin and Tilton, Casey and Morrison-Westphal, Ryan
Published: 2017
URL: https://www.ssrn.com/abstract=2993485
Abstract: The 2017 Shifting Landscape of Global Internet Censorship by the Berkman Klein Center for Internet &amp;amp; Society is the 2017 update to their report which studies Internet censorship in 75 countries. The study looks at the filtering of documents and information, both in terms of specific topics or individuals as well as entire platforms.</description></item><item><title>Why An Encryption Backdoor for Just the "Good Guys" Won't Work</title><link>/entries/why-an-encryption-backdoor-for-just-the-good-guys-918a9e9d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/why-an-encryption-backdoor-for-just-the-good-guys-918a9e9d/</guid><description>Authors: Stepanovich, Amie and Karanicolas, Michael
Published: March 2018
URL: https://www.justsecurity.org/53316/criminalize-security-criminals-secure/
Abstract: Recently, U.S. law enforcement officials have re-energized their push for a technical means to bypass encryption. But seeking to undermine encryption only looks backward instead of focusing on where technology is going. We should be having conversations about new investigative techniques, not trying to preserve the access enjoyed in the days before encryption was so widespread, particularly when so much is at stake in doing so.</description></item><item><title>World Map of Encryption Laws and Policies</title><link>/entries/world-map-of-encryption-laws-and-policies-af6d8b94/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/world-map-of-encryption-laws-and-policies-af6d8b94/</guid><description>Authors: Global Partners Digital
URL: https://www.gp-digital.org/world-map-of-encryption/
Abstract: This interactive map provides an overview of encryption laws throughout the world. The law categorized nations by minimal, some, and widespread restrictions, as well as imposing filters based on specific law or policy measures.</description></item></channel></rss>