<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Public Safety Radios on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/public-safety-radios/</link><description>Recent content in Public Safety Radios on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/public-safety-radios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best Practices for Encryption in P25 Public Safety Land Mobile Radio Systems</title><link>/entries/best-practices-for-encryption-in-p25-public-safety-c4ce136f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/best-practices-for-encryption-in-p25-public-safety-c4ce136f/</guid><description>Published: September 2016
URL: https://www.cisa.gov/sites/default/files/publications/20160830%20Best%20Practices%20for%20Encryption_Final%20Draft508_0.pdf
Abstract: In September 2016, The Federal Partnership for Interoperable Communications (FPIC), in coordination with Aviation Safety Communique (SAFECOM) and the National Council of Statewide Interoperability Coordinators (NCSWIC), published a report to guide all levels of government in their efforts to improve encrypted interoperability for public safety land mobile radio systems. The “Best Practices” they advocate for the government pertain to: key management organization, key generation and distribution, adopting a National SLN assignment plan, standards-based encryption, crypto period considerations, communications planning, education and training, communications exercises and testing, and experts outreach.</description></item><item><title>Considerations for Encryption in Public Safety Radio Systems</title><link>/entries/considerations-for-encryption-in-public-safety-rad-7298abf0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/considerations-for-encryption-in-public-safety-rad-7298abf0/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: September 2016
URL: https://www.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/publications/20160830_fact_sheet_considerations_final_draft508_0.pdf
Abstract: In September of 2016, at the request of the public safety community, the Federal Partnership for Interoperable Communications (FPIC), produced a report on the key reasons, implications, and considerations associated with the encryption of critical portions of public safety communication systems. Among the key considerations for policy and stakeholders were what to encrypt; how to encrypt; the impact on Interoperability; public information access; and general cost considerations.</description></item></channel></rss>