<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/apple/</link><description>Recent content in Apple on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brief of Amici Curiae Access Now and Wickr Foundation in Support of Apple Inc.'s Motion to Vacate</title><link>/entries/brief-of-amici-curiae-access-now-and-wickr-foundat-c51e7fcb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/brief-of-amici-curiae-access-now-and-wickr-foundat-c51e7fcb/</guid><description>Authors: Wickr Foundation
Abstract: This amicus brief was filed by Access Now and the Wickr Foundation in support of Apple in the Central District of California, asserting that allowing the government to install software to weaken encryption would have far-reaching effects beyond the singular iPhone at hand. The FBI petitioned the court to require Apple to create and install &amp;ldquo;GovtOS&amp;rdquo; which would allow the FBI to work around security features and potentially access encrypted information.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 10/27/2016</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-10-27-2016-20313e86/</guid><description>Published: October 2016
Abstract: On October 27, 2016, a coalition of domestic organizations and experts sent a letter to President Barack Obama in which they urged the White House to respond to a petition using the Administration&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;We the People&amp;rdquo; platform. The petition asked that the Administration &amp;ldquo;[p]ublicly affirm your support for strong encryption,” to “[r]eject any law, policy, or mandate that would undermine our security” online, and to &amp;ldquo;encourage other governments worldwide to do the same.</description></item><item><title>DOJ Plans to Strike Against Encryption While the Techlash Iron Is Hot</title><link>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/doj-plans-to-strike-against-encryption-while-the-t-bdfdad83/</guid><description>Authors: Pfefferkorn, Riana
Published: February 2020
URL: /blog/2020/02/doj-plans-strike-against-encryption-while-techlash-iron-hot
Abstract: This blog post by Riana Pfefferkorn argues that since 2016, the Department of Justice sought to capitalize on public anti-technology sentiment to weaken encryption. First, the article describes the political climate, shaped by the Apple v FBI case, the role of big tech in various privacy scandals and foreign interference in the 2016 election, and foreign legislation, particularly in Australia and the U.</description></item><item><title>Encryption and the Press Clause</title><link>/entries/encryption-and-the-press-clause-46f389c7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-and-the-press-clause-46f389c7/</guid><description>Authors: Baranetsky, D Victoria
Published: 2017
Abstract: This law review article by D. Victoria Baranetsky argues that, through a historical understanding of the purpose of the Press Clause, the First Amendment protects encryption technology. The article begins by describing the Framers’ intent and purpose in the Press Clause, as well as the traditional interpretations and debates that have arisen surrounding its meaning, then goes on to describe how those interpretations may interact with and protect encryption.</description></item><item><title>Ex-NSA Chief Thinks the Government is Dead Wrong in Asking Apple for a Backdoor</title><link>/entries/ex-nsa-chief-thinks-the-government-is-dead-wrong-i-8b5c5590/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ex-nsa-chief-thinks-the-government-is-dead-wrong-i-8b5c5590/</guid><description>Authors: Business Insider
Published: February 2016
URL: https://www.businessinsider.com/michael-hayden-encryption-apple-2016-2
Abstract: On February 25, 2016, Business Insider published an article regarding comments made by a former NSA Chief, General Michael Hayden, in which he expressed his rejection of the notion that tech companies should implement a backdoor to encryption on behalf of law enforcement. While he noted that a lack of a backdoor for encryption imposes “an unfair cost”, he said “we are not required to organize our entire national life around the needs of American law enforcement.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Says It Has Unlocked iPhone Without Apple</title><link>/entries/u-s-says-it-has-unlocked-iphone-without-apple-c5d963b4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/u-s-says-it-has-unlocked-iphone-without-apple-c5d963b4/</guid><description>Authors: Benner, Katie and Lichtblau, Eric
Published: March 2016
URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2016/03/29/technology/apple-iphone-fbi-justice-department-case.html
Abstract: This New York Times article by Katie Benner and Eric Lichtblau reports on the government&amp;rsquo;s successful unlocking of the iPhone of the suspect in the San Bernardino mass shooting, the investigation which gave rise to the Apple vs. FBI court case. The article reports on how the successful unlocking may lead Apple to request information about the exploited vulnerability in order to fix it.</description></item></channel></rss>