<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Criminal Law on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/criminal-law/</link><description>Recent content in Criminal Law on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/criminal-law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Compliance with Court Orders Act of 2016 - Draft</title><link>/entries/compliance-with-court-orders-act-of-2016-draft-517e2d28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/compliance-with-court-orders-act-of-2016-draft-517e2d28/</guid><description>Authors: Burr, Richard, Feinstein, Dianne
URL: https://www.feinstein.senate.gov/public/index.cfm/2016/4/intelligence-committee-leaders-release-discussion-draft-of-encryption-legislation</description></item><item><title>the People of the State of Colorado v. Shaun R. Davis</title><link>/entries/the-people-of-the-state-of-colorado-v-shaun-r-davi-ca69bf48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-people-of-the-state-of-colorado-v-shaun-r-davi-ca69bf48/</guid><description>Published: April 2019
Abstract: In Colorado v. Davis, the Colorado Supreme Court held that using a passcode given to police officers to execute a search warrant on a smartphone did not violate the Fourth Amendment. In this case, a criminal defendant had given his cellphone passcode to police officers during his arrest so they could call his girlfriend. Later, after law enforcement received a warrant to search the phone, the passcode was used to search the phone.</description></item><item><title>The Last Refuge of the Criminal: Encrypted Smartphones</title><link>/entries/the-last-refuge-of-the-criminal-encrypted-smartpho-ba7ee311/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/the-last-refuge-of-the-criminal-encrypted-smartpho-ba7ee311/</guid><description>Authors: de Bolle, Catherine, Vance, Cyrus R., Jr.
Published: July 2021
URL: https://www.politico.eu/article/the-last-refuge-of-the-criminal-encrypted-smartphones-data-privacy/
Abstract: Catherine de Bolle and Cyrus R. Vance, Jr., write in Politico that encrypted devices—particularly encrypted smartphones—pose an intolerable impediment to law enforcement, the pursuit of justice, and vindication of victims and their families. They argue that criminals exploit unregulated encryption to perpetrate a variety of crimes, from ransomware to child sex trafficking, and that the ability to lawfully access devices is overwhelmingly frustrated by judges, policies, and budgets.</description></item></channel></rss>