<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Economic Impact on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/economic-impact/</link><description>Recent content in Economic Impact on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/economic-impact/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beyond Secrets: The Consumer Stake in the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/72/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/72/</guid><description>Published: December 2017
URL: https://advocacy.consumerreports.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Beyond-Secrets-12.21.17-FINAL.pdf
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Economic Impact Emergency Communications Healthcare Mobile Primer</description></item><item><title>CEOs and Encryption: The Questions You Need to Ask Your Experts</title><link>/entries/70/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/70/</guid><description>Authors: Robin, Wilton
Published: March 2018
URL: https://www.internetsociety.org/blog/2018/03/ceos-encryption-questions-need-asking-experts-2/
Tags: 2010s Corporate Economic Impact Public Key Encryption Abstract: Barely a week passes without something in the news that reminds us of the critical role encryption plays in securing our data. It is a technology that protects so much of what we rely on, as individuals protecting our privacy, as companies securing our business assets and transactions, and as governments responsible for critical national …</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 5/19/2015</title><link>/entries/88/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/88/</guid><description>Published: May 2015
URL: https://static.newamerica.org/attachments/3138&amp;ndash;113/Encryption_Letter_to_Obama_final_051915.pdf
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Economic Impact Human Rights National Security Abstract: We urge you to reject any proposal that U.S. companies deliberately weaken the security of their products. We request that the White House instead focus on developing policies that will promote rather than undermine the wide adoption of strong encryption technology. Such policies will in turn help to promote and protect cybersecurity, economic growth, and human rights, both here and abroad.</description></item><item><title>Encryption in the U.S.: Crypto Colloquium Outcomes Report</title><link>/entries/67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/67/</guid><description>Published: January 2018
Tags: 2010s Access Now Backdoors Economic Impact National Security Primer Abstract: U.S. government agencies have identified the inability to access information on encrypted mobile phones as one of the largest current challenges to criminal investigations. In September 2017, Access Now, supported by the Mozilla Foundation’s Tech Policy Fellowship, hosted the Crypto Colloquium — an invite-only dialogue, with participation under the Chatham House rules — to discuss this challenge.</description></item><item><title>Encryption, Trust, and the Online Economy: An Assessment of the Economic Benefits Associated with Encryption</title><link>/entries/63/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/63/</guid><description>Authors: Ryan Hagemann, Josh Hampson
Published: November 2015
URL: https://www.niskanencenter.org/encryption-trust-and-the-online-economy-an-assessment-of-the-economic-benefits-associated-with-encryption/
Tags: 2010s Economic Impact Abstract: The problems of online security and the non-economic benefits of encryption are well understood, but there has yet to be a comprehensive analysis of the economic benefits created by the spread of encryption. This is not surprising. When encryption is working properly, the user is not even aware of its existence. In order to gauge …</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad IDea</title><link>/entries/47/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/47/</guid><description>Authors: New America: OTI
Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Tags: 2010s Amendment I Backdoors Cybersecurity Economic Impact Foreign Concerns Going Dark Human Rights OTI Primer SAFE Act Surveillance Abstract: In testimony before House Oversight and Government Reform Committee today, Bankston pushes back against legislative fixes to limit the avail</description></item><item><title>Secrets or Shields to Share? New Dilemmas for Dual Use Technology Development and the Quest for military and Commercial Advantage in the Digital Age</title><link>/entries/37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/37/</guid><description>Authors: Jay Stowsky
Published: February 2003
Tags: 1990s 2000s Dual-Use Technology Economic Impact National Security Primer</description></item><item><title>Surveillance Costs: The NSA's Impact on the Economy, Internet Freedom \&amp; Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/120/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/120/</guid><description>Authors: Robyn Greene, Danielle Kehl, Robert Morgus, and Kevin Bankston
Published: July 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/policy-papers/surveillance-costs-the-nsas-impact-on-the-economy-internet-freedom-cybersecurity/
Tags: 2010s Cybersecurity Economic Impact Government Access National Security OTI Personal Privacy Abstract: It has been over a year since The Guardian reported the first story on the National Security Agency’s surveillance programs based on the leaks from former NSA contractor Edward Snowden, yet the national conversation remains largely mired in a simplistic debate over the tradeoffs between national security and individual privacy.</description></item></channel></rss>