<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Economic Impact on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/economic-impact/</link><description>Recent content in Economic Impact on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/economic-impact/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beyond Secrets: The Consumer Stake in the Encryption Debate</title><link>/entries/beyond-secrets-the-consumer-stake-in-the-encryptio-5a9a086a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/beyond-secrets-the-consumer-stake-in-the-encryptio-5a9a086a/</guid><description>Published: December 2017
URL: https://advocacy.consumerreports.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Beyond-Secrets-12.21.17-FINAL.pdf
Abstract: On December 21, 2017, ConsumersUnion and Upturn released this paper on consumers’ stake in the encryption debate. The paper begins with information on cryptography: what it is and how it works. It then discusses the ways in which encryption benefits consumers, including: protecting their health information, safeguarding their financial well-being, facilitating sale software updates, ensuring physical safety, and allowing consumers to communicate with confidence. The purpose of this paper is to educate consumers about the many ways that encryption benefits consumers and the systems and infrastructure consumers rely upon, and the potential costs if encryption were to be compromised.</description></item><item><title>CEOs and Encryption: The Questions You Need to Ask Your Experts</title><link>/entries/ceos-and-encryption-the-questions-you-need-to-ask-f054d98f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ceos-and-encryption-the-questions-you-need-to-ask-f054d98f/</guid><description>Authors: Wilton, Robin
Published: March 2018
URL: https://www.internetsociety.org/blog/2018/03/ceos-encryption-questions-need-asking-experts-2/
Abstract: On March 16, 2018, Robin Wilton, Director of Internet Trust, published a paper – originally created as an internal memorandum for Internet Society CEO, Kathy Brown – detailing the key questions CEOs should ask technical experts to ensure encryption policy competency. The paper explores three key topics: (1) getting a snapshot of your organization’s crypto strategy and current states, (2) practical challenges of deployment and management, and (3) non-technical factors around risk mitigation and law enforcement access.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 5/19/2015</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-5-19-2015-ad5d54f2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-5-19-2015-ad5d54f2/</guid><description>Published: May 2015
URL: https://static.newamerica.org/attachments/3138&amp;ndash;113/Encryption_Letter_to_Obama_final_051915.pdf
Abstract: We urge you to reject any proposal that U.S. companies deliberately weaken the security of their products. We request that the White House instead focus on developing policies that will promote rather than undermine the wide adoption of strong encryption technology. Such policies will in turn help to promote and protect cybersecurity, economic growth, and human rights, both here and abroad.</description></item><item><title>Encryption in the U.S.: Crypto Colloquium Outcomes Report</title><link>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</guid><description>Published: January 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/02/Encryption-in-the-United-States-Crypto-Colloquium-Outcomes-Report.pdf
Abstract: In September of 2017, Access Now, a non-profit dedicated to human rights advocacy in the digital age, hosted the Crypto Colloquium—an invite-only dialogue of civil society, academic experts, technology companies and former U.S. government officials—to discuss challenges associated with U.S. government agencies’ inability to access information on encrypted mobile phones. The Report, produced by Access Now, provides a summary of the key takeaways from the Colloquium, including a section on the “Lessons Learned” in each of the Law and Policy, Security, and Economics sectors.</description></item><item><title>Encryption, Trust, and the Online Economy: An Assessment of the Economic Benefits Associated with Encryption</title><link>/entries/encryption-trust-and-the-online-economy-an-assessm-b5968feb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-trust-and-the-online-economy-an-assessm-b5968feb/</guid><description>Authors: Hagemann, Ryan and Hampson, Josh
Published: November 2015
URL: https://www.niskanencenter.org/encryption-trust-and-the-online-economy-an-assessment-of-the-economic-benefits-associated-with-encryption/
Abstract: On November 9, 2015, the Niskanen Center published a report that assessed the economic benefits associated with the use of software-based encryption. The report’s aim is to “provide a ballpark estimate of the economic value of encryption” and “suggest how a more accurate estimate might be achieved”, with the end goal of showing “the way toward a better understanding of the role and benefit of encryption in the Internet-age economy”.</description></item><item><title>OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston Offers Ten reasons Why Backdoor Mandates Are a Bad Idea</title><link>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reas-349f9fa5/</guid><description>Published: April 2015
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/oti-policy-director-kevin-bankston-offers-ten-reasons-why-backdoor-mandates-are-a-bad-idea/
Abstract: In April 2015, OTI Policy Director Kevin Bankston was schedule to testify before the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform’s Subcommittee on Information Technology regarding backdoor mandates and potential U.S. policy responses. New America published this blog post, on April 28, 2015, summarizing Bankston’s prepared statement and highlighting the ten key reasons Bankston identified against backdoor mandates. The reasons identified by Bankston were: 1) surveillance backdoors were already rejected as a policy approach two decades ago, including by Congress; 2) it would seriously undermine U.</description></item><item><title>Secrets or Shields to Share? New Dilemmas for Dual Use Technology Development and the Quest for military and Commercial Advantage in the Digital Age</title><link>/entries/secrets-or-shields-to-share-new-dilemmas-for-dual-34d6ebbe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/secrets-or-shields-to-share-new-dilemmas-for-dual-34d6ebbe/</guid><description>Authors: Stowsky, Jay
Published: February 2003</description></item><item><title>Surveillance Costs: The NSA's Impact on the Economy, Internet Freedom \&amp; Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/surveillance-costs-the-nsa-s-impact-on-the-economy-5c789458/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/surveillance-costs-the-nsa-s-impact-on-the-economy-5c789458/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle and Bankston, Kevin and Greene, Robyn and Morgus, Robert
Published: July 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/policy-papers/surveillance-costs-the-nsas-impact-on-the-economy-internet-freedom-cybersecurity/
Abstract: It has been over a year since The Guardian reported the first story on the National Security Agency’s surveillance programs based on the leaks from former NSA contractor Edward Snowden, yet the national conversation remains largely mired in a simplistic debate over the tradeoffs between national security and individual privacy. It is time to start weighing the overall costs and benefits more broadly.</description></item></channel></rss>