<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>National Security on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/national-security/</link><description>Recent content in National Security on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/national-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bureau of Export Administration Annual Report 1998</title><link>/entries/bureau-of-export-administration-annual-report-1998-b53ffd24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/bureau-of-export-administration-annual-report-1998-b53ffd24/</guid><description>Published: 1998
Abstract: The Annual Report issued by the Bureau of Export Administration (BXA) provides the fiscal year highlights of the Bureau’s administration, enforcement and regulation of exports of dual-use commodities, technology and software from the United States and its territories. In 1998, the BXA was tasked with implementing the Clinton Administration’s commercial encryption policy. BXA was tasked with the objective of “promot[ing] growth of electronic commerce and secure communications worldwide while protecting the public safety and national security.</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 5/19/2015</title><link>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-5-19-2015-ad5d54f2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/coalition-letter-to-president-obama-5-19-2015-ad5d54f2/</guid><description>Published: May 2015
URL: https://static.newamerica.org/attachments/3138&amp;ndash;113/Encryption_Letter_to_Obama_final_051915.pdf
Abstract: We urge you to reject any proposal that U.S. companies deliberately weaken the security of their products. We request that the White House instead focus on developing policies that will promote rather than undermine the wide adoption of strong encryption technology. Such policies will in turn help to promote and protect cybersecurity, economic growth, and human rights, both here and abroad.</description></item><item><title>Congress Mulls Stiff Crypto Laws</title><link>/entries/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws-50dadb61/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws-50dadb61/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/09/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws/
Abstract: On September 13, 2001, Wired published an article about the impact of 9/11 terrorist attacks on the encryption debate, and declared that “[t]he encryption wars have begun”. The article claims that the balance of the debate between privacy and security “abruptly shifted” in the wake of 9/11, and that “political winds have shifted from business to national security”. The article discusses various Clinton Administration initiatives related to encryption, and highlighted quotes from Congress members who “called for a global prohibition on encryption products without backdoors for government surveillance”.</description></item><item><title>Encryption in the U.S.: Crypto Colloquium Outcomes Report</title><link>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/encryption-in-the-u-s-crypto-colloquium-outcomes-r-9fd86b2f/</guid><description>Published: January 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/02/Encryption-in-the-United-States-Crypto-Colloquium-Outcomes-Report.pdf
Abstract: In September of 2017, Access Now, a non-profit dedicated to human rights advocacy in the digital age, hosted the Crypto Colloquium—an invite-only dialogue of civil society, academic experts, technology companies and former U.S. government officials—to discuss challenges associated with U.S. government agencies’ inability to access information on encrypted mobile phones. The Report, produced by Access Now, provides a summary of the key takeaways from the Colloquium, including a section on the “Lessons Learned” in each of the Law and Policy, Security, and Economics sectors.</description></item><item><title>Ex-NSA Chief Thinks the Government is Dead Wrong in Asking Apple for a Backdoor</title><link>/entries/ex-nsa-chief-thinks-the-government-is-dead-wrong-i-8b5c5590/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ex-nsa-chief-thinks-the-government-is-dead-wrong-i-8b5c5590/</guid><description>Authors: Business Insider
Published: February 2016
URL: https://www.businessinsider.com/michael-hayden-encryption-apple-2016-2
Abstract: On February 25, 2016, Business Insider published an article regarding comments made by a former NSA Chief, General Michael Hayden, in which he expressed his rejection of the notion that tech companies should implement a backdoor to encryption on behalf of law enforcement. While he noted that a lack of a backdoor for encryption imposes “an unfair cost”, he said “we are not required to organize our entire national life around the needs of American law enforcement.</description></item><item><title>Federal Bureau of Investigation: FY 2010 Budget Request</title><link>/entries/federal-bureau-of-investigation-fy-2010-budget-req-f44e795f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/federal-bureau-of-investigation-fy-2010-budget-req-f44e795f/</guid><description>Authors: FBI
URL: https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/jmd/legacy/2014/04/12/fbi-bud-summary.pdf
Abstract: The FBI’s FY 2010 budget request proposed a roughly $560.3 million (or 7.7%) increase in funding from the preceding year. Included within this requested increase in funding were plans to increase total positions by 1,389—adding 407 new agents—and program enhancements to a number of FBI projects. Most notable among the program enhancements, in the context of encryption, was a requested $9 million increase (to the $233.</description></item><item><title>First and Fifth Amendment Challenges to Export Controls on Encryption: Bernstein and Karn</title><link>/entries/first-and-fifth-amendment-challenges-to-export-con-41c9888c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/first-and-fifth-amendment-challenges-to-export-con-41c9888c/</guid><description>Authors: Pilkington, Laura M.
Published: 1996
URL: https://heinonline.org/HOL/P?h=hein.journals/saclr37&amp;amp;i=177</description></item><item><title>Former National-Security Officials Suddenly See the Peril of Weakening Encryption</title><link>/entries/former-national-security-officials-suddenly-see-th-d46b3725/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/former-national-security-officials-suddenly-see-th-d46b3725/</guid><description>Authors: Friedersdorf, Conor
Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2015/07/former-national-security-officials-see-the-peril-of-weakening-encryption/399848/
Abstract: This new article examines how former national security officials, after leaving their government jobs for private industry, tended to support strong encryption and argued against mandatory backdoor access. The article reported comments made by several former national security officials who had then transitioned to private industry, and the comments they made against government infringement on encryption at the Aspen Security Forum in 2015.</description></item><item><title>GAO Report on Communications Privacy</title><link>/entries/gao-report-on-communications-privacy-9342867b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/gao-report-on-communications-privacy-9342867b/</guid><description>Authors: U.S. General Accounting Office
Published: November 1993
URL: https://epic.org/crypto/reports/gao_comm_privacy.html
Abstract: In November 1993, the GAO produced a report, at the request of Jack Brooks, the then Chairman of the House Judiciary Committee, exploring the impact of federal policies on U.S. corporations’ ability to protect themselves against economic espionage. The Report focused on a few key issues: the need for information privacy in computer communications system through encryption; federal agency authority to develop cryptographic standards for the protection of sensitive, unclassified information; the roles, actions and policies of NSA and the Department of State related to export controls for products with encryption capabilities and industry rationale for requesting liberalization of controls; and the Federal Bureau of Investigation’s (FBI) legislative proposal regarding telephone systems that use digital communications technology.</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Lawful Electronic Surveillance in the Face of New Technologies</title><link>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-5165cb74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-f-5165cb74/</guid><description>Authors: Valerie Caproni
Published: February 2011
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/testimony/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-face-of-new-technologies
Abstract: On February 17, 2001, Valeria Caproni, General Counsel, Federal Bureau of Investigation, testified before the House Judiciary Committee, Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security. In her testimony, Caproni discussed the “Going Dark” problem facing law enforcement. The “legal authorities [the FBI has] for intercepting electronic communications are adequate”, but the government often does not have the “practical ability to actually intercept those communications”.</description></item><item><title>IC on the Record, Video: ODNI General Counsel Robert Litt</title><link>/entries/ic-on-the-record-video-odni-general-counsel-robert-f1f2db82/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/ic-on-the-record-video-odni-general-counsel-robert-f1f2db82/</guid><description>Authors: Robert Litt
Published: February 2015
URL: https://icontherecord.tumblr.com/post/110099240063/video-odni-general-counsel-robert-litt-speaks-on
Abstract: On February 4, 2015, Robert Litt, General Counsel, Office of the Director of National Intelligence, gave a talk titled “U.S. Intelligence Community Surveillance One Year After President Obama’s [January 2014] Address” at the Brookings Institute. Litt discussed issues related to transparency in intelligent activities, limitations on surveillance, bulk collection of data, incidental collection of data, protection for non-American citizens, and the future.</description></item><item><title>Secret US Cybersecurity Report: Encryption Vital to Protect Private Data</title><link>/entries/secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-vital-to-9703fda8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-vital-to-9703fda8/</guid><description>Authors: Ball, James
Published: January 2015
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/jan/15/-sp-secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-protect-data-cameron-paris-attacks
Abstract: Newly uncovered Snowden document contrasts with British PM’s vow to crack down on encrypted messaging after Paris attacks</description></item><item><title>Secrets or Shields to Share? New Dilemmas for Dual Use Technology Development and the Quest for military and Commercial Advantage in the Digital Age</title><link>/entries/secrets-or-shields-to-share-new-dilemmas-for-dual-34d6ebbe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/secrets-or-shields-to-share-new-dilemmas-for-dual-34d6ebbe/</guid><description>Authors: Stowsky, Jay
Published: February 2003</description></item><item><title>Security vs. Security - Rapid7 Supports Strong Encryption</title><link>/entries/security-vs-security-rapid7-supports-strong-encryp-4634f37f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/security-vs-security-rapid7-supports-strong-encryp-4634f37f/</guid><description>Authors: Geiger, Harley
Published: April 2016
URL: https://blog.rapid7.com/2016/04/01/security-vs-security-rapid7-supports-strong-encryption/
Abstract: A major area of focus in the current cybersecurity policy discussion is how growing adoption of encryption impacts law enforcement and national security, and whether new policies should be developed in response. This post briefly evaluates several potential outcomes of the debate, and provides Rapid7&amp;rsquo;s current position on each. Background</description></item><item><title>Statement of General Keith B. Alexander, Commander, United States Cyber Command, Before the Senate Committee on Armed Services</title><link>/entries/statement-of-general-keith-b-alexander-commander-u-d467327a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/statement-of-general-keith-b-alexander-commander-u-d467327a/</guid><description>Authors: Alexander, Keith B.
Published: March 2013</description></item><item><title>Surveillance Costs: The NSA's Impact on the Economy, Internet Freedom \&amp; Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/surveillance-costs-the-nsa-s-impact-on-the-economy-5c789458/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/surveillance-costs-the-nsa-s-impact-on-the-economy-5c789458/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle and Bankston, Kevin and Greene, Robyn and Morgus, Robert
Published: July 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/policy-papers/surveillance-costs-the-nsas-impact-on-the-economy-internet-freedom-cybersecurity/
Abstract: It has been over a year since The Guardian reported the first story on the National Security Agency’s surveillance programs based on the leaks from former NSA contractor Edward Snowden, yet the national conversation remains largely mired in a simplistic debate over the tradeoffs between national security and individual privacy. It is time to start weighing the overall costs and benefits more broadly.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Supercomputer Export Control Policy</title><link>/entries/u-s-supercomputer-export-control-policy-9f12a98a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/u-s-supercomputer-export-control-policy-9f12a98a/</guid><description>Published: November 1997
URL: http://commdocs.house.gov/committees/security/has317000.000/has317000_1.HTM
Abstract: This hearing is from the House of Representatives Committee on National Security, in their 1997 hearing on U.S. Supercomputer Export Control Policy. Here, many high-level government officials are questioned on the details of encryption export policy. It gives a thorough accounting of the attitudes of the government officials involved in encryption policy in the 1990s.</description></item><item><title>US Government Fines Intel's Wind River Over Crypto Exports</title><link>/entries/us-government-fines-intel-s-wind-river-over-crypto-09cbe60a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/us-government-fines-intel-s-wind-river-over-crypto-09cbe60a/</guid><description>Authors: Leyden, John
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.theregister.co.uk/2014/10/17/intel_subsidiary_crypto_export_fine/
Abstract: This article by John Leyden discussed a $750,000 fine by the Department of Commerce on Wind River for exporting products utilizing encryption to foreign nations, including China, Russia, and Israel. The article explores increasing action by regulators, viewing large fines for violations as the norm going forward, in the conflict over foreign control over encryption. The article explores the consequences of escalating enforcement action over the trade of encrypted technology with foreign nations.</description></item></channel></rss>