<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>National Security on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/national-security/</link><description>Recent content in National Security on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/national-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bureau of Export Administration Annual Report 1998</title><link>/entries/124/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/124/</guid><description>Authors: Bureau of Export Administration
Published: 1998
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls National Security</description></item><item><title>Coalition Letter to President Obama 5/19/2015</title><link>/entries/112/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/112/</guid><description>Published: May 2015
URL: https://static.newamerica.org/attachments/3138&amp;ndash;113/Encryption_Letter_to_Obama_final_051915.pdf
Tags: 2010s Backdoors Economic Impact Human Rights National Security Abstract: We urge you to reject any proposal that U.S. companies deliberately weaken the security of their products. We request that the White House instead focus on developing policies that will promote rather than undermine the wide adoption of strong encryption technology. Such policies will in turn help to promote and protect cybersecurity, economic growth, and human rights, both here and abroad.</description></item><item><title>Congress Mulls Stiff Crypto Laws</title><link>/entries/105/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/105/</guid><description>Authors: McCullagh, Declan
Published: September 2001
URL: https://www.wired.com/2001/09/congress-mulls-stiff-crypto-laws/
Tags: 2000s 9/11 Crypto Wars Crypto Wars II National Security Terrorism Abstract: Some lawmakers say encryption laws can let terrorists plot attacks such as Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s assaults on the East Coast. Congress is considering a crypto-crackdown. Declan McCullagh reports from Washington.</description></item><item><title>Encryption in the U.S.: Crypto Colloquium Outcomes Report</title><link>/entries/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/18/</guid><description>Published: January 2018
URL: https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2018/02/Encryption-in-the-United-States-Crypto-Colloquium-Outcomes-Report.pdf
Tags: 2010s Access Now Backdoors Economic Impact National Security Primer Abstract: U.S. government agencies have identified the inability to access information on encrypted mobile phones as one of the largest current challenges to criminal investigations. In September 2017, Access Now, supported by the Mozilla Foundation’s Tech Policy Fellowship, hosted the Crypto Colloquium — an invite-only dialogue, with participation under the Chatham House rules — to discuss this challenge.</description></item><item><title>Ex-NSA Chief Thinks the Government is Dead Wrong in Asking Apple for a Backdoor</title><link>/entries/92/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/92/</guid><description>Authors: pzdupe2
Published: February 2016
URL: https://www.businessinsider.com/michael-hayden-encryption-apple-2016-2
Tags: 2010s Apple Backdoors NSA National Security</description></item><item><title>Federal Bureau of Investigation: FY 2010 Budget Request</title><link>/entries/14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/14/</guid><description>URL: https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/jmd/legacy/2014/04/12/fbi-bud-summary.pdf
Tags: 2010s Going Dark Mobile National Security Surveillance</description></item><item><title>First and Fifth Amendment Challenges to Export Controls on Encryption: Bernstein and Karn</title><link>/entries/190/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/190/</guid><description>Authors: Pilkington, Laura M.
Published: 1996
URL: https://heinonline.org/HOL/P?h=hein.journals/saclr37&amp;amp;i=177
Tags: 1990s Clinton Export Controls Law Enforcement National Security</description></item><item><title>Former National-Security Officials Suddenly See the Peril of Weakening Encryption</title><link>/entries/173/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/173/</guid><description>Authors: Friedersdorf, Conor
Published: July 2015
URL: https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2015/07/former-national-security-officials-see-the-peril-of-weakening-encryption/399848/
Tags: 2010s NSA National Security Abstract: Now that they&amp;rsquo;re in the private sector, they are speaking out against the push to mandate “backdoors” in communication platforms.</description></item><item><title>GAO Report on Communications Privacy</title><link>/entries/194/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/194/</guid><description>Authors: U.S. General Accounting Office
Published: November 1993
URL: https://epic.org/crypto/reports/gao_comm_privacy.html
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I National Security</description></item><item><title>Going Dark: Lawful Electronic Surveillance in the Face of New Technologies</title><link>/entries/172/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/172/</guid><description>Authors: Valerie Caproni
Published: February 2011
URL: https://www.fbi.gov/news/testimony/going-dark-lawful-electronic-surveillance-in-the-face-of-new-technologies
Tags: 2010s CALEA Going Dark National Security Terrorism Abstract: Statement Before the House Judiciary Committee, Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security</description></item><item><title>IC on the Record, Video: ODNI General Counsel Robert Litt</title><link>/entries/169/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/169/</guid><description>Authors: Robert Litt
Published: February 2015
URL: https://icontherecord.tumblr.com/post/110099240063/video-odni-general-counsel-robert-litt-speaks-on
Tags: 2010s National Security Personal Privacy Surveillance Abstract: VIDEO: ODNI General Counsel Robert Litt Speaks on Intelligence Surveillance Reform at the Brookings Institute</description></item><item><title>Secret US Cybersecurity Report: Encryption Vital to Protect Private Data</title><link>/entries/75/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/75/</guid><description>Authors: Ball, James
Published: January 2015
URL: https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/jan/15/-sp-secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-protect-data-cameron-paris-attacks
Tags: 2010s GCHQ NSA National Security Snowden Surveillance The NSA files UK News UK Security and Counter-Terrorism World News Abstract: Newly uncovered Snowden document contrasts with British PM’s vow to crack down on encrypted messaging after Paris attacks</description></item><item><title>Secrets or Shields to Share? New Dilemmas for Dual Use Technology Development and the Quest for military and Commercial Advantage in the Digital Age</title><link>/entries/74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/74/</guid><description>Authors: Jay Stowsky
Published: February 2003
Tags: 1990s 2000s Dual-Use Technology Economic Impact National Security Primer</description></item><item><title>Security vs. Security - Rapid7 Supports Strong Encryption</title><link>/entries/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/27/</guid><description>Authors: Geiger, Harley
Published: April 2016
URL: https://blog.rapid7.com/2016/04/01/security-vs-security-rapid7-supports-strong-encryption/
Tags: 2010s National Security Abstract: A major area of focus in the current cybersecurity policy discussion is how growing adoption of encryption impacts law enforcement and national security, and whether new policies should be developed in response. This post briefly evaluates several potential outcomes of the debate, and provides Rapid7&amp;rsquo;s current position on each. Background</description></item><item><title>Statement of General Keith B. Alexander, Commander, United States Cyber Command, Before the Senate Committee on Armed Services</title><link>/entries/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/6/</guid><description>Authors: Alexander, Keith B.
Published: March 2013
Tags: 2010s Cyber Command Law Enforcement National Security</description></item><item><title>Surveillance Costs: The NSA's Impact on the Economy, Internet Freedom \&amp; Cybersecurity</title><link>/entries/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/15/</guid><description>Authors: Kehl, Danielle and Bankston, Kevin and Greene, Robyn and Morgus, Robert
Published: July 2014
URL: https://www.newamerica.org/oti/policy-papers/surveillance-costs-the-nsas-impact-on-the-economy-internet-freedom-cybersecurity/
Tags: 2010s Cybersecurity Economic Impact Government Access National Security OTI Personal Privacy Abstract: It has been over a year since The Guardian reported the first story on the National Security Agency’s surveillance programs based on the leaks from former NSA contractor Edward Snowden, yet the national conversation remains largely mired in a simplistic debate over the tradeoffs between national security and individual privacy.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Supercomputer Export Control Policy</title><link>/entries/50/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/50/</guid><description>Authors: House of Representatives, Committee on National Security, Chairman, Hon. Floyd D. Spence
Published: November 1997
URL: http://commdocs.house.gov/committees/security/has317000.000/has317000_1.HTM
Tags: 1990s Crypto Wars Crypto Wars I Export Controls Hearing National Security</description></item><item><title>US Government Fines Intel's Wind River Over Crypto Exports</title><link>/entries/56/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/56/</guid><description>Authors: John Leyden
Published: October 2014
URL: https://www.theregister.co.uk/2014/10/17/intel_subsidiary_crypto_export_fine/
Tags: 2010s Export Controls National Security Abstract: New emphasis on encryption as a weapon?</description></item></channel></rss>