<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AES on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/aes/</link><description>Recent content in AES on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/aes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) 197: Advanced Encryption Standard</title><link>/entries/federal-information-processing-standards-fips-197-d91011f8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/federal-information-processing-standards-fips-197-d91011f8/</guid><description>Authors: NIST
Published: November 2001
URL: https://web.archive.org/web/20030406010431/http://www.csrc.nist.gov/publications/fips/fips197/fips-197.pdf
Abstract: The Advanced Encryption Standard (AES), officially published on November 26, 2001, provides a Computer Security Standard (Cryptography), for use by Federal departments and agencies when an agency determines that sensitive (unclassified) information requires cryptographic protection. The standard may also be used and adopted by non-Federal Government organizations. The AES specifies Federal Information Process Standards’ (FIPS’) approved cryptographic algorithm that can be used to protect electronic data.</description></item><item><title>How secure is AES Against Brute Force Attacks?</title><link>/entries/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks-a76070ac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks-a76070ac/</guid><description>Authors: Arora, Mohit
Published: May 2012
URL: https://www.eetimes.com/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks/
Abstract: In May of 2012, Mohit Arora, Sr. Systems Engineer &amp;amp; Security Architect for Freescale Semiconductor, wrote for the EE Times regarding the security of Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) against brute force attacks. Arora analyzed the system’s strength against brute force attacks with different key sizes and projected advancements in processing speeds. Ultimately, Arora concluded that “even with a supercomputer, it would take 1 billion years to crack the 128-bit AES keying using [a] brute force attack,” and thus deemed AES “safe against any brute force attack.</description></item></channel></rss>