<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quantum Resistant on The Encryption Compendium</title><link>/tags/quantum-resistant/</link><description>Recent content in Quantum Resistant on The Encryption Compendium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/quantum-resistant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Status Peport on the First round of the NIST Post-Quantum Cryptography Standardization Process</title><link>/entries/116/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/116/</guid><description>Authors: NIST and Alagic, Gorjan and Alperin-Sheriff, Jacob and Apon, Daniel and Cooper, David and Dang, Quynh and Liu, Yi-Kai and Miller, Carl and Moody, Dustin and Peralta, Rene and Perlner, Ray and Robinson, Angela and Smith-Tone, Daniel
Published: January 2019
URL: https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2019/NIST.IR.8240.pdf
Tags: 2010s NIST Public Key Encryption Quantum Resistant Quantum Safe Abstract: The National Institute of Standards and Technology is in the process of selecting one or more public-key cryptographic algorithms through a public competition-like process.</description></item><item><title>The Search for Quantum-Resistant Cryptography: Understanding the Future Landscape</title><link>/entries/25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/entries/25/</guid><description>Authors: Sectigo
Published: September 2019
URL: https://sectigo.com/newsroom/the-search-for-quantum-resistant-cryptography-understanding-the-future-landscape
Tags: 2010s Quantum Quantum Resistant Abstract: To help enterprises prepare for the implications of quantum computing, Sectigo has created a broad set of 15 educational resources for security industry professionals in the form of a whitepaper, podcast episodes and transcriptions, and articles.</description></item></channel></rss>